Unknown: [gentle music] That is pretty good.
DM: So we pick up
DM: in the morning.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, we have, like...
Delwath: We stay up late talking to Dimitaur.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: We have, like, potential-
DM: We'll...
Kenzo: Go, go play that in the hot tub.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: All right. Long rest?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Hm.
DM: Reset your charges on things.
Kenzo: No longer have 120 hit points.
Unknown: Or do I?
Unknown: Or I do have 100 hit points.
Unknown: You do.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Delwath: Out of pocket.
Wellby: All right.
Wellby: We're at nine, nine days to
Wellby: total-
DM: Like, you know, like-
Wellby: ... catastrophic world ending
DM: ... 10 days or 11 days.
Kenzo: I don't really don't think it's not gonna be that bad.
Seeker: Can I recover my exhaustion probably?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: I think it's only gonna be fun if he gets out a little bit, and then we have to put him back in the box.
Unknown: I think he already has gotten out a little bit.
Unknown: Has he?
Wellby: Kind of, right? Kinda.
Wellby: Sorta.
Kenzo: Feels pretty mild.
DM: So
DM: from the peak of the mountain, you look out at the sunrises across the forests of
DM: the island below you.
DM: You can see from the mountain, from this perspective up here, especially in the morning light, that there's seven rivers that, like, run down and,
DM: and they actually, they do the reverse thing that rivers go.
DM: As they run down, they split into more and more smaller streams as they get towards the edge of the forest, and all of them stop at some point in these little pools.
Unknown: Nymph pools.
DM: There must be dozens of them scattered across the forest in little clearings.
DM: And you look, from here you can see with the sun rising to the west, a tall,
DM: it must be maybe 15, 20 miles away, right on the coast,
DM: a tall tower, 250 feet tall, taller even than the statues,
DM: made of the same black-
Unknown: Hm
DM: ... uh, marble that the whole island seems to be sculpted of.
DM: Um, rising up about, you know, 100, 150 feet or so, and then a d- a viewing platform, and then a spire that goes up further to another
DM: viewing platform.
DM: Seems to be completely undamaged.
DM: Smooth stone.
DM: Um, the vibe is kind of more Orthanc than Cap- you know, than Barad-dûr.
Kenzo: Sorry, where, where are you describing again?
Unknown: Apollyon's Tower.
DM: This is Apollyon's Tower to the west that we can see now-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... because you're on the top of the mountain in the daylight.
Seeker: Or, so you mean like Saruman as opposed to Sauron?
DM: No, just the visual vibe is more.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: It's, like, smooth stone that it doesn't have, like, all sorts of battlements and-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... you know, things coming off of it.
DM: It's just kind of a smooth pillar of black stone that extends up 150 feet, and then there's an open,
DM: uh, viewing platform that must be, you know, the size of the...
DM: And then a much smaller tower that goes up another 100 feet from there, and comes to a, a peaked roof that has a sort of crenellation around the very top.
DM: Um, the middle viewing platform, at least from here, you can't see any indication that there's, like, a guardrail or anything.
Kenzo: Um, before you went to, before we long rested, did you have, uh, ti- did you have the ability to do another clairvoyance?
Delwath: It's too far away.
Unknown: Too far away.
DM: How many... You've got four charges, so that's two, four, that's eight miles.
DM: You could look at...
DM: That's within the, like, dragon lair area, like about eight miles in.
Unknown: Oh, so I could do it, actually.
Kenzo: Do that. Do dragon lair before long rest.
DM: All right. Don't, if you use, like, lots of charges, you have to, like, roll something and it might go wrong.
Seeker: Yeah, let's look at it. [clears throat] And-
Unknown: This seems like a good one to, right?
Seeker: This is a good thing to do it on 'cause it, it'll just mean the clairvoyance is, like, in a quicker spot that goes off.
Unknown: I mean...
Delwath: I, it's a good... I'm not saying I would do it.
Delwath: I... Don't you think we're gonna have to long rest again before we-
Unknown: No, we're doing this before the long rest.
Delwath: No, no, I know, but I mean...
Unknown: No, no, just do it.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: We'll do, tomorrow we'll do the tower.
Wellby: The day after that we'll do the dragon.
Delwath: I'm just saying we're doing... Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: I think we're gonna long rest again.
Unknown: Um-
Delwath: We're gonna go do the tower this morning.
DM: So you have to roll-
Kenzo: Oh, that's what we're doing first? We're gonna do tower-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... before dragon?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Why did we decide to do that? Why, why the-
DM: Uh, you can discuss it. You have to roll...
DM: So before, we'll retcon back to before the long rest.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: It's, you're spending four charges.
DM: So you need to roll,
DM: uh, an ability check, so just a D20 plus five,
DM: and you have to beat a 16, otherwise something unpredictable happens.
Delwath: Oh, that's not, like, guaranteed at all.
DM: No, if you spend more than two charges, it's not guaranteed.
Wellby: You have heroic inspiration.
Delwath: You do have heroic inspiration.
Seeker: And this is, we're about to go to sleep.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: It's like, all right, let's, let's just try to clairvoyance that crazy tall needle-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... of a tower over here.
Kenzo: No, no, no, we're doing the dragon's lair. That, that, the tower's too far away.
DM: Tower's too far. Tower's 15 miles away.
DM: Plus you can't see it in the dark.
Seeker: But four charges is two, four-
Unknown: Two, four, eight
Unknown: ... eight, 16.
Unknown: 16.
DM: Oh, that's true. Except you can't see it in the dark.
DM: You don't know it's there until you wake up in the morning.
Seeker: So what am I clairvoyancing?
Unknown: The dragon's lair.
DM: You can do the dragon's lair with three charges.
DM: It's eight miles away.
Seeker: But the gla- dragon's lair is underground.
Unknown: Well, we just, uh, scan.
DM: I mean, you can do the surface.
Seeker: Oh, just look at the surface.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Okay, so we're gonna look above ground at the dragon's lair.
DM: Yeah, you can't do the tower simply because you don't know it exists until you wake up in the morning and see it in the sun.
Seeker: It's, it's dark. Okay. Okay, I gotcha, I gotcha.
Seeker: So I'm expending-
DM: Three charges
Seeker: ... three charges.
DM: So then it's only against, uh, 14.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: 16.
DM: Yeah, no problem.
Seeker: Or is that 18?
Seeker: It must be a 16.
Wellby: I think.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So,
DM: uh- You just kind of guess somewhere to put it 'cause you can't really see that much details and it's not that, you know, it's dark, but the...
DM: Okay, so a few things you can definitely clearly see.
DM: Um,
DM: the, the sc- the what looks from a distance like this reddish bruise is actually like, uh,
DM: it's like, it looks like a, a mat of like this sort of red and
DM: orange and sort of angry scarred, like s- like moss that's sort of growing in like a spongy layer over the top of the ground.
Kenzo: How is the moss angry?
DM: That's just the color. It's, it's-
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And that seems to extend for this whole distance, right?
DM: So this red thing you're seeing from a distance and clairvoyance up close is like a, it's like a mat of something that's grown over the land, this weird-
Unknown: Moss
DM: ... moss.
DM: Um, there is
DM: a structure here. So you can see there's, um,
DM: there's like a road that leads from the pilgrims path towards, uh, what is a big sort of oval, um,
DM: uh, like a big oval plaza, sort of like stone paved where the moss hasn't seemed to grown.
DM: Um, the moss is like creeping over the road, but not entirely.
DM: So you can see like little bits of the road, but it hasn't grown over this,
DM: um, this plaza. And then the road splits and one, um, this area is clear of the moss.
DM: One,
DM: uh, path goes off to a hill where there's a
DM: not really intact villa, just like, um, again, just pretty much level.
DM: But you can see the outlines, like there's a courtyard, and then you can see the walls.
DM: Um, like the left half, the one half closer to you is still kind of standing like three stories and a bit of a roof.
DM: The right half on the other side is like completely destroyed down to the found- like the rubble foundations pretty much.
DM: Um, but it once was probably a fairly big,
DM: fairly substantial villa, and it's overlooking about a half mile away what looks like, uh...
DM: There's like a, a big pool.
DM: It almost looks like, like thermal baths, right?
DM: It's like a big pool and then three little pools around it that are all arranged, like nice paved marble area.
DM: You can see a row of columns around it.
DM: Um,
DM: if there once was a roof, it's gone.
DM: But there's, uh, you know, there's a whole entrance complex that is now mostly rubble.
DM: But, um, you can see like a few dragonets kind of perched around, snoozing a little bit.
DM: Um, seemingly sleeping in the plaza further, a little further away are four, um,
DM: pretty large, like horse sized beasts that have the head of a dragon, a goat, and a lion all coming out of their neck with
DM: wings.
Seeker: So each beast has three heads.
DM: Each beast has three heads.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Have
Seeker: I seen something like that before?
DM: Yeah, you've, I mean, yeah, these are, these are chimeras.
Seeker: Ah.
Seeker: Our party's not encountered these.
DM: You haven't, although you,
DM: uh, in Ravenshold-
Seeker: Yeah
DM: ... there was an old chimera lair that, where the chimera had been killed.
Seeker: Ah.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: All right.
Kenzo: What was that little family of weird beasts that we killed?
DM: Manticore.
Seeker: Manticore.
Delwath: Ah, yeah.
DM: Swatted the poor innocents.
DM: Seeker-
Wellby: It's worse when you say family.
Unknown: Hmm?
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: It's worse when you say family.
Kenzo: Well, it was... I forget who wanted to kill them all.
Seeker: Seeker was advocating against.
DM: Um [laughs]
Seeker: We're not sure.
DM: Wellby was probably-
Seeker: It's not clear exactly.
Kenzo: It was somebody that advocated.
Seeker: Somebody, somebody-
Wellby: Wellby didn't call them a family, though.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Threatening beasts, sorry.
Seeker: Chimeras have heads...
Seeker: Each one has the head of a dragon, a goat, and a lion?
DM: Yep.
Seeker: That is so weird. Wow.
DM: But they're usually not considered to be nearly as dangerous as dragons.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: Like, they're more pests than-
Seeker: Pests
DM: ... four of them wouldn't be, it wouldn't be a total cakewalk, but it wouldn't really usually be that big of a challenge for a group.
Seeker: But what do they do in here?
Delwath: Guard. They're probably servants, right?
Wellby: Guarding the...
Seeker: So those pools were like-
Unknown: It's the entrance way
Seeker: ... right. They were like the luxurious-
Unknown: Right
Seeker: ... geothermal baths-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... of this villa 1,000 years ago, and now
Seeker: somehow the dragon has carved out a cavity deep underground underneath the-
Unknown: Or a portal
DM: Oh, you know what? Um-
Seeker: No, right. It's just a portal. Right.
Seeker: Right, right, right.
Kenzo: Before bed also, um...
Kenzo: Oh, but we're gonna go, we're gonna go west first, right?
DM: I think so, yeah. That's...
Delwath: The theory was it makes more sense to do that because
DM: the...
DM: Once we get the jade,
Delwath: it gives us more options for getting the jade that involve quick escapes.
Delwath: Like, "Oh, no, we have the jade and everybody's after us.
DM: Let's cast teleport."
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Right?
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Although there's pretty much no chance teleport would work.
Delwath: No, we could teleport onto the boat.
DM: Oh, onto Myla's boat.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Uh, 'cause I wanted to do, um, aura sense one more time.
Unknown: Um-
DM: Yeah, you can do that before you sleep.
Kenzo: Yeah, I'll do that. Um, I guess I got...
Kenzo: I'm just so curious about what's east now, now that we just did lair.
Kenzo: Oh, and also, like, we, we still haven't seen the...
Kenzo: I can... I'll do that in the morning 'cause we'll short rest again at one point, at some point during the day.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Probably, yeah. Yeah, how about this?
Kenzo: I'll, I'm gonna, um, I'm gonna follow up your clairvoyance with a, an aura, um, analysis of the lair.
Kenzo: In particular, is the dragon there?
DM: You can't sense any dragon.
Kenzo: Great. Extra dimensional.
DM: Mm.
Kenzo: Fuck. Okay.
Kenzo: What else do, do I sense the, the, the things that, um...
DM: Yeah, like I mean-
Kenzo: Are there any other beings other than what, um, uh, Seeker revealed in the Clairvoyance
Unknown: that I sense?
DM: Um, that is a good question.
DM: Give me one sec.
Unknown: [clears throat] I'm gonna grab my phone.
Unknown: Very excited to see this.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. [doorbell rings] Oh, food is here.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Perfect.
DM: Um...
Unknown: Hey, thank you so much.
DM: Oh, wait for Kong.
DM: I gotta check one thing on my notes anyway.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh-
Kenzo: You guys want a break for dinner or-
Wellby: Play through dinner?
Delwath: Yeah, just play through dinner, honestly
Unknown: ... play through dinner?
Delwath: We just got started.
DM: The other thing Kenzo senses, Kong, is, um,
DM: a fiend underneath the villa.
Unknown: Great.
Unknown: Ouch.
Unknown: Which v-
Wellby: Which villa?
DM: The villa in the Dragonmire.
Delwath: I was just thinking how we haven't fought any fiends, and my sword is so good against fiends.
Unknown: Uh, I don't know what this thing is.
Unknown: That's probably the chili lime chicken that I ordered.
Wellby: Apollyon's fiend is fiends, right?
Unknown: Is that... I don't think so
Kenzo: This is maybe two enchiladas.
Delwath: I got two enchiladas and a taco.
Delwath: Tim, you got just two enchiladas?
DM: I... Yeah, but it's gonna look exactly the same way that you get yours.
Delwath: Uh, uh, meat and cheese.
Unknown: I don't remember.
Unknown: Get a new taco.
Unknown: Oh, because we got... My taco's just half of...
Unknown: mostly.
DM: These are huge.
Unknown: I know.
Unknown: I'm like, no wonder they cost $30.
Unknown: I was like, crazy, like, these are $18.
DM: Oh, that's true.
DM: I think I got one beef and one chicken.
DM: I got two chicken, one beef.
DM: So it's-
Unknown: Hold on. I'll just cut a new...
Unknown: Wait, yeah, hold on.
Kenzo: Maybe this is the... Maybe this is me and Schwartz's.
DM: Oh, that's what this is. This is...
DM: So is it... That's you and Schwartz.
Unknown: That's what it's called on the [paper rustling].
Unknown: Jesus Christ.
Delwath: [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: No, you're right.
Wellby: What just happened there?
Unknown: It was just-
DM: This is the taco guy.
Kenzo: Holy crap. Look at this fucking thing.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Well, at least I have delicious tomatoes.
Unknown: The, the weight.
DM: Yeah, this is a [laughs]...
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It's like a pitcher almost.
Wellby: I'll just structure it in the container.
Unknown: Schwartz, you wanna... Do you want a knife and a fork?
Wellby: Uh, I got knives and forks right here.
Unknown: Oh, you do? Awesome.
Unknown: You can use whatever.
DM: Yeah, I did not continue to get this chili.
Delwath: Well, you can just stick it in the fri- I mean...
DM: Well, the fried things.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Better eat this-
Unknown: That's true
DM: ... than have my enchiladas.
DM: The fried things.
Kenzo: Oh, my God. Oh.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
Unknown: Did it again.
Wellby: Oh, that's better.
Unknown: There you go.
Unknown: No, no, stop.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: It's not surprising that that happened.
DM: Okay. So-
Delwath: The, the sword's actually pretty... Like, you can just crop it before the stem.
DM: It's, uh, I could have totally split one.
DM: We can... I mean, you can save them for lunchtime.
Kenzo: Yeah, this is outrageous.
Kenzo: I thought, like, it was gonna be a burrito that I could, like, pick up and eat, but...
Wellby: Mm. Mm.
Unknown: Is it good?
Unknown: It's tasty though.
Unknown: It's pretty good, yeah.
Delwath: Hm, I might've gotten two chicken instead of a chicken and a beef, but that's okay.
DM: So in the morning,
DM: say goodbye to Dimitar. Where do you wanna go?
Seeker: Well, we should have a meal from the, uh, magical runic meal provision.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I give Dimitar a, um, really cool, um, statue out of himself.
Delwath: Oh, I cooked a fancy meal last night too.
Kenzo: We can roll play that later.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, so are we heading... Okay, we're heading to the to- tower.
Delwath: We're all, we're all okay with... We're all on board with Apollyon first?
Wellby: What if we go through the tower, like, from the top to the bottom rather than the bottom to the top?
Unknown: I was just gonna ask what you thought about what people thought about that.
DM: So again, another thing you can see in the morning
DM: is that,
DM: [clears throat] um,
DM: for maybe...
DM: So the tower's right on the coast, and for maybe five miles inland from the coast, the terrain is just these
DM: jagged rocks, just like, you know-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... a giant, like, spike of stone sticking up like this with rubble crumbling around it, and then another jagged rock.
Unknown: It looks-
DM: It looks...
Unknown: I mean, this would be... This will be...
DM: This would be very challenging to walk through.
DM: Not impossible, obviously, but it's, like, extremely jagged terrain.
Unknown: You'd be, like, scrambling up through
DM: pits and, and it's about five miles.
Unknown: It's light.
DM: Yeah. [clears throat] Yeah.
Delwath: And I'm wondering if we just head for the top.
Kenzo: Tim, before we leave, um, I'll do, uh, an aura sense of, um-
DM: In that direction
Kenzo: ... in that direction focused around the tower, but also, like, you know, if there's any, like, notable things on the way there.
Seeker: So [clears throat] we know
Seeker: that Jade is not in this tower.
Seeker: What are we looking for?
Kenzo: This is, uh, Apollyon's Tower.
Unknown: So-
Seeker: We're, we're looking for, like-
Kenzo: His divine... His Divinity Forge is there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Where he, like, made the Scepter of Command and other...
Kenzo: potentially the crown-
Unknown: Yes
Kenzo: ... potentially other items that we don't know about.
Seeker: And so
Seeker: are we stealing stuff or just learning about him?
Kenzo: We're investigating.
Wellby: Kind of a side quest, if you will.
DM: So
DM: Kenzo extends his consciousness out.
DM: Uh, so the forest continues for maybe five miles,
DM: seven miles, something like that, to the west.
DM: But then once the forest ends, there's nothing.
DM: There's nothing you can sense that has any kind of
DM: aura or soul.
Unknown: Soul.
DM: It's-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... there's no dragonets over here.
DM: There doesn't... You don't see anything moving on the landscape in this direction.
Unknown: Huh.
DM: You don't sense anything living in the tower.
Kenzo: Nothing alive. Can I sense undead things with this?
DM: Um,
DM: you-
Unknown: I mean, I could sense the-
DM: Your general aura sense, uh,
DM: typically doesn't work for like this, just like what's out there.
DM: You would normally miss constructs.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And some undead, if they're like-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... uh, zombies or skeletons or those kind of corporeal undead.
DM: But if it's-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... anything with a consciousness-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Right
DM: ... you wouldn't sense them, like vampires or, you know, liches or-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... wraiths or something.
Kenzo: Yeah. Higher lev- higher, uh-
DM: Yeah.
DM: So it could be full of zombies, it could be full of constructs, it could be full of magical traps.
DM: You wouldn't sense any of those.
DM: But there's not like a vampire on the top.
DM: You would sense that.
Kenzo: Yeah. Or this is like, um,
Kenzo: also just the physical entrance to the branch, right?
DM: To, uh, actually the branch.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yes. That's always a possibility.
Seeker: All right.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: So should we fly over this rugged terrain?
Delwath: I don't think fly will get us five miles, actually.
DM: How long does fly last?
Unknown: 10 minutes.
Delwath: It only lasts 10 minutes.
Seeker: Mm. And, and if I animate the ladder, that lasts one hour.
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: And the summon constructs thing is also one hour.
Seeker: But the fly speed of each of those...
DM: Well, the construct can't even fly.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Probably.
DM: Oh, but I can
Seeker: glove magic it so it can.
DM: Uh, you can...
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: We can innately fly. Like we can fly.
Delwath: Well, I don't know how long the raven's whistle lasts.
Unknown: That's a good question.
Wellby: I think I have three hours a day altogether.
Wellby: I think raven's whistle is like-
DM: You have three charges and each one lasts for your con mod
Wellby: ... in minutes?
DM: It says on there.
Delwath: Of the raven's whistle or?
DM: The raven's whistle. The raven's whistle doesn't do you a lot.
DM: It's mostly a combat thing.
DM: It doesn't do a lot of-
Unknown: Got it. Got it.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: But I can also just run across the terrain.
DM: You could probably run across the terrain, yes.
Kenzo: I totally can. That's my, that's my shit.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Then you're exposed to the, whatever's watching from the tower,
Seeker: and we'll have to think about how to get back, too.
Wellby: Can you make a thing that flies?
Delwath: I mean, if we're close to it, we can all fly.
Unknown: Can we all fit on the ladder?
Seeker: The ladder can carry two creatures, I think.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Can you make something that's small
Kenzo: and we can just like fit in or somebody's pocket?
Seeker: That would be cool,
Wellby: but in large-
Wellby: What about the, we all turn into beasts?
Delwath: Mm, mm, mm.
Delwath: Oh.
Wellby: Of course.
Unknown: We should totally do that.
Seeker: Thank you, Schwartz.
Unknown: Animal shapes.
Delwath: That's a really good idea, too, 'cause we can approach it much less seen.
Delwath: Like, let's all turn into ospreys.
Seeker: We'll just look around for a while, see what's already flying around.
Unknown: Yeah, it's a bird that's-
DM: Yeah, there's lots of different kinds of sea birds.
DM: So there's, uh...
DM: You know, there's the, the most common one are gulls and these tropic birds that have like long, streaming tails, but there's like a few ospreys.
DM: There's terns. There's
DM: sort of any kind of shore and sea bird.
Delwath: All right. It requires concentration.
Unknown: That's too bad, but that's okay. You should still do it.
Seeker: It'll get us there.
Wellby: Can I talk with one of the birds?
Unknown: Yeah, whoa. CR4 or lower.
DM: Challenge 4 or lower.
Seeker: So they can be-
DM: You can turn into giant eagles.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You can turn into...
DM: You're, there's not... So you're a little...
DM: You're... Most of the-
Unknown: Two 40s.
DM: Yeah. Most of the birds don't come into the forest.
DM: There are like little forest creatures, like little chickadees and, you know, chipmunks and things in the forest.
DM: Um, but they... You get a pretty clear sense just from watching, like things-
Unknown: Wow
DM: ... stay in the forest but don't come into the forest.
Delwath: That's really powerful.
Unknown: Right,
Unknown: right.
Unknown: What is?
Unknown: The spell?
Delwath: Yeah. It's a-
DM: Well, it's an eighth level spell. Like-
Unknown: It doesn't have to be animals.
Delwath: It's any, any creature with CR4 or less.
Kenzo: What is CR4?
Unknown: Like-
Seeker: As though you were a level four player character.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, wow.
Delwath: There's lots of good creatures CR4 or less.
DM: No, it's a beast.
Delwath: Oh, it has to be a beast, CR4 or less.
DM: Um, but there's, there are a bunch of...
DM: Like, you could turn into-
Delwath: And we can turn back. You can turn us into animals whenever we want.
DM: As long as you-
Delwath: As long as you don't lose concentration.
Delwath: So that would mean you're not able to do other concentration.
Delwath: But your forms of creation stuff's not concentration, right?
DM: Right.
Unknown: Now [laughs] with the ladder-
Kenzo: Wait, we can turn into multiple things or just one thing?
Delwath: Each turn he can turn us into something else.
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
DM: We can change. Yeah.
Delwath: For a full 24 hours.
DM: On later turns-
Unknown: Over and over again
Seeker: ... you take a magic action to transform the targets again.
Unknown: We just have to concentrate.
Unknown: He has.
Unknown: The whole time.
Delwath: Not... Yeah, but not the rest of us.
Kenzo: He, he has to concentrate for 24 hours?
Kenzo: Feels like a long time to concentrate.
Delwath: It just means he can't cast other spells that require concentration.
DM: Right. And then-
Delwath: We get a whole bunch of temporary hit points, too, right?
Seeker: Um, yes, that is true.
DM: It looks like that.
Kenzo: Yeah, that's awesome. We should use that e- we should use that for every combat.
Kenzo: Every, just-
Delwath: I mean, we're probably all more effective in our natural shapes.
Seeker: That's the thing. You can't use any of your weapons or spells, I think, so.
Unknown: Oh, true.
Seeker: Here you go. Here's that one. "Target gains the number of temporary hit points equal to the beast form's hit points,
DM: which is added."
Delwath: Well, temporary hit points don't stack with each other.
Kenzo: Ooh, and then you can turn us into mice.
Delwath: But we don't lose the temporary hit points.
Kenzo: Oh, this is how we can sneak into the lair, into the dragon's lair.
DM: We could be fish.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: We need to sneak into the dragon's lair as like fucking whatever the fucks, and then avoid-
Seeker: Well, we, we fly there and then change to fish and dive in the water.
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
DM: That's interesting.
Unknown: Holy shit.
DM: I like it. I like it.
Unknown: Yeah. Hell yeah. [knocks]
DM: [clears throat]
Unknown: And then wait, what beings can live in acid?
DM: Good question. [laughs]
Unknown: Seriously.
Wellby: That's a fish.
DM: Dire-
Wellby: Oh, no.
DM: Dire bird of prey.
Kenzo: Seriously, though. Is it... There's some like acid resistant-
DM: 90-foot fly. That's pretty good
Kenzo: There must be some kind of acid resistant animals or creatures.
DM: Wow. +10 bonus to perception checks.
Kenzo: Tim, what's an acid resistant-
DM: I'm helping you out here
Kenzo: ... what's an, what's an acid resistant animal?
Wellby: I don't think you have acid.
Unknown: Like, uh, deep sea vents worms.
DM: Please be worms. I want acid.
Wellby: That wouldn't really help us.
DM: I was looking. It could be like two worms.
Delwath: Well, hold on, hold on. We're doing... Let's, let's, let's, um- [laughs] You're getting ahead of yourself.
Delwath: Hold on. How do I filter by able to fly?
DM: Go to,
DM: uh, movement type.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: fly.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: Here's all the CR4 creatures.
Delwath: It'll sort by CR.
DM: You gotta turn on partnered content yes if you want the free mortal stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay. So,
Delwath: okay, so let's see. We could be...
Delwath: We don't want any of those.
Delwath: Giant... I mean, there's like the standard.
DM: Death butterfly. What?
DM: Some of those I don't have.
DM: Death
DM: hawk.
Delwath: Death hawk
Delwath: can sense the presence of undead
Delwath: within five miles.
DM: Excuse me.
Delwath: One of us should be a death hawk.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Everybody can be something different. We can all be different.
Delwath: We can all be different things.
Delwath: But sense presence of undead that have...
Delwath: or corpses that have been dead for less than 90 days.
Delwath: Fly speed of 60.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: but the, the dire bird of prey
Delwath: is even better 'cause it has +10 bonus to wisdom checks to see things.
DM: Now remember, we wanna look like-
Delwath: That's the real question
DM: ... And neither one of those will look like things around here.
DM: You gotta decide between effective combat stats or camouflage.
Wellby: We can change in the middle of battle.
DM: We can change.
Delwath: He can change us, but not while you're a beast, can you?
Delwath: You have to take the magic action, which you can't do while you yourself are-
DM: That seems impossible.
Delwath: That's true. How do we-
DM: otherwise the spell wouldn't work. I'm sure you can take the magic action.
Delwath: How do we change out of...
Delwath: Do we... Can we decide to just leave the beast form or do you have to?
Seeker: This is a good question. It's not 100% clear on that.
Wellby: Uh, target can leave beast form as bonus action.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Who wants to see other time lapse?
DM: I do.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Whoa.
Kenzo: I have to edit out those jostles.
Kenzo: And actually, like, this part's really cool and all the clouds dissipate.
DM: Oh, wow.
Unknown: And then...
DM: That's amazing.
Unknown: Yeah, I kept it-
DM: That's awesome
Kenzo: ... I kept it going all the way.
Seeker: Oh, and then the darkness falls.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That is incredibly atmospheric.
Seeker: That's really, that's really good, man.
Delwath: Yeah. That is epic for sure.
Kenzo: What did you use to, um, edit the, um, the mix thing?
Kenzo: I just wanna edit it a little so like-
Seeker: Oh, you should have iMovie on your phone.
Unknown: Oh, perfect. Okay.
DM: Wow.
Delwath: So okay, here's the question.
DM: Worth it.
Delwath: Right. So, so presumably the way it works is that you would have to leave beast form as a bonus action and then change us back to other forms.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So it would cost...
DM: In order... But it's...
DM: So it would cost you both your bonus action and your action on a turn to shift them, 'cause you use bonus action to turn yourself out, then you use an action to shift everybody
DM: to whatever you want.
Seeker: Yeah. And so I can't do that-
DM: But we keep-
Unknown: ... in, in midair for instance.
DM: Sure you could.
DM: Well, I would f- f-
DM: You'd fall I would bet.
Seeker: And then I just-
DM: You'd only fall for a few seconds
Unknown: ... for like 15 seconds.
DM: Yeah. If you're high enough up and you so you don't hit the ground, it might be okay.
Seeker: Seeker's not like that excited about that concept, but-
Delwath: Um, but we keep the temporary hit points even when we leave the beast form, right?
Delwath: There's nothing there that says the temporary hit points go away when the spell ends or even, right?
DM: I mean-
Wellby: 176 meters
Wellby: is how far you'd fall.
Unknown: Um-
DM: In six seconds?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: No, y- you don't keep the temporary hit points if you're not in the beast form.
Seeker: It's not the falling, Seeker, you're afraid of.
DM: No. [laughs]
Unknown: It's the impact.
Delwath: It just says the target gains a number of t- temporary hit points equal to the beast form's hit points.
DM: Yeah, but that's an effect of the...
Unknown: Well, if you switch to a new...
DM: I guess if you switch to a new beast form with lower hit points, you could keep the old hit points.
Delwath: Why couldn't you just keep them when you leave the beast form?
DM: I guess as long as Seeker is still concentrating on the spell, there's no reason why you couldn't.
Delwath: That's how I would read that.
Delwath: I mean, most, most spells that give you temporary hit points, you don't even have to still be concentrating on the spell to keep them.
DM: Yeah, you do.
Unknown: You don't.
Delwath: Armor of Agathys, there's n- there's no duration.
Delwath: Uh, well, it- it's within the...
Delwath: Oh, no, that's true. It's within the duration.
Unknown: Never mind. It's within the duration.
Seeker: Where's this beast finder thing that you have?
Delwath: I just went to D&D Beyond.
DM: But yes, I think it would make sense that if you switch out of the...
DM: Well, I mean-
Wellby: I just have about five minutes.
DM: Yeah I don't know.
DM: It's a little bit complicated, though. The w- they rewrote, uh, in the new version of these, of the rules, they rewrote all polymorph spells to give you temporary hit points instead of the beast's hit points.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: I think it's, uh, I think-
Delwath: It's probably intended to be-
DM: The intent is-
DM: ... while you're in the beast form
DM: ... the, the-
Unknown: Fine, fine, fine
DM: ... the intention is definitely while you're in the beast form because they also changed every spell that is supposed to give you permanent temporary hit points to instantaneous.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So false life doesn't have a duration anymore.
Unknown: Right, right, right, right, right.
Unknown: No, that makes sense.
DM: So I assume the way it's intended to work-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... is the temporary hit points lasts-
Unknown: No, no
DM: ... while you're in the beast form.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. That makes sense.
Delwath: I didn't realize they had made that change 'cause, like, in the...
Unknown: Yeah, that perfectly makes sense.
Delwath: You know, I think we're choosing between either, um,
Delwath: totally not hidden, completely obvious, in which case our best bet is something like
Unknown: a, a
Delwath: death hawk or a dire bird of prey, some sort of giant-
Seeker: And it's great 'cause we don't know anything about what's at this tower.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: 'Cause we can't see any creatures or any activity of any kind.
Delwath: Right. If we wanna be sneaky, we should really just be ospreys or something like that, or just, like, nothing, nothing strong at all.
Delwath: We're just, like, little birds.
Delwath: Right? Go with, like, a,
Delwath: you know, a hawk.
Seeker: We're still not in the right, like, beast.
Delwath: The big beast and then if you go to movement type.
Unknown: I don't see that here.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I couldn't find it for some reason, but wait.
Unknown: Where is it?
Delwath: Wait, you have a different...
Seeker: I, I went to, oh, homebrew/monsters.
Delwath: No, don't go to homebrew.
Delwath: Go to, just go to source, go to game rules-
Unknown: Also-
Unknown: ... monsters. [laughs]
Kenzo: Jen gave me this.
DM: That's awesome.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: It currently does not have drugs in it, but I've also put drugs in it.
Unknown: It's really good.
DM: Beast.
Kenzo: Take your energy substance.
DM: Ooh, attack.
Delwath: Right. I think we either go with, like, like, ospreys or eagles, something that, like, there's no
Delwath: special skills except advantage on perception.
DM: I mean, keep in mind you can, you can change, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So.
Delwath: I think we start as e- I think we start as ospreys.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And fly towards-
Seeker: Space swan.
Delwath: I think that's, I think, I think-
Unknown: I've got another question.
Seeker: Is the construct
Seeker: a creature that I could turn
Seeker: into an osprey?
DM: Yeah, sure. Why not? It just says, like, willing targets, right?
DM: It doesn't say-
Unknown: As long as the construct-
Unknown: It says willing creatures.
DM: Yeah, they're a creature.
Delwath: As long as the construct's a creature.
Seeker: Is the, is the ladder a creature?
DM: Yeah. As long as it's animated it becomes a construct.
DM: You can't turn a, you can't turn it.
DM: You have to use Performance of Creation first.
DM: So you can't just turn an inanimate object into a bird.
DM: You have to Performance of Creation-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... to activate it.
Seeker: Definitely. That's what I was imagining.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: So I, okay. I use Performance of Creation.
Delwath: Ima- we're not gonna be an hour if we do that.
Unknown: It's too, too short because-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... you only-
Unknown: It's a 20-mile flight, or a 15-mile flight.
DM: It's a 15-mile flight.
Seeker: How long is it gonna take?
DM: I'm just googling how far ospreys can fly.
Seeker: I mean, how long does my constructs last?
Seeker: One hour. Oh, that's also a concentration spell, so I can't really do the construct.
DM: Oh, you can't do both.
Seeker: And animal shapes at the same time.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: So I really, I can't, I can't do either of those things.
Delwath: Ospreys during migration go 175 miles a day.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Yeah, but you're not mi- I mean-
Delwath: They typically average 100
Delwath: according to the Virginia Institute of Marine Science.
DM: I think that's, I think that's about like-
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: ... five miles an hour. That seems appropriate.
Seeker: So it's gonna take a while.
Unknown: Well, five miles an hour for 20 miles-
Unknown: Take four hours
DM: ... is gonna take you four hours.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That's not too bad.
DM: But yes, it'll take you long enough that you can't
DM: animating performance something here.
DM: But you could find a place to land,
DM: bonus action, change yourself, animating performance,
DM: and then-
Seeker: Like, there are these giant boulders all around.
Unknown: I can hide behind one.
DM: Yeah.
DM: And I think technically you have to, um,
DM: determine if, like, the targets are the targets you pick at the beginning.
DM: But I think for-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... you know, coolness sake, there's no reason you can't add.
DM: I will say, at least for now, you can add-
Delwath: Ospreys have wife up.
Delwath: They fly according to a study by some undergrad at, uh, using GPS tracking technology,
Delwath: the most common speed that of observed ospreys was somewhere between 15 and 25 knots.
Seeker: Unladen African swallow.
DM: Right, but most birds, no, no osprey is gonna sustain that flight for four hours straight.
DM: So this is not-
Delwath: These were migrating birds.
DM: Yeah, yeah. On, maybe on migration.
Delwath: But, but we can choose how we wanna fly, right?
DM: No, no, no. You, you gotta spend m- weeks stocking up on fat-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... like eating tons of fish.
DM: You can't, you can't animal shape into a migrating osprey.
Delwath: [laughs] Okay.
DM: [laughs] They undergo a whole series of physiological changes to get into their migratory state.
DM: Plus, we don't even know if ospreys actually migrate.
DM: The ospreys that live here probably don't migrate.
Delwath: I'm just saying-
DM: Well
Delwath: ... um, don't you think we can go a little faster than five miles an hour?
DM: Okay. Maybe, like-
DM: Yeah, maybe a little faster, but what difference does it make?
DM: You're not gonna go fast enough to get there in an hour, so what's the difference?
Unknown: No, um,
Delwath: just to preserve more of our day.
Unknown: Oh, for your hit points?
Delwath: For hit points and just if we want a short rest when we get there, like...
DM: You can get there in three hours.
Delwath: Still gives you four hours to explore.
Delwath: I know. [sighs]
Unknown: [thudding] [sniffs] [thudding] What? [sighs] [sighs] All
Unknown: right. [thudding]
Unknown: [clattering]
Seeker: I think mine is not worth selling the table.
Unknown: Yeah, I think this is probably not the right...
Unknown: Are we waiting for Schwartz? [clattering]
Unknown: [coughs] [thudding] All right.
Unknown: [clattering]
Unknown: Sweet.
Kenzo: [clears throat] Really just can't touch that phone, man.
Seeker: What's that?
Kenzo: I'm gonna try this again tomorrow.
Kenzo: This was, um...
Kenzo: It's like all the little jostles, you can edit them out, but it's, like, kinda noticeable little clips-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... you know?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: [clears throat]
Seeker: Let's see.
Seeker: Yeah, you can probably cross fade them.
Unknown: Oh, that's a good idea.
Seeker: Maybe just, like, a long press on the little transition point.
Seeker: There's, like, different options probably.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Are we waiting, we're waiting for Schwartz.
DM: Um,
Unknown: I mean...
Delwath: We can fly towards the area.
DM: We can fly towards the area.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: All right, that's good.
DM: So you're turning into
Unknown: Seeker. It's like, "Wait, wait, guys."
Wellby: Ah.
Unknown: "Got a new trick."
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: It used to just be I could turn myself into a giant crab or something,
Seeker: but now we can all become birds.
Kenzo: Pretty epic. [laughs]
DM: So you're turning into what?
DM: Ospreys?
Seeker: To start, yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: So you head, you fly west.
DM: Um, flying pretty fast as ospreys, uh, you quickly descend from the mountain to past the forest,
DM: uh, and come out into this sort of open plain about five or six miles between the
DM: forest and the edge of this sort of rocky terrain.
DM: You can see that there's two, again, there's these divine towers, the statues.
DM: Um, they both are, like, Apollyon's Tower is sort of placed equidistant between-
Seeker: It's, like, here?
DM: No, it's-
Seeker: Here?
DM: S- one more south
DM: Yeah.
DM: It's, like, equidistant between, between the two statues there.
Seeker: So which ones are those?
DM: Um,
DM: well, I have an order somewhere.
DM: It doesn't really matter. Um,
DM: so-
Seeker: Or it doesn't matter
DM: ... those ones would be,
DM: uh, let's see.
DM: Um,
DM: so the Warlord
DM: and the,
DM: and the Wildling.
Seeker: Wildling.
Seeker: Does that tell you something about Apollyon's self-image?
Unknown: Maybe. [laughs]
Seeker: Wildling, Warlord.
Wellby: All right, sorry to keep going.
Delwath: No, that's okay.
DM: It's okay. You're-
Delwath: We're ospreys flying towards the thing.
Seeker: We took off.
DM: Awesome.
DM: So, you know, a couple hours pass
DM: as you fly
DM: and find yourself now approaching the sort of upturned black rugged terrain about six miles from the tower.
DM: Um, you know, it's
DM: jagged rocks below you.
DM: You're, I mean, there's other birds around, right?
DM: So now you're close to, relatively close to the coast.
DM: They, they seem to be, I mean, they seem to avoid the tower, right?
DM: You don't see any birds flying around the tower, just kind of on the outskirts.
DM: And the further you fly towards the tower, the more
DM: oppressive the atmosphere feels.
DM: There's, it almost is difficult to even keep flying.
DM: The air feels thick.
DM: It doesn't stop you.
DM: You can, you're, you know, powerful adventurers.
DM: You can push through, but you can see why sort of normal birds would probably feel very dubious of this.
Seeker: What kind of effect would that be?
DM: I, it feels like, it, it feels like the air is almost getting, like, soupy.
DM: Like, it just takes more effort to beat your wings.
Seeker: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
DM: Takes a- just more thought to just keep moving forward.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: You have to consciously exert.
DM: You almost find if you stop paying attention, like, you just kind of feel yourself veering back.
Seeker: Ah, it's a kind of repulsion.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Are we landing on the top? Is that the plan?
DM: So you fly closer.
Seeker: I, I was, uh... So we s- we have our telepathy set up so we can communicate.
DM: Mm, not anymore.
Seeker: Because-
DM: Unless you're stopping every hour to reset it.
DM: It only lasts an hour.
Seeker: Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Wellby: But I can relay telepathically.
DM: You could, I mean, you can stop.
DM: You can, you can stop.
Unknown: Wellby can just relay.
DM: Yeah, Wellby can relay, or you can stop and reset the telepathy and redo the-
Seeker: So, well, Seeker, at any rate, flies down and finds a very large
Seeker: boulder amid the ones upturned.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Choosing one where I'll be able to land
Seeker: on the ground in such a way that we'll be totally hidden from line of sight of the tower.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: And
Seeker: that's cool. And I'm just, I'm just gonna, um,
Seeker: briefly transform back to a dwarf.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [clears throat] Briefly.
Seeker: Pull the rope ladder out of my pack.
DM: [clears throat]
Seeker: Animate it,
Seeker: turn it into an osprey, then turn myself back into an osprey.
Seeker: This is all legal, right?
DM: Yep.
Wellby: That's amazing.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: We're just getting rope ladder osprey [coughing] who will, um, rosprey.
Seeker: R- Rope osprey.
Wellby: Rosprey.
Seeker: Yeah. Um,
Seeker: ladder, rope spray the ladder bird will fly behind me.
Seeker: So I take off again and rejoin.
DM: So as of now, you're now, like, maybe a 20 minute flight from the,
DM: from the top, and you can see more details of the tower now.
DM: Um, so the, the,
DM: again, it's
DM: 250 feet tall.
DM: The main section rises about 150 feet from the ground, and there's this big flat open space.
DM: It's about, the whole thing is about 100 feet in diameter.
DM: Is that right?
Seeker: It was big, but...
DM: I don't think that's it. Hold on.
Seeker: Just looking for a picture of an osprey.
Seeker: Oh, it's those. Oh my God.
Seeker: It's like a-
DM: No, it's 50 feet in diameter.
Seeker: Like a hawk basically.
Seeker: I was trying to think if it was too big.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: The, the whole thing is about, the whole thing is about
DM: 50 feet in diameter, and at the very top,
DM: so not at the very top, halfway up, 150 feet up, there's this open battlements area, but there's no railing around it or anything.
DM: And there are two, um, fairly large statues kind of standing, um, like with their hands up like this, like metallic.
DM: ... sort of metallic-ish with mostly stone, but with like metal, metal on their hands, like metal fists.
DM: Both of them have metal fists.
Unknown: Where are they standing?
DM: Um, they're standing on that second, like facing, looking out towards the island.
DM: Yeah, right there.
Unknown: And those are-
DM: Like there
Seeker: ... they're, they're human figures?
DM: They look like big humans.
DM: They're maybe eight or nine feet tall, maybe 10 feet tall.
Delwath: Is there a door there or anything?
DM: Um, yes, there is, uh, there is a door there, and then there's the second part that goes up another 100 feet, and then at the very top there's a crenellated,
DM: um, place to stand and you can see down from there, like there's a trapdoor at the very top.
DM: There is also a big set of double doors at the very bottom,
DM: uh, also facing away from the ocean.
Delwath: Top, right? Very top.
Delwath: Trapdoor at the top.
Kenzo: Did we wanna do clairvoyance inside here any place, or was, we're just gonna go in?
Seeker: [clears throat] That's interesting.
Seeker: I would vote we land first.
Delwath: I mean, land at the top, right?
Seeker: And then-
DM: The very top. Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh yeah, Tim, [clears throat] um, now that we've long rested,
Kenzo: beings, entities inside this thing.
DM: Wait, you just did that. I just-
Unknown: I did that before sleep.
Kenzo: I did that before sleep for the dragon slayer.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, sorry. So then we did it-
DM: No, you already did when you woke up
Unknown: ... at Krakow.
DM: You already did it.
Unknown: Yeah, we already did.
DM: And you're very-
Unknown: And there was nothing here
DM: ... y- no, nothing.
DM: No-
Kenzo: No beings
DM: ... no beings.
Kenzo: Skills on this.
Wellby: Just automatons.
Delwath: Yeah, I think it's just magical constructs.
Unknown: Fuck.
Delwath: Maybe undead.
Kenzo: Are we doing this in the right order?
Wellby: Too late now.
DM: I mean, you're ospreys, you could turn around and fly off.
DM: The spell lasts for an hour.
Wellby: Ah. We're doing it in the right order.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: So you go up to the very tip top.
DM: Yeah. So you-
Kenzo: Whatever we do is the right order
DM: ... uh, so you fly-
Unknown: Whatever we do
DM: ... like sort of aiming for the top.
Delwath: Like but, but I don't wanna like fly, like it's not like up and like that.
Delwath: It's like [imitates whooshing] and come down like that.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So you're coming... So the, the tower, i- the top tower extends about, like I said, about 100 feet.
DM: Um, and as you come in to land, about 20 feet before you're at the top [dice rolling]
DM: um,
DM: uh, f- four...
DM: The, the two statues raise their hands, and out of the palms of their fists these darts shoot up at the ospreys.
DM: Um-
Delwath: Darts. So they're like 150 feet below us.
DM: They're like 120 feet below you.
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
DM: Yeah. Um-
Seeker: As long as we attack
DM: ... that's one, two,
DM: three,
DM: four. Um, so that's one on each of you.
DM: They each have two attacks.
Seeker: Well, there's actually five of us.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: There are five of us.
DM: Okay. So let's see.
DM: Um,
DM: one, two, three, four.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Pierces doesn't really attack.
DM: Delwath does not get attacked.
Seeker: Nice. Thanks ladder.
Unknown: [clears throat]
Seeker: Ladder's great.
DM: Um,
DM: and
DM: all of their attacks hit.
Kenzo: What do you mean?
DM: Crystal darts are flying out of their palms straight at the osprey.
Unknown: They don't know how to hit us.
DM: They're pretty accurate.
Unknown: The fuck?
DM: They don't want-
Seeker: It's like a catapult spell. It's a magical-
DM: They don't want birds to land on the tower.
Wellby: We should see if they'll come to Vinga Sharna when they're done here.
Seeker: I know, right?
DM: Um-
Seeker: We could use-
DM: Kenzo takes-
DM: We could use a couple statues like that
DM: ... uh, the osprey is only how many hit points?
DM: The ospreys have like five hit points, so I'll subtract five.
Unknown: I, yeah.
Delwath: Right, but you lose the animal form when you lose the hit points of the animal form.
Wellby: [laughs] Oh, no.
DM: Oh.
Seeker: Wait a second. Are we gonna fall?
Unknown: No.
DM: Well, you're only gonna fall like 20 feet.
DM: Yeah, you're gonna fall.
Delwath: The transformation lasts for the duration of each target, or until the our target has no temporary hit points.
Unknown: [laughs] Whoops.
DM: Ah.
Seeker: Is it really fi-... Wait, can we-
DM: Oh, this is cool
Unknown: ...
Unknown: can we check?
Delwath: Oh, how many hit points does a hawk have?
Unknown: Yeah, I was just looking.
DM: Yeah, check. It's gonna, it's gonna do more damage than the hawk has.
Unknown: Except the, the,
Unknown: my computer's being dumb, but.
Kenzo: Can we fight these constructs?
Wellby: This says one.
DM: I think one is probably accurate for a hawk.
Unknown: Oh, God.
DM: Okay. So Kenzo appears
DM: after having taken-
Unknown: Yeah, so-
DM: ... one point of damage as a osprey, and then an additional 13 points of damage as Kenzo.
Unknown: What the fuck?
DM: And falls gently to the top of the tower.
Delwath: Oh, 'cause... Oh yeah, yeah, I see. Oh, I'm gonna die.
Delwath: Oh, God. [laughs]
Kenzo: [clears throat] Wait, so I actually do 13, take 13 points of damage.
DM: 13 takes the damage. Seeker, um, takes 12 points of damage, and then falls 20 feet to the top of tower, taking an additional
DM: 10 points of falling damage.
Unknown: All right. All right.
DM: The ladder turns back into a ladder, having taken 13 points of damage, but can fly, so does not fall.
DM: [clears throat]
Seeker: Oh, I gotta track the ladder's hit points.
DM: And Wellby-
Delwath: Oh, you have, uh... Oh, no, you also, you have 20 extra hit points.
DM: [coughs] Wellby takes-
Delwath: I cast the aid spell this morning again.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Click your hit points, change your max.
Delwath: The max HP modifier of 20.
DM: Wellby takes, uh-
Unknown: 15
DM: ... 12 points of damage.
Delwath: You haven't actually taken-
Wellby: I can candy dodge and take six.
DM: Okay. Uh, so actually it was 13.
DM: Oh, no, wait, ca- you can't, uh, you can't dodge in the osprey form.
Wellby: Fair.
DM: So you take the 12 points, and you with your Kenku armor do not take any fall damage.
Wellby: Right.
DM: [clears throat] So now you are all standing
DM: on the very top.
Delwath: Nope, Del is still flying.
DM: Oh, Delwath, Delwath is still flying.
DM: The ladder and Delwath are still flying.
DM: Delwath as a osprey, the ladder as a ladder, looking at Seeker prone on the ground, rushing to his defense.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Thank you, ladder. [clears throat]
DM: Standing guard over the ladder
DM: as you watch and wait to see what happens.
DM: You're not entirely sure whether the
DM: constructs below noticed
DM: you
DM: falling-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... because of the angle.
Unknown: Right. Um-
Wellby: I'm gonna take a look at this trap door.
Unknown: Yeah. Um-
Wellby: Is it locked, trapped?
Wellby: Open.
Delwath: Uh, I'm, I'm gonna turn out from...
Delwath: I'm gonna become back into Delwath, land and sit on the floor.
Delwath: There's no point in staying a bird.
DM: All right.
Delwath: He can always turn us back.
DM: He can turn us back. Yeah. Oh, make a constitution save for concentration.
DM: I think you have advantage.
Delwath: Just roll real dice.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. [dice rolling] So [dice rolling] that's-
Wellby: 16
DM: ... You just need to beat a 10, you're fine.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Uh, so the spell does not end.
DM: Um,
DM: the... So okay, so here's what you see.
DM: You're at the very top of this tower.
DM: Um, the, the way that it's shaped, right, so you are sort of directly above it, like 20 feet above it when you got hit.
DM: Um,
DM: there's about 10-foot-tall crenellations around the edge.
DM: So depending on how quickly you fall, it might have looked to them like
DM: the bird just fell onto the surface.
DM: You're not entirely sure whether they noticed you turning out of bird form and whether they can even fly to come get you.
Kenzo: Or whether they're even smart enough to know.
DM: Or whether they're even smart enough to know.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Let's, uh, let's stay
DM: You might have a minute of breathing space.
DM: Um-
Seeker: So I tell the, suggest to the ladder that it stay down low.
DM: Yeah, yeah, it immediately rushed down to like...
DM: [whooshes] And it crouches down next to Seeker.
DM: So you see, so the entire surface is smooth black.
DM: Um, this space is only about, uh,
DM: it's about a third of the size, so instead of a 50-foot diameter, it's about maybe, say, a 20-foot,
DM: 15-foot diameter.
DM: It's like a pretty narrow
DM: tower.
DM: Um, the, the trapdoor is just, you don't see any obvious handle.
DM: It's just a smooth, there's like a, um,
DM: a, just a smooth crack in the top of the thing.
DM: Um, no clear obvious way, uh, to lift it.
Wellby: We've, unclear obvious ways.
Delwath: Um, remember how I said I should have taken knock?
Delwath: No, that would've been too obvious.
Wellby: We have a charm of opening.
Delwath: That's true. We have a charm of opening.
DM: Um, well you don't know if it's locked, it's just-
Unknown: That's true
DM: ... maybe there's j- maybe it just pushes up from the bottom.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: But a charm of opening would just open things.
DM: Yes, that's true, the charm of... So make an investigation check.
Wellby: Investigation check is, uh, [dice rolling] um, 20.
Delwath: Magic.
DM: Uh, detect magic?
Delwath: Yeah. I guess it takes me a minute.
DM: So it still takes you a minute.
Delwath: Yeah, okay. Hmm.
Delwath: It's probably,
Delwath: he's investigating.
DM: Well, Wellby's investigating, what's everybody else doing?
Delwath: I'm gonna cast detect magic.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: Somebody keep guard.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: I'm not sure what I'm gonna do.
DM: Who's keeping guard?
Unknown: I'll keep guard.
DM: Okay.
DM: I'll-
Delwath: Kenzo in the ladder should keep guard.
DM: Make a, Kenzo, make a perception check.
Unknown: D20?
DM: D20.
Seeker: Plus?
DM: Uh, I don't know, you gotta, I think it's plus five.
Unknown: I think it's plus five also. [dice rolling]
Unknown: Fuck. 13.
Delwath: You, you could use heroic inspiration if you want.
Unknown: Is it here?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Wait, what's this for again? Perception-
DM: Just keeping guard.
Delwath: Just keeping guard.
Kenzo: I, no, gotta save the heroic inspiration for something-
DM: Hmm
Kenzo: ... more, more awesome than this.
DM: Okay, and Seeker is-
Seeker: Um, tremor sense.
DM: Hmm.
Wellby: Good call.
DM: Ah, okay.
DM: Um,
DM: interesting. How, what's the range of that?
Seeker: I think it said 30 feet.
Unknown: Um-
DM: 'Cause you're, I mean, technically anything moving in the tower is connected to the same surface.
Seeker: Right.
DM: But 30 feet would just, would not reach down below the top of this spire.
Unknown: Oh, 60 feet.
DM: That still doesn't reach down below the top of the spire.
DM: So you can sense anything in the spire, but not anything in the lower part of the tower.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Sounds like that matters.
DM: Just for my information.
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: a, a minute or two passes as Wellby looks around.
DM: Um, you can see, so you do see a sort of re- recessed, like a faintly recessed area that looks like the way this is designed is it's not designed for you to be
DM: able to come from the outside.
DM: It's designed that you open it and there's like a, a little notch that it latches into, and it stays open while you're up, and then you close it when you come down.
DM: But if, if you're, it's not open, it's not designed to open from the top.
Delwath: I mean, I guess if you were super strong you could try and just lift it off.
Wellby: Sure, sure. We understand the direction of the hinge and-
DM: Yeah. The way it hinges is it hinges up like this.
DM: It, it can be sort of latched in place on the top.
Wellby: Like a big suction cup.
Seeker: Uh, move the ladder.
DM: That's right.
Delwath: Why don't we just use the charm of opening? We've never used it before.
Wellby: I think it's noisy.
Wellby: Take a look at that.
Delwath: I mean, are we really concerned about noise?
Delwath: I could cast silence. [dice rolling]
Wellby: Oh, I love it. Yeah. Strike it.
Wellby: Each time you strike it, one lock or latch opens.
Wellby: If no locks or latches remain, the object itself opens.
Wellby: So if it's unlocked, it opens.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: If it's locked, we unlock it, then it opens.
Unknown: Cool.
Kenzo: Yeah. Why not? Silence.
DM: So are you gonna do that?
Wellby: I like silence.
Delwath: Uh, oh, hold on.
DM: Go ahead.
Delwath: So should we cast silence?
Kenzo: Yeah. Is it a low level spell?
Unknown: Like is it-
Delwath: I mean, I could cast it as a ritual.
Unknown: Oh, let's do that.
Delwath: It just takes 10 minutes, but.
Unknown: Yeah, let's do that.
Delwath: Are we okay to take 10 minutes, or I could burn a slot.
Unknown: No.
Kenzo: I don't burn a slot.
Kenzo: Take 10 minutes.
Unknown: Okay. Everybody roll initiative.
DM: You two with disadvantage.
Unknown: What?
Delwath: Who has disadvantage? Hold on, hold on.
Unknown: You two.
Delwath: Has detect magic already been cast?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Disadvantage gives you-
Kenzo: Well, we get advantage, right?
DM: Uh, no.
Kenzo: Or is, or is our advantage canceled out?
DM: It cancels out.
Seeker: Fucking advantage.
DM: Got an 18.
Unknown: 29.
Delwath: One.
Delwath: Uh, three actually.
DM: 29 [laughs].
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Oh my God, you are ridiculous.
Wellby: Does my halfling luck re-roll ones on initiative?
DM: Any roll.
Unknown: Yep, any roll.
DM: Re-do 20 roll.
Wellby: In that case, 18.
DM: Okay, what did you roll?
Delwath: A one. Well, three total.
DM: Oh, wait, you might change things around.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Okay, so, um, Kenzo notices the two statues, like having not noticed the little mechanical fly they
DM: sent to spy on the top to see whether anybody was there.
DM: Does, however, notice the two flying constructs rising up to this level-
Unknown: Ah
DM: ... as they move to attack, and shouts a warning as you spring, I mean, you don't have to attack them, but they're clearly looking like they're about to shoot more darts
DM: at you.
Kenzo: And what... How far away are they?
DM: Like, they're... You just see the tops of their heads coming over the edge of the battlements.
Unknown: And how big are they again?
Seeker: They're like 9 feet tall.
DM: They're like 9 feet tall.
Seeker: They're stone statues with metal hands.
DM: Stone statues with metal hands
DM: that apparently can fire darts.
Kenzo: I mean, I don't know if there's an advantage to anybody else going first, so I'm just gonna give advantage to one of them.
DM: So wait, sorry, Kenzo was-
Kenzo: Are you going first? I have a 29.
Wellby: I mean, another thought is we chime of opening, and just
Wellby: get-
Kenzo: Go in. Go in
DM: What was, what was, uh...
DM: Well, Kenzo gets the jump on everybody, so-
Wellby: Yeah, 18
Unknown: But I can, but I can swap as well
DM: ... so actually Wellby does, Wellby does-
Delwath: But you can both... Both of you could swap
DM: What was Seeker?
Seeker: I got a total of eight.
DM: [laughs] Okay.
DM: So the two super alert ones,
DM: uh, notice these things, and nudge everybody.
DM: Dalwath is just trying to, like, is distracted trying to start this ritual for silence, and Seeker's-
Kenzo: I mean, do you want-
DM: I don't know, chatting with the ladder
Unknown: ... does anybody just chat, or do we just dive into the hole?
Kenzo: Dive in? Or do we stay out here and fight these things?
Wellby: I think we...
Wellby: I think we try to conserve-
Unknown: Can I-
Wellby: ... hit points-
Unknown: Wait, I can, I can-
Wellby: ... and we'll take less damage if we run rather than fight
Kenzo: ... hold on, hold on. I can, I can, um, also, uh, bonus action,
Kenzo: uh, or what is it? I can just...
Kenzo: Like how strong are these things? Can I do like a, an ultra fast-
DM: You, you can... Wow.
DM: That would... Yes. On your turn you can 100% bonus action soul sight them.
Kenzo: I mean, I can just go first soul sight, let us, you know, see are these, these things gonna...
Unknown: If they're super nasty, we can just dive in.
Delwath: Can you bring somebody with you when you move?
Kenzo: I can bring somebody with me when I move.
Delwath: Does that take a bonus action also?
DM: That does also take your bonus action.
Delwath: Like, what if he just moves as an...
DM: No, he has to use step of the wind to take somebody with him.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: But if you use step of the wind, you can move like 100 feet and carry somebody with you, but you can't soul sight and step of the wind.
Delwath: Well, you could soul sight as an action, but then you couldn't attack.
DM: Then you couldn't attack.
Wellby: I, I think we should flee as quickly as possible.
Seeker: We've just got to get the door open first.
Wellby: I think you and I should swap initiative.
Wellby: I'll ring the chime.
Wellby: If it doesn't immediately open, you grab the chime and ring it,
Wellby: and then
Wellby: we can all start-
DM: Well-
Wellby: ... moving in.
DM: Yeah. So Seeker and Dalwath are caught somewhat by surprise, so they are before the...
Delwath: Right. But you could bring Seeker with you.
Kenzo: I can. If, if the, if it opens, then I can bring, I can grab Speaker, Sneaker, Skeeter.
Delwath: But, but you can also-
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: ... you can presumably soul sight as an action.
Kenzo: I can't soul sight.
Delwath: You don't have to bonus action soul sight.
Kenzo: Yeah, I can't soul sight as an action.
DM: Yes. You can soul sight as an action.
Delwath: So you, if we're running, you could soul sight them just to know what we were running away from.
Unknown: Sure.
Wellby: I think-
Kenzo: That's fine
Wellby: ... so first though is-
Unknown: Chime
Wellby: ... ring the chime.
Kenzo: You're, so we're gonna swap-
Wellby: So once we swap-
Unknown: Yep
Wellby: ... I'm up first, I ring the chime.
DM: [chime] Thing opens.
Seeker: Nice.
Kenzo: Is that your action?
Wellby: Uh, so that's the action, then I have a move.
Delwath: You can do a object interaction as part of a move.
DM: Not activate a magic item.
Wellby: Right, right. It's, that's an action.
Wellby: So I'll, uh,
Wellby: I'll briefly look around and say, "I'm, I'm gonna go scout ahead."
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: And I'll jump down into the hole.
Delwath: Did you take observant?
DM: No, he didn't take observant.
Unknown: Oh, he took a bard instead.
DM: He took elven. He took-
Delwath: 'Cause this would be a time when searching as a bonus action would actually be useful.
DM: Would be very useful.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: He took sharpshooter.
Delwath: Oh, which is better.
DM: Which is also very good.
Unknown: Which is-
DM: Okay, so, so Kenzo's up.
DM: Wellby jumps down into the hole.
Delwath: Is it... What's down there?
Wellby: What's down there? Yeah.
DM: There's a ladder.
DM: Um, I'll tell you in a minute.
DM: The rest of you don't know yet.
Wellby: Well, already we have one ally.
DM: [laughs] That's correct.
Kenzo: Um, I will now...
Kenzo: Um, yeah, I'm gonna, I'll, I'll bonus action...
Kenzo: Well, okay, I'm gonna action soul sight the thing.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Tell me.
DM: Um, so it is, like, CR 13-ish.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: There's two of them.
Kenzo: We are, we are, we are choosing wisely.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: I mean-
Seeker: Run away
DM: ... keep in mind, monsters don't quite scale.
DM: And so, like, a dragon would be CR 20-ish.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Generally speaking, you can, you should be able to take on...
DM: A hard fight would be twice your level in CR.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: I mean, a hard, like, a hard fight.
DM: Like, you might not survive fight.
Kenzo: Yeah, but this is like, let's save our...
Unknown: I mean, this, this-
Unknown: It's... No, saving is wise
Delwath: ... yeah, this, this is... Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, they'll be lurking around here when we try and escape, but that's okay.
Unknown: That's fine. We'll just teleport out.
Delwath: What, what else are they?
Unknown: What else? But so-
DM: Oh. Oh, yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... hold on. Tell us the whole soul sight
DM: ... let me give you all their...
DM: Uh, they are immune to basically everything.
DM: Charm, exhaustion, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poison, which is kind of the standard construct, doesn't have a
DM: soul as-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... they're also immune to poison damage.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: They are resistant to force and psychic damage,
DM: and bludgeoning, piercing, slashing from non-magical attacks, but that doesn't matter to any of you.
DM: They are extremely good at strength and constitution.
Delwath: Ah, but force is what his ladder uses, right?
DM: Yes.
DM: They are extremely good at strength and constitution.
DM: They are bad at charisma.
Delwath: Banish.
Unknown: Bad at charisma.
Delwath: That's banish.
Kenzo: How many things can you banish?
Unknown: One?
Unknown: Two or three.
DM: Oh, that's great.
Kenzo: Um, what kind of movies do they like?
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Romantic, romantic comedies I guess.
DM: Violent ones.
Unknown: Yes. No. [laughs]
Delwath: Solsite doesn't tell us anything about hit points, right?
Unknown: No.
DM: No, it just tells you level.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay, so force damage-
DM: All right, so, so anyway
Delwath: ... force and psychic, that's like all of your damage.
Unknown: That's rough for Seeker.
Unknown: That's really rough for you.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Well, we're not gonna fight them.
DM: No, but Seeker can also change...
DM: Well, oh, you could change the ladder.
DM: Oh, no, 'cause you already summoned that.
Unknown: I could change-
Delwath: The ladder to do a different kind of-
DM: Could you make it, like, fire with your...
Delwath: But it's not a spell.
DM: No, isn't that, like, the h- doesn't...
DM: Look at your thing.
Unknown: Can you go out and change?
Seeker: Oh, yeah, yeah. The...
Delwath: Okay. But anyway, you are taking damage.
DM: You can give it a fire.
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I, Kenzo-
DM: Kenzo runs, grabs Seeker, jumps down the hole
Kenzo: ... yeah, yeah. Like, super ultra fast.
DM: Thank you.
Kenzo: Seeker doesn't even know what the hell is going on, and all of a sudden it's like, whoop.
Unknown: Whoa [laughs].
Unknown: And then is that done.
DM: Um, Delwath is in for a bit of a rough time, though.
DM: [dice rolling] Um-
Delwath: I mean, I have a pretty good AC.
DM: Yeah, maybe it'll miss.
DM: [dice rolling] Um, I can't see.
DM: That's a 17.
Unknown: That misses.
DM: That misses. [dice rolling] Oh, geez, another 17.
DM: [dice rolling]
Seeker: They're shooting darts?
DM: They're shooting darts. That's a 28.
Seeker: Oh, fuck.
Unknown: That hits. [dice rolling]
DM: That's an 18.
Unknown: One dart.
DM: One dart hits, and they move.
DM: They shoot four darts at you, and then they fly up and over and they land next to you.
Unknown: Okay. [dice rolling]
DM: Uh, the darts, ooh, that's...
DM: The one dart that hits does 10 points of damage.
Delwath: That's like nothing.
Unknown: Who cares?
Seeker: It's a bee sting. No problem.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: What's, what's the-
Delwath: 10 points of damage, that's... I'm not even, I'm not even at, out of eight yet.
Delwath: Actually, none of you are either.
Unknown: Out of what?
Delwath: You have to add 20 to-
Unknown: Yeah, I got it. Yeah
Delwath: ... we haven't, I haven't burned that yet.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: We're still in our free hit point zone.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So
DM: that was their turns.
Unknown: Those, those are our free hit points?
DM: The two of them landed next to Delwath.
Delwath: Okay. What, what's down the...
Delwath: What's below me? I mean, I can see down there, right?
Unknown: Um, into the, into the hole?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, yes. Seeker, I assume, commands the ladder to run as well.
Seeker: Oh, yes.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, so you are looking down
DM: at... Oops, where did my list go?
Unknown: When we, um-
Delwath: And can I close-
Unknown: ... shut the door
Delwath: ... well, I, I haven't escaped yet.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Delwath: Can I close the door? That I can do as part of a move, right?
DM: That you can do as part of your move.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That's your free... Where did I?
Kenzo: It'd be funny if, like, they're not allowed to open the door and follow us.
DM: [laughs] They're just down-
Delwath: Or what would be even more funny is if they have a magic key to open the door to follow us.
Unknown: That would... And then-
DM: Or if we can't
Kenzo: ... and now instead of fighting them, like, out in the open, we're, like, all stuck in a tunnel and like, uh-
Delwath: Okay. But honestly, being stuck in a tunnel to fight them feels bad
DM: ... you are in-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you are looking down in a small room
DM: ... 'cause they can fly.
DM: It's only about, it's say maybe-
Delwath: Oh, they can fly
DM: ... 20 feet in diameter.
DM: Um, on one wall there are manacles chained to the wa- ha- hanging on the wall.
DM: Um, and there is a,
DM: a channel carved into the floor that spirals and spirals and spirals and spirals downwards.
Delwath: So this is the killing place.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: The manacles are gonna try and attack you and bind you.
Unknown: Probably.
Delwath: Is there-
Wellby: That's okay
Delwath: ... okay, and the ladder's in the center?
Unknown: And, hold up. And?
DM: Uh, I'm not done yet. Um, no, actually the ladder's offset.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Right? So the, the room is not in the center of the, the big thing.
DM: The ladder is-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... the description was a little bit i- inaccurate.
DM: The trapdoor is not in the center of the-
Delwath: Right, right. Okay. It's like-
DM: ... it's on the edge
Delwath: ... yeah, yeah. Okay.
DM: So the ladder comes down like a wall.
DM: Um, there is also what looks like a,
DM: um,
DM: a
DM: anvil
DM: s- up against the, a wall on the opposite side of the-
Delwath: Hey, we found the divine forge already.
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... it's on, it's on the opposite side of the
DM: manacles.
DM: Um, and there's a line in the floor that runs from...
DM: There's like a, a well in the center.
DM: There's this channel that goes around to a well, and then there's like a line that runs-
Unknown: Right from the channel
DM: ... from the well in the center to the,
DM: to the forge that kind of cuts through the...
DM: So, like, you can imagine if you filled the circle, it would be like spirals around and then a line that goes like this from the center through the spirals to where the forge is.
Seeker: Ah, okay, found the forge.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, you can see, I mean, you don't have much time.
DM: It's, it's completely black, but everybody has darkvision, right?
DM: Um, you don't have much time to look around.
DM: Uh, it's a small, I mean, it's a small anvil, right?
DM: It's not, this isn't like a huge forge construct.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It looks like nothing like that.
DM: There's like, what seem like bits of construction and things scattered around.
DM: Um-
Delwath: How far is it from?
DM: It's about 10 feet down-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... from the ceiling.
Wellby: And what's the exit from this room?
DM: Um, there are stairs down.
Delwath: Like weaving from
Delwath: one of the-
DM: So there's like basically four sides, right?
DM: So-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... manacles, forge, ladder, stairs.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Okay. Well, I will disengage-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... as my action, climb down, closing the trapdoor behind me.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: And then
Delwath: s- stand on the ground.
Unknown: Stand on the what? Ladder?
Unknown: I mean, uh-
Unknown: Go down to the ground.
DM: The stairs, the door?
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Closing the door behind me.
Delwath: I mean, I, honestly, I have a climb speed, right?
Delwath: I can... Can I f- would I be able to fight kind of okay f- hanging onto the wall?
Delwath: I guess I need, I couldn't really use my shield.
DM: You'd need a free hand to be hanging onto the wall.
Delwath: Right. So I'd have to-
DM: You'd either have to not use your shield and fight with your sword, or use your shield and cast a spell.
Kenzo: So manacles, is it sort of like sucking out the spirits, the souls of people, and they get put into the stuff in a forge?
Wellby: Or is it like- Draining their blood and then the forge is powered by blood?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Spiric forge. So we're in this room-
Seeker: Just putting in, in the dark crystal
Wellby: ... safe, at least for the moment?
Delwath: Okay. I am going-
DM: For possibly a very short moment
Delwath: ... I am going to...
Delwath: Well, I mean, my turn is-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... is I can't do anything. I'm not doing anything with my bonus action.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: So I'm just-
DM: Just shutting the door
Delwath: ... shutting the door, but I'm not going all the way down
DM: Putting the forge in the hole again.
Unknown: Like-
DM: Okay
Unknown: ... I'm gonna-
DM: Maybe like hanging at the top
Delwath: ... hang like close to the top, and as soon as I can, I'm gonna ready an action-
DM: Let's do it
Delwath: ... to cast Sorcerer's Burst if they come through.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Which-
Unknown: With...
Delwath: Uh, wait, hold on.
Delwath: They were not immune.
Unknown: Acid damage would be good against them, right?
DM: Acid's fine. Any... It seemed like the only thi- so force, and psychic, and poison would be bad.
Wellby: It just strikes me that I,
Wellby: I pull out one of the, the dart that hit me, and I've got a few drops of blood.
Wellby: Just sort of idly splash those on the forge in case that, I don't know-
DM: On the forge?
Wellby: See if it does anything.
DM: Yeah, nothing happens.
Wellby: All right. Yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: I mean, so Dalwath is hanging on the top of the ladder.
DM: What are the rest of the three of you doing?
Wellby: I'm gonna scout the stairway down.
DM: Like start going down the stairs?
Wellby: Eh, like look through-
Delwath: Look for traps on the top stair [laughs]
Wellby: ... check for traps, see what's going on.
Delwath: Is there anything magic up here?
Seeker: Yes, I think.
Delwath: I already had to take my magic off.
DM: You have to take magic off.
DM: Uh, yeah. Okay.
Seeker: Let's magic.
DM: Um, the...
DM: I mean, the manacles are magic.
DM: The f- the forge is not magic.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: It's really just the manacles.
Delwath: What kind of magic?
Seeker: Well, I could use Identify on the manacles.
Delwath: No, save your Identify.
DM: You could.
Delwath: Although,
Delwath: maybe not.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Up to you
DM: ... it seems to be-
Seeker: The manacles may be the most interesting thing we see today
DM: ... necromantic.
Unknown: Necromancy. Fuck.
Seeker: Oh, man.
Seeker: I, [laughs] I identify the manacles.
DM: Okay. That's what Seeker's doing.
Wellby: Checking for traps and
DM: Checking for traps
Wellby: ... doing that.
DM: What's Kenzo doing?
Kenzo: Yeah, I'll, I'll search. I'll do investigation.
DM: Okay.
DM: So you wanna just help him, then he can roll with advantage?
Seeker: Perfect. [dice rolling] Nice.
Seeker: 27.
Wellby: Uh, yeah, 27.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: so
DM: Identify casts a minute to touch and, or cast, and you have to touch the thing you're identifying, just to let you know.
Seeker: Oh.
Seeker: Actually, I have to touch the thing?
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um-
Seeker: Isn't he doing it with the goggles?
Wellby: Touching with a go- seems like we're
Seeker: Isn't it, isn't it the goggles?
Wellby: ... grabbing risk.
Seeker: No, but isn't it goggles?
Unknown: That's-
Seeker: Like, but he just looks at it with the goggles
Unknown: ... but no, you always have to touch the thing
Seeker: Why do you have to touch it with the goggles?
Kenzo: The goggles are like, "Oh, I just see the things."
Wellby: So you're touching with your vision.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: I'm gonna touch them really carefully.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: [laughs] Oh, Seeker.
Seeker: Seeker, Seeker, Seeker.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Curiosity is so often rewarded.
DM: I know. Okay. So, um-
Wellby: Very true
Delwath: Has it ever actually been rewarded?
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs] Once or twice.
DM: A, a, a minute or so passes.
DM: The-
Unknown: Like-
DM: ... it doesn't seem like anything's coming immediately from the top.
Delwath: Okay. Like after a little bit, I'm gonna stop.
Delwath: Um, is there any-
Unknown: What he should've done is just tried trimming some skin while
Delwath: ... is the wall, is the stone, is stone?
DM: It's stone, yeah.
Delwath: Is there any magic above me?
DM: No.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
DM: Um, while you are search- so you're searching, um, there does not...
DM: You, you're pretty confident that these, this top of the stairs is safe.
DM: But you do just about, as you finish like checking quickly, as Seeker's finishing off with identification, you hear what sounds like a door shutting below.
Wellby: Like the big double doors that the constructs flew down to?
DM: The, yeah, well you can't, it...
DM: You wouldn't probably be able to hear the big double doors at the bottom.
Unknown: No, no, no.
DM: The door at the bottom of the steps.
Unknown: The middle.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: The door at the bottom of the step?
DM: Of the bottom of the tower.
Unknown: This door.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: The constructs came in the other way.
Wellby: The, it's from the-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... upper door.
DM: And are now probably going up the steps.
Wellby: Well, that's
Wellby: fine. We can go back out the top again and [laughs]
Seeker: We switch back to ospreys.
Wellby: So let's-
Delwath: Or we just fight 'em.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: This room seems like a good spot to fight 'em.
Unknown: We can-
DM: Seeker
Delwath: ... we can hold the stairs
DM: ... make a constitution saving throw.
Wellby: Fuck.
Seeker: Oh, God.
Wellby: Heroic. Heroic saving.
DM: Or actually, sorry, wisdom.
Seeker: A wisdom saving throw.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: I have plus, uh, zero.
DM: Zero. [dice rolling]
Seeker: And that is a 18.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Ooh.
DM: You stare as you touch very gently the, the chains, and you look at them.
DM: These are...
DM: Uh, so these are
DM: chains that are used to rip the souls from people's bodies and feed them to a lich's phylactery.
Seeker: Oh.
Wellby: Ah.
Seeker: Feed them to the phylactery. For what purpose?
Delwath: You know what we should show to the mirror?
Delwath: These would tell us what his phylactery was, right?
Seeker: Oh.
Wellby: Yes.
Unknown: Probably.
Seeker: Well, and how does the feeding to the phylactery work?
Seeker: Does the phylactery have to be here?
DM: You don't know from the-
Seeker: Yeah, okay
DM: ... just the Identify spell.
DM: But you know, like all, all you can get with...
DM: I mean, this is a complicated artifact, right?
DM: But like from your Identify it's...
DM: Well, actually go ahead and make an arcana check.
Seeker: That's what I'm talking about.
Seeker: And I'm, I'm wearing the goggles, so I think I get advantage.
DM: So you're advantage, yeah.
Delwath: [laughs] [dice rolling] Oh, natural 1.
Seeker: 20 and 19. [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Natural one.
Seeker: Wow. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Whoa.
DM: Okay. Seeker, Seeker's like touching this.
Unknown: So that's how you die.
DM: And he like shakes off the curse that's trying to seep into his hands.
DM: He's like, "Not today, curse."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And then he looks it, looks carefully.
DM: Um, so yes, this is, this item is used as part of the ritual to basically create a lich.
DM: Like you would-
Seeker: Whoa
DM: ... have these, like obviously somebody was sacrificed, or many people were sacrificed, chained up against this wall.
DM: And as Um, the magic of these chains when they're...
DM: Normally if somebody is killed in Tal'Dorei, their souls go off to the land of the dead, and they walk through and they find their gods.
DM: But not if you're killed while you're held by these chains.
DM: Your souls don't go off to the land of the dead.
DM: Your souls go to the liche's phylactery.
DM: And once you have
DM: killed enough souls,
DM: you can use the phylactery to create potion of transformation, which you then drink to turn into a liche.
Seeker: So he did this process for himself?
DM: Yes.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: And the phylactery has to be here for the souls to absorb it.
Seeker: It does.
Delwath: Uh, so probably if we could show the mirror...
Delwath: Wait, we don't have a mirror charge now, do we?
DM: Yes, you do.
Delwath: Fuck. Should we just do it?
Unknown: Fuck.
Seeker: Just hope nobody shoots a dart at the mirror and breaks it.
Seeker: [laughs]
Delwath: No, no, no, no, we have to kill these guys first.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Coming up the stairs. Fuck.
Delwath: I, I think we should just look at these things, right?
Delwath: Don't you wanna know how Apollyon became a liche?
Seeker: Like, how, who did he kill to do it, and what was the-
Delwath: And what is his phylactery like?
DM: What, what, what's the phylactery?
Kenzo: Yeah, that's the most important thing.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. We need to see.
Kenzo: 'Cause that's what we're trying to get out of the, out of the Rye's hand.
Delwath: And I doubt the... I bet you we're not gonna be able-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... to bring... It would be hard to bring these manacles with.
Delwath: Like, I pre- presume they're...
Unknown: They're chained to the wall.
Unknown: Chained to the wall.
Unknown: They're built into the wall.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like, this room was specially constructed to turn yourself-
Unknown: Like-
DM: ... into a liche.
Unknown: Yes
Delwath: ... I mean, we have some magic that can manipulate
Delwath: stone and earth, right? But probably it's gonna be hard to get these out of here.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, okay, so cool.
Delwath: [laughs] I, I think we should take out the mirror, but I think we need to make sure that...
DM: Wellby now hears the sta-
Unknown: Yeah, we-
DM: Well, you don't actually hear... No, they-
Unknown: No, uh-
Seeker: ... they're walking. They're not gonna be flying
Seeker: ... uh, we don't need to go down those stairs.
Seeker: I can wall of stone them up.
Delwath: But hold on. Wait, what's...
Delwath: Can we have, like, 30 seconds to-
DM: Yep, you've got 30 seconds
Unknown: ... make a plan?
DM: But you hear them coming up.
DM: You hear footsteps on the stairs.
Seeker: No, I can just literally put a wall of stone blocking the stairs completely.
Delwath: Yeah. But I think we should just fight them.
Unknown: To keep the concentration you would use animal shape.
Delwath: Yeah, but give up animal shape if you want.
Delwath: Let's, let's just kill them. Let's just make a plan and kill them.
Seeker: I don't... I, I need-
Unknown: Right
Seeker: ... to figure out what attacks I can actually use against them.
Delwath: I mean, while we get to, like, Delwath and...
Delwath: I think the best plan is to try and keep them, like...
Delwath: Okay, I'm trying to picture the stairs.
DM: It's like a spiral staircase that emerges
DM: off of the top.
Kenzo: You and I just drop down, engage them in melee.
Kenzo: You shoot them from up there, and then-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... um, Seeker, you know, watches some movies on YouTube.
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, yeah.
Delwath: Uh, I...
Delwath: Yeah, right? Like, um,
Delwath: I mean, I can, I can...
Delwath: They're not immune to... They had no resistance to radiant damage, right?
DM: Nope.
Seeker: So their wisdom was neither strong nor weak.
DM: Didn't show up. Charisma...
Delwath: Oh, but they have a really good con save.
DM: Con and-
Delwath: They'll probably make the second radiant save
DM: ... con and con and strength are their saves.
Seeker: I c- I can try zero resistance-
Unknown: How was dex?
Seeker: ... to a curiosity on them.
DM: What?
Wellby: How's, how was dex for them?
DM: Didn't show up. Didn't come up.
Seeker: An int?
DM: Didn't come up.
Seeker: Okay. So any of those are worth trying.
Unknown: Ow. Huh.
DM: Uh, remember, they're immune to charm.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, so I can't use zero resistance for curiosity.
Seeker: But what about psychic disruption?
Kenzo: Uncanny metabolism is so great, but I have barely, I haven't used any...
Kenzo: Oh, I, actually we haven't done a short rest.
Kenzo: We haven't done it. We haven't rested.
DM: No, you used your free use-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... of the sense. You didn't need to use it before.
DM: So you should have ardor key.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh.
Unknown: I'll say that.
Delwath: Hey, Tim, I didn't realize fountain of moonlight wasn't a bonus action.
Delwath: That's a big disadvantage compared to spirit shroud.
DM: Is spirit shroud a bonus action?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Oh, it just means you gotta spend two sorcery points.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: You can s- we can switch it around.
Delwath: No, no, no, no, no, it's fine.
Delwath: It's fine. I have time to plan right now anyway, so it doesn't matter.
DM: Oh, you know why that is, is it's be- designed for druids, and you're supposed to bonus action wild shape, action cast the spell.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: I mean, it fit nicely the way we were-
Delwath: It does
DM: ... born with the spells.
Unknown: It does.
Unknown: And I don't think that two sorcery points is that big a deal.
Unknown: Yeah, it's not.
Kenzo: Hey, so you know, Tim, I've got-
Unknown: Oh
Kenzo: ... I've got disciplined survivor.
Unknown: There's a constitution as well.
Kenzo: I can, I can, um, spend.
Unknown: Must use.
Kenzo: I can re-roll. Oh, but I must use the new roll.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Well, you'd only use it if you failed, so.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: If you fail a save, though, keep that in mind 'cause you can try again.
Kenzo: Yeah, but I can only try it again once.
Delwath: They're immune to charm, so I, there's no point in trying to charm them.
Delwath: They didn't have particularly good...
DM: Bad at charisma.
Seeker: I could use watery sphere, which would trap them, and then I can push them down the stairs inside of it.
Seeker: [laughs]
Delwath: I mean, the problem is actually I have no charisma targeting spells except banish, which is not that wor- which isn't really worth it.
Seeker: Well, that, that's a strength save, and they're good at strength.
DM: They're good at strength.
Seeker: Yeah, so I shouldn't use that one.
Seeker: That would be funny, but
Seeker: I think it's gonna be psychic disruption.
Delwath: Um, I assume conjure animals, the slashing damage is magical, right?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
Seeker: 'Cause that can in- they can't be immune to incapacitated, though.
DM: Nope.
Seeker: Okay, so there.
Delwath: So I think the main thing is, is there a way we can keep them from getting past Delwath and Kenzo?
Delwath: We need to, like, try and block the...
Delwath: Fill the stair-
DM: So here we go
Unknown: ... right.
DM: I have a little-
Delwath: Oh, you have a map
DM: ... we can actually draw a map of it.
Kenzo: So they're immune to charm, right?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: They're immune to charm.
Kenzo: So, so, uh, disrupting strike's not gonna work.
DM: [laughs] Correct.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh, they were immune to...
Delwath: 'Cause if we can, if we can hold the line so they-
DM: Charm, frightened. They're not immune to stun, but they have good con saves.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: If we can hold the line so they can't easily get through.
Wellby: I feel like we can hold them in the doorway probably.
Seeker: W- maybe I could, like, wall of stone.
Delwath: No concentration. Keep, keep-
Seeker: No, I can't wall of stone
Delwath: ... don't use a concentration spell.
DM: So it's actually... I'm drawing this very poorly.
Seeker: Okay. Watery sphere is concentration too.
Delwath: Yeah. Not, I mean, not using concentration's kind of limiting.
Delwath: See, what I'm trying to envision is where is the ceiling,
Delwath: where is the ceiling above the-
DM: How about I draw a circle that's...
DM: If I put it here and here.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: No, but that's only three.
DM: How do you draw a 20-foot diameter circle?
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Oh, I do it from here.
DM: So it's two in all directions from here.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah. Nice.
DM: Okay. So the ladder going up is right here.
DM: The stairs-
Unknown: Ah, fuck.
Seeker: They're immune to force damage?
DM: They're resistant to force damage.
Delwath: No, they're resistant. I think half force damage.
Seeker: Oh.
DM: The stairs coming up are, like, here.
DM: The manacles are there, and the anvil is there.
Delwath: Okay. But, like, if Delwath was standing on the top stair and Kenzo was flying in the air above-
Seeker: Oh, the ladder can just physically obstruct the entire stairway.
Delwath: And the ladder [paper rustles] Right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Try and grapple them when they run into it.
Unknown: Right, like-
Seeker: It would be force damage to grapple, yeah
Delwath: ... so if Kenzo's stand-
Seeker: Ah
Delwath: ... here's what I'm envisioning. Kenzo fly above the stairs and, like, punch them while flying.
Seeker: Okay.
Delwath: Delwath then stands at the top stair and attacks them,
Delwath: and then, um,
Delwath: uh, the ladder is next to Kenzo.
Delwath: Like, the goal is to try and block them from coming up.
Seeker: Yeah, we're box- we're boxing them in
Delwath: ... try and box them in, and then Wellby peppers them with arrows.
Delwath: And with sharpshooter, it doesn't...
Delwath: I don't know, it never matters if you're shooting past your allies anyway, but...
Delwath: And you can, I don't know, do stuff.
Seeker: Wish I still had heat metal.
Seeker: They have metal hands.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Too bad I couldn't deflect missiles as an osprey.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Too bad.
Seeker: That would've been funny.
DM: That would've been very funny.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: Um, these were CR 13, and there's two of them.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: So it's kind of worth probably pumping a few spells into this.
Seeker: Yeah, I'm gonna...
Delwath: I think I'm gonna go with,
Delwath: I think I'm gonna go with, um, Font of Moonlight, although it's a con-
Seeker: I can also Telekinesis them
Kenzo: ... so let me see.
Kenzo: They're, they're resistant to psychic damage?
DM: They're resistant to psychic damage.
DM: Immune.
Seeker: Oh, psychic, yeah. Resistant.
DM: They're immune to poison.
Seeker: All right.
DM: Okay. You guys ready? You've had-
Seeker: Yeah
DM: ... plenty of time to plan.
Seeker: Totally.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: Go ahead and roll initiative.
Seeker: Fuck yeah. [dice rolling]
DM: Regular straight rolls or advantage?
DM: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Uh, that's, that's [dice rolling] a big six.
Seeker: 25.
Wellby: 20 for me.
Delwath: Uh, 11.
DM: Okay, 20 Wellby.
Wellby: Yep.
Seeker: 25 Kenzo.
DM: I got it. 11 Delwath.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: And six for Seeker.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: This is gonna be like every battle-
Seeker: Yeah
DM: ... that we play this morning. Do you want to switch with anybody?
Delwath: You two should swap so that-
Wellby: I go first?
Delwath: ... Kenzo has advantage.
Wellby: Oh, I have-
Delwath: Uh, 'cause if he hits you have advantage.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah. All right, cool.
Delwath: Um, I mean-
Seeker: This is so great
Delwath: ... I assume we positioned before initiative started.
DM: Yeah, yeah, you can position before initiative.
Delwath: And I can cast a spell before initiative starts?
DM: Uh, yeah-
Unknown: If-
DM: ... if it's a short... I mean, sure, yes.
DM: I mean, combat's not gonna last more than 10 rounds, so-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... you're casting a minute duration.
Delwath: Yeah. Well, I haven't decided if I'm casting...
Delwath: I think I'm just gonna cast Font of Moonlight.
Seeker: Quantum Moonlight?
Delwath: Font, Font of Moonlight.
Seeker: You should get Quantum Moonlight.
Seeker: That would be much better.
Kenzo: Yeah, it would, because it's cooler. [laughs]
Delwath: I mean, resistance to radiant doesn't help me that much.
Seeker: Why is this?
Kenzo: [sighs] That was amazing. You both sighed at exactly the same time.
Delwath: Is it better-
Seeker: Twins
Delwath: ... yeah.
Delwath: No, I'm gonna cast Conjure Animals, actually.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Okay, so grab some-
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... tokens or dice or something to mark out the guys.
Delwath: Um, would I need to use...
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Oh, yeah. [coughs] You can, you can dig through this, or you can just use dice.
DM: [paper rustles]
Delwath: Okay. So-
Seeker: These are too big
Unknown: ... um-
DM: There's a ton of them in here, but nobody looked at them, I think, so.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Um.
DM: And there's, [paper rustles] there's bases in here.
DM: [thud]
Unknown: So-
DM: I would use dice
Delwath: ... before the...
Delwath: That'll do. Before the battle starts, Delwath waves his hand and a whole pack of, like, shadowy lynxes just appear.
Delwath: Uh, what is the radius?
Unknown: [paper rustles]
DM: How do you get to do stuff before the battle starts?
Unknown: I thought we rolled initiative. [laughs]
Delwath: You can cast a spell too if you want.
DM: You just can't cast a spell targeting them, but if you cast a spell targeting yourself.
Delwath: This is a concentration spell.
DM: This is-
Unknown: Area of effect
DM: ... you, you hear them, you hear them coming up the stairs, so you have, like-
Unknown: Okay, okay
DM: ... a minute or... Like, not a minute-
Unknown: I get to go
DM: ... but you have...
Seeker: Oh, I could do... No, I can't do...
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: The like-
Seeker: I can't do the construct thing.
DM: Yeah, so they're coming up.
Delwath: Uh, this is only a single square.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: The ladder-
Unknown: Okay
Wellby: ... the ladder
Wellby: is also-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Wellby: ... over the stairwell, right?
Unknown: Can you see them from there?
Seeker: From down the stairs?
Delwath: But it affects-
Wellby: But they're coming up this way.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: And I'm kind of crouching behind the forge for fresh cover.
Unknown: So hold on. It's like within 10.
Wellby: And so as soon as I have a line of sight, like, as soon as their head comes above the floor.
Unknown: I think it's-
Seeker: Oh, okay.
DM: That's, that's where initiative starts is when their heads get a, c- come into-
Unknown: But-
Seeker: And can the ladder-
Delwath: ... they're actually gonna come into the Conjure Animals before that
Seeker: ... I was very definitely touching the manacles earlier, so.
Delwath: Where it says Conjure Animals under conjure f- it's a 60-foot range.
Delwath: I'm gonna conjure a pack of animals, so Delwath is gonna-
DM: But you have to see it, right?
Unknown: Yeah, just-
DM: The stairs turn like that
Delwath: ... but I'm just, as far as I can see, just wherever the edge of what I can see, but they come within 10 feet of it, it takes effect.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So it's probably... It's a little hard to...
Unknown: What are these?
Wellby: This way?
Delwath: That's Kenzo and the, the ladder.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: And then what are these? Are these used?
DM: Those are them.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh-
Wellby: Very
DM: But can you, you can move Conjure Animals?
Delwath: I, uh, Conjure Animals anytime...
Delwath: Let's see. Uh, whenever the pack
Delwath: decks, um, you can move the p- um, whenever I...
Delwath: Yes, on my turn.
Unknown: Okay And what does, what does it do?
DM: So they run into it.
Delwath: Uh, dex save or a 5d10 slash damage.
DM: They both make their saves.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: uh, you know-
DM: Do, do they take damage on a fail?
Delwath: On a failed save it...
Delwath: Ah, wait, hold on.
Delwath: On a failed sa- no
DM: It... As they, as they run through it, like, it seems almost as if the lynxes cannot get any
DM: purchase on them
DM: as they charge up.
Delwath: Okay. So it's, like, there.
Unknown: So-
DM: Yep
Delwath: ... yeah, 5, 10. So even if they're standing there, that's still within 10 feet.
DM: Yep, and they run up, and initiative starts with Wellby.
Wellby: Uh, I take steady aim.
Wellby: Well, uh, do they run into the ladder first, or...?
DM: Uh, the ladder's, like, blocking.
DM: I can't quite visualize what the ladder's supposed to mean.
Wellby: The ladder's... I think the intent was the ladder is sort of horizontal across the open area-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... of the stairwell, kinda-
Delwath: So the stairwell's going like that.
DM: Ah, okay.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: So they would run into ladder, but you have initiative-
Wellby: Ah
DM: ... so what do you want to do? Like-
Wellby: I want to take steady aim and shoot the first one.
DM: [dice rolling] You can see right through the ladder.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: There's a 19.
DM: Oh, good.
Wellby: So it's a, it's a lot.
DM: That hits.
Wellby: Whatever it is. Um,
Wellby: I'm gonna use three dice to do a,
Wellby: uh,
Wellby: a, a Obscure Sneak Attack, so I'm gonna try and shoot them in their eyes.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: And the-
DM: Oh. [dice rolling] Oh. Oh, dear.
Wellby: This hits.
Wellby: Uh-
DM: What is that, a save?
Wellby: That is a DC 18 dex.
Wellby: 10, 18.
DM: Uh, you're shooting the one in the front?
Wellby: Yep.
Seeker: He did try to shoot us first, so...
DM: Uh, you hit it straight in the eye.
Wellby: Holy fuck.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: What does that do?
Wellby: Um, sorry, 29 damage, before I forget.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Um, so it gives them the blinded condition until the end of its next turn.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Awesome.
Unknown: That's-
DM: All right
Kenzo: ... that's, that's for the one in the front?
DM: The one in the front, the, Wellby's arrow, like, strikes right in his face, and it, like, squints as it's running forward.
DM: It still knows where you all are, but it has disadvantage on its attacks.
Wellby: And we all have advantage against it.
DM: And you have advantage against it,
DM: as-
Unknown: Kenzo is up
DM: ... Kenzo is up.
Wellby: Uh-
Kenzo: Kenzo is up. Man, you know, so I, I could do, um, Lengau's Claw, but that's also an additional d6 of force damage, which would be divided by two?
DM: The-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... force damage would be reduced, yes.
Kenzo: But I can still do the 15-foot range on the punches?
DM: Yep, you can still do the 15-foot range.
Delwath: But can't you just... I mean, you're set up to be-
Wellby: Uh, yeah, I'm, I'm already-
DM: You could just punch it in the head.
Kenzo: Yeah, this is, uh, uh, this, this is, this is less useful in this environment.
Kenzo: All right, I'm just gonna go ahead and, um,
Kenzo: um, and, uh,
Unknown: fuck it up.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: So I'm gonna do
Kenzo: two staff attacks, but I have advantage now?
DM: You got advantage, yep.
Kenzo: On all my attacks?
DM: All your attacks.
Unknown: Wow, crazy.
Kenzo: All right, so hold on. I need to see how much damage I can do here.
Unknown: [clears throat] Okay.
Kenzo: So wait, what the heck?
Kenzo: Why is my, why is my staff attack only, um, a d10?
Kenzo: Shouldn't there be a, shouldn't it be plus something?
DM: That's weird.
Kenzo: 'Cause my unarmed strikes are at a, my unarmed strikes-
DM: Oh
Kenzo: ... are 10 plus 5.
DM: You know what? It's because...
DM: Yeah, yeah, ignore that. Just use your unarmed strikes.
DM: It's exactly the same as your unarmed strikes.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's an extra plus. It's plus 6.
Kenzo: Plus 6 for, to the staff? For the staff?
DM: To the damage, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You don't need that.
Unknown: All right.
DM: It's, it's because it's a magic weapon, and then it, I need to update it so it works with the new model.
Kenzo: Right, these are the details, right?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Okay. All right, first staff attack,
Unknown: uh, very big.
DM: No d10. That's definitely gonna hit.
Kenzo: What's, uh, what's my plus on my attacks?
DM: Plus, plus 11 with the staff.
DM: Plus 10 otherwise.
Kenzo: Fuck. Wow, 30. All right, so that hits.
DM: Yeah, that hits.
Kenzo: And this does, uh, 2 plus 6.
DM: That hits.
Unknown: Right?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: 2 plus 6, that's 8 for the, 8 damage for the first attack.
Kenzo: Second attack, uh, oh,
Unknown: 18?
DM: 18 hits.
Unknown: Oh, wait. 19. 19, 19.
DM: 19 hits.
Unknown: 19.
DM: Oh, nice.
Kenzo: And then, uh, 14 damage.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: And then three, um,
Kenzo: uh, unarmed strikes,
Unknown: um-
Unknown: So it's gonna keep her fairly low as-
Unknown: Yep
DM: ... Kenzo goes.
Unknown: Yep.
Kenzo: And, um, this one, yeah, 23 hits.
DM: That hits.
Kenzo: And this one's plus 5, so another 13 damage.
Kenzo: Um, fourth attack,
Kenzo: uh, hit very badly, strongly.
Unknown: And then,
Unknown: oh, 9.
DM: Wow, that hits.
Kenzo: Uh, that's another 14 damage.
DM: Sorry, 8, 14, four- what was the third one?
Unknown: 13.
DM: 13.
DM: And then 14.
Kenzo: 14, and then my last attack
Kenzo: is als- oh, natural 20.
DM: Crit.
Unknown: Crit.
DM: Nice.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: So roll it twice.
Unknown: Roll it twice?
DM: 2d10.
Kenzo: 8 plus
Unknown: 18-
DM: Half plus-
Kenzo: 18 plus 6
DM: ... plus 6.
Unknown: Oh, plus, it's only plus 5.
DM: Plus 5 for the...
Delwath: So 23.
Wellby: 23.
Unknown: Dude, Kenzo does-
DM: Nice
DM: ... does nearly 100 points of damage-
Wellby: Wow
Delwath: ... in one round.
Wellby: Wow.
DM: As fists are... Like, there's, like, there's, like, shards of stone flying off of its head as it staggers.
DM: Um-
Wellby: This is the blind one?
Unknown: This is the blind one.
DM: This is the blind one, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: but now-
Unknown: Is it, like, wounded?
DM: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's not quite bloody, but it's definitely hurt.
DM: Um-
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: The blind one is staggering around and is first gonna try and just punch the ladder out of the way.
DM: So that's a
Unknown: 16. What's the ladder's AC?
Unknown: Is this, uh-
Wellby: I thought that might be Kenzo.
Unknown: Hey, that's great. Thank you.
Seeker: The ladder's AC is 16.
DM: So it hits.
DM: Um, the ladder takes 21 points of bludgeoning damage, and it has to make...
DM: Oh, and it just, it goes flying 10 feet away as there's like a mnemonic action on its fist, and it hits and then shoots the la- Oh wait, the ladder's large, right?
Unknown: Sh- yeah.
DM: Oh, nope, sorry, the ladder does not move.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: It's pissed now.
Unknown: Big ladder.
DM: It's gonna punch the ladder again, with disadvantage 'cause it's blind.
DM: That's still a 22.
DM: So the ladder takes another-
Unknown: Wow
DM: ...
DM: uh-
Unknown: I guess,
Unknown: uh, 15
DM: ... 19 points of, of bludgeoning damage, but again is not pushed.
DM: Um, and this one is looking sort of
DM: like the end of its next turn, so it's not blind anymore.
DM: It shakes its eyes, and it, like,
DM: looks around annoyed,
DM: um, as the second one now can't really reach, can't get past it because the ladder's blocking it.
DM: It's gonna fire crystal darts at the ladder.
Seeker: Yeah, ladder.
Delwath: Man, ladder's sucking all the damage.
DM: So, okay, question.
DM: We could play either allies...
DM: So normally speaking, en- if your f- if an enemy is between you and the person that you're attacking, then you get cover from the enemy.
DM: We could just say allies get out of the way, and the ladder doesn't have cover, but it also doesn't mess up Kenzo.
DM: Or we could say, I mean, it doesn't mess up Wellby.
DM: Or we can say allies also block, and the ladder has cover, but-
Delwath: Of course allies block. W- uh, he can shoot through cover.
DM: Oh, he's got sharpshooter, so it doesn't matter.
DM: So of course allies block.
Delwath: We, we get in the way all we can.
DM: Right.
Delwath: And Kenzo just threads his arrow between people's legs.
DM: Uh, so that then would-
Unknown: I mean, not Kenzo, Wellby
DM: ... so that the ladder has, has an 18 AC, so that misses.
Unknown: That's what I'd do.
DM: Then the second crystal dart,
DM: um, that one hits.
Delwath: Who is it, uh, hitting?
DM: The ladder.
Unknown: Oh, the ladder.
Unknown: It's trying to get the la- it, they can't push the ladder.
Unknown: It's too big, yeah.
DM: It's too big. So that's 17 points of force damage on the ladder.
Kenzo: I'm bringing out all the kind of humanoid looking ones.
DM: And that ends their turn. Delwath is up.
Delwath: Now can I reach the one in the front?
Unknown: Oh, that's perfect.
Unknown: That's, wow.
Wellby: That is perfect.
DM: Um.
Delwath: I mean, the intention-
DM: The ladder is in, like, I thought the ladder was just blocking-
Unknown: Oh, shit
DM: ... the passage, right?
Delwath: How did Kenzo attack it?
DM: Kenzo's flying.
Delwath: I mean, okay. Ah.
DM: Right? So the way I envisioned it is Kenzo's flying, like, above.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And they can either attack the ladder or Kenzo, but that's the only space, unless somebody else flies.
Unknown: I mean, it-
DM: Yeah, that's a good-
DM: That's kind of how I thought you set it up with the ladder blocking.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. It just, it means I can't do anything.
Kenzo: You can do things.
DM: Not really.
Seeker: [laughs] The ladder's full of holes.
Seeker: You can shoot through the ladder.
Delwath: I don't have any good ranged attacks, though.
Delwath: I mean, I would have to...
Delwath: The only mechanism I thought we were setting it up so that...
Delwath: I didn't quite envision this correctly.
Unknown: It's, it's a cramped space.
Delwath: It's a cramped... So I was trying to draw double scale so I could see it better.
Delwath: But like, 'cause I'm trying to visual- like, are they down here?
DM: One of them is behind.
Unknown: They're two... They, they don't, they don't, they don't...
DM: Only one fits. They can't get past each other in the stairs.
Unknown: Right, right, right, right, right, right, right.
Unknown: Yep, yep.
DM: So one is at the top of the stairs where the la- so the ladder's over the top of the stairs.
Delwath: Right. So the ladder is, like, filling these two squ- these squares.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Is that... Okay.
DM: So one is, like, in combat with the ladder.
DM: Kenzo is flying.
Delwath: And Kenzo's like here.
DM: Right. Kenzo, no, Kenzo's even further down.
DM: He's there.
Delwath: Kenzo's like there. Okay.
DM: In the air above the-
Delwath: So it's like that.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: It's basically like-
DM: Exactly like that. Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Okay. I mean, that's fine.
Delwath: I don't really need to go, I don't need to be...
Delwath: It's better to let, I mean, when the ladder dies, then I will go fight it.
Seeker: The ladder has taken 67 of its 85.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Well, I wasn't sure I remembered correctly.
Seeker: It got hit by the dart.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Was that 10?
DM: 10 for the last.
Unknown: Really?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Okay. So it's taken 67.
DM: 67 of its 85.
Delwath: I, I, I don't mind the ladder sucking all the blows.
Delwath: I don't have any very effective things to do against it.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: I mean, yeah.
Seeker: The ladder's standing strong for the moment.
Unknown: You can grant me an action.
Unknown: Surprise, there's no ladder.
Delwath: But if I-
DM: Seeker's next
Delwath: ... well, hold on. I'm not skipping my turn.
DM: I know. I'm just reminding people.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: I mean-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... Eldritch Blasts their, they take-
Unknown: I think it, uh, probably does not.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: I could just cantrip them.
Delwath: I mean, it's not, like, the most useful thing in the world, but.
Unknown: Possible black dragon? No, I like that.
Unknown: Yeah, definitely black dragon.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Or it's gonna acid his mouth.
Delwath: That, he bl- he did half the damage of one.
Delwath: We, we think one of them is just about bloodied.
DM: Just about, yeah.
Delwath: Okay. Uh.
Seeker: So they have 200 hit points?
DM: A little more.
Unknown: Jeez.
DM: But, I mean.
Delwath: Okay. Uh, maybe I will bonus action Sanctuary the ladder.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs] What does that do?
Delwath: It means they can't attack it.
Seeker: Nice.
Seeker: They can't attack it?
Delwath: Unless they beat an 18, DC 18 Wisdom save.
Kenzo: So they can only attack the ladder. Well, I guess they can still shoot darts at anybody.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah, you've got cover.
Delwath: Okay. I will do that, and then I will, I will cantrip.
Delwath: I will Sorcerer's Burst.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Acid damage at the blinded one.
Unknown: Kenzo.
Unknown: Oh, word.
Unknown: Have it.
Delwath: Uh, 19.
DM: It-
Unknown: Oh, cruising
DM: ... deflects off of its body
DM: and hits the ladder.
Seeker: What?
Seeker: It can redirect?
Unknown: How does it...
Delwath: I don't even know what that means.
Unknown: It's interesting, yeah.
DM: The Sorcerer's Burst hits it, and its, like, stone hardens for a second, and the spell reflects off of its body and hits the ladder.
Delwath: So they're immune to spells.
Unknown: What?
Delwath: Does the ladder take the damage?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: How much?
Delwath: But the ladder,
Delwath: how does Sanctuary interact with that?
DM: It's you making the attack
Delwath: But if I'm attacking the ladder, I can't attack the ladder.
DM: No, sanctuary still affects you.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: well, it can hit Kenzo then.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Wait, wait, wait. What's hitting me?
Unknown: A spell?
DM: Dwarves sorcerer's burst.
Unknown: Fuck.
Kenzo: Wait, but this is not energy.
Kenzo: What, what, what kind of force is this? Is this-
DM: It's acid.
Kenzo: Oh, I can't, I can't deflect that.
DM: You can.
Unknown: Oh, okay. I'll try to deflect it.
Delwath: Wait, you can deflect a spell cantrip?
DM: You can deflect any-
Unknown: At- attack roll
DM: ... attack roll.
Delwath: Yeah, deflect it.
DM: Okay. So roll damage.
Unknown: What the
Delwath: fuck? But this is annoying, I can't...
Delwath: Spells aren't...
Unknown: Is it all spells?
DM: You also-
Delwath: 18. They've gotta be... They didn't take damage from my slashing attacks either.
Unknown: It's, it's a perfect 0.
Delwath: They have to be, like, immune to spells.
Kenzo: Or not. It's pretty good.
Seeker: Should I try psychic disruption?
Delwath: They're gonna be immune to it.
Unknown: No.
Seeker: What can we do?
Delwath: Punch it. Fight it.
Unknown: Melee.
Delwath: I don't think we can hurt it with spells.
Seeker: But they can't...
Seeker: They're immune to force damage too.
Unknown: Half damage.
Seeker: They're resistant to force damage.
Delwath: I, I rolled eight- 18 for damage.
DM: Okay. Now Kenzo, Kenzo deflects that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But I can... Can I redirect... Oh, I, I can only redirect it if it's more than 25?
DM: Uh, no.
DM: You can, you can spend a ki to redirect it.
DM: You reduce the damage to zero.
Delwath: But don't. Don't redirect it.
DM: But it would redirect to Delwath, so don't redirect it.
Delwath: There's no way you can redirect it.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: These guys are immune to magic.
Kenzo: Yeah. All right. I won't redirect it, but I will...
Kenzo: I'll di- I'll di- I'll deflect it to like wherever the hell.
DM: Yeah, it deflects, splashes harmlessly against the wall.
DM: Kenzo takes no damage. A- as far as I can...
Delwath: I would assume that they are completely immune to magic.
Kenzo: Is this one resistant?
Delwath: So I don't know what you can do.
DM: I don't know what, uh-
Delwath: But you shouldn't try and affect...
DM: A Delwath?
Delwath: That's, that's Delwath, yeah. I would not try and affect them with magic.
Seeker: What about the like banishment kind of stuff?
Delwath: I... Maybe they're not immune to-
Seeker: Oh
Delwath: ... non attack spell magic.
Seeker: Yeah, they're immune to that.
Delwath: But they have not taken any damage from attack magic.
Kenzo: The only dwarfy ones are like not...
Seeker: You know?
Unknown: So-
Kenzo: This is a pr- this is a good one
Delwath: ... I don't, I would not do anything that takes an attack roll or a save.
Seeker: So wait, the damage from Kenzo's attacks-
Delwath: It's just attacks
Unknown: It's immune to perfectly here from me.
Seeker: Even-
Unknown: Are you gonna bitch? Huh?
Seeker: Even though that's bludgeoning damage, and so they take half of whatever his
Unknown: But he's, his magic fails.
Seeker: Oh, I see. So it's spells in particular.
Delwath: No, no, no. I think they, they...
Delwath: Tim sort of hinted when he said it seemed like the
Delwath: claws of the lynxes just bounced off them.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: I mean, you can always polymorph yourself into a giant ape and just go punch them.
Delwath: But you can't. There's not enough space.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Seeker: And I'm concentrating on animal shapes.
Delwath: Oh, and you're concentrating on animal shapes.
Delwath: You could use animal shape to turn into a flying creature and go punch them.
Seeker: Oh, that's right.
DM: Yeah, that's true. There were some pretty decent flying creatures.
Delwath: 'Cause you could fly over their head.
Delwath: Turn into a, turn into a dire, a, a dire, um-
DM: There's even a medium one
Delwath: ... a medium dire creature.
Seeker: What's that [laughs]?
Delwath: Uh, sorry. What was it? Do let me find it.
DM: I'll, I'll send it to you.
Seeker: A dire hawk or something?
Delwath: A dire hawk, yeah. Um-
Seeker: I still never found the right-
Unknown: Yeah, hold on
Seeker: ... beasts collector.
Unknown: Hold on. I'll find it for you. Actually, you'd...
Delwath: It's a magic action, so it'd be your action.
DM: That's, yeah.
Delwath: Still, probably a good move.
Seeker: Oh, to just transform?
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: Just in case [laughs]...
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... they get through.
Unknown: That way. Hold on. I have to say show filtered content.
Seeker: So the ladder didn't take any damage in that last-
Unknown: No
Seeker: ... direct situation.
Kenzo: I can't believe, I can't believe there's no hal- I haven't seen a single halfling.
Wellby: I haven't seen anyone with a bow.
Unknown: Yeah, nobody with a bow.
Seeker: Or any dwarves.
Kenzo: They're dwarves, but they're not quite...
Kenzo: They're like-
Seeker: They're like-
Kenzo: There's a, there's a good, there's a good Roswitha.
Seeker: [laughs] There's a grok.
Kenzo: Yeah, they're really too, too fiery.
Kenzo: Yeah, they're just like-
Seeker: That's very strange
Unknown: ... dire dwarves.
Delwath: You have to say show filtered content and then click filter again.
Seeker: Ah. You guys are doing the important work over there.
Delwath: Yeah. Oh, but it's still not showing up.
Delwath: Oh, 'cause I changed the...
Delwath: Their... D&D Beyond is not a very good website.
DM: Yeah. Here you go. I'm, Eric, I'm sending this to the group chat, and you can look at the stat block.
DM: It's perfect. It's got multi-attack, flyby, so you don't provoke of opportunity attacks.
Delwath: Yeah, totally. Dire... Yeah.
Delwath: Perfect. Uh, 68 hit points, so that's actually a lot.
Seeker: Nice.
Delwath: Yeah. Turn into a dire medium bird of prey.
Unknown: How is it possible that the giant-
Kenzo: I guess, yeah, that's kind of...
Kenzo: It's kind of reasonable.
Seeker: So that's my action.
DM: So the Seeker turns into this small, vicious bird as his action.
DM: That ends Seeker's turn. Wellby, you're up.
Seeker: Oh, and, um,
Seeker: I, I get to command the ladder to continue doing the good work that it is doing.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: [laughs] They both went?
DM: And if... Yeah.
Kenzo: Both of the things have gone?
DM: Yeah, they both went.
Wellby: I'm gonna do the-
DM: And if you want to give them an inspiration, you should-
Seeker: Oh, oh. No, no. It's, it should grapple them, not hit them, basically
DM: ... you should inspire somebody before you shift.
Seeker: Oh, uh, inspiration to...
Seeker: Who's closest to everything?
Seeker: Wellby or Kenzo?
Delwath: No, Wellby's not close.
Seeker: Kenzo. Inspiration.
Delwath: Give Kenzo inspiration-
Seeker: Um
Delwath: ... 'cause Kenzo's about to get the brunt-
Seeker: Wait, the, the, the ladder gets an attack now, right?
DM: Yeah, and the ladder gets an attack now. So-
Delwath: Ah, but if the ladder attacks, it loses sanctuary.
Seeker: And what does sanctuary do to it?
Delwath: It means they can't attack it.
Kenzo: Wait, why would we want to do that? So now it's only, they can only attack me?
DM: But we-
Kenzo: Why wouldn't you give sanctuary to me and instead of the ladder?
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: That might have been smarter [laughs].
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: So now they can only attack me.
DM: We can, we can do that instead.
DM: I didn't even think of that.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
DM: Why would you do that?
Unknown: Can we, can we do that instead?
DM: Yes, sure. Then the ladder takes the damage, takes the 18 points of damage though.
Delwath: That would kill it, right? You'd have to-
DM: No, no, not quite.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But yes.
Seeker: Uh, oh, wait.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Otherwise, Kenzo's gonna be more worried about El.
Delwath: I didn't even, I didn't even... Sorry, I didn't even think of that.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I forgot you were down there.
Unknown: Eh,
Delwath: it's fine.
Delwath: But it's actually useless to give you sanctuary.
Seeker: Use map.
DM: That does bring it to a precise-
Unknown: There's no point
DM: ... he's about to attack.
Delwath: 'Cause you're gonna attack.
Delwath: Oh, I lose, I lose that.
Delwath: You lose it when you attack.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: There's no point. Leave it on the ladder.
Kenzo: All right. Leave it on the ladder. It's fine. Yeah.
Seeker: Okay.
Kenzo: Keep, keep the hit points for the ladder.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Okay. That would've killed the ladder.
Delwath: Yeah. But-
Unknown: Yeah. Good
Delwath: ... 'cause there's no point in giving Kenzo sanctuary, 'cause you just lose it.
Unknown: That's fine.
Delwath: As soon as you attack, you lose it.
Wellby: Got it. Tim, you made the first one's attacks with disadvantage?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Cool.
Delwath: But the theory is the ladder's better off not doing anything and just blocking the space.
Seeker: Just being in the way. Okay.
Delwath: And being in the way than-
Seeker: That's... It was doing that well before, so.
DM: But it's not blinded anymore 'cause it's the, at the end of its turn, right?
Wellby: Yep. But I'm gonna do exactly-
DM: Same thing
Wellby: ... the same thing we did last time and use another 3d6 to blind it again.
Wellby: That's 20-
DM: That, yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... 28 or something.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: This plus 11, so there's 10, 15, 26 plus a DC 18 dex save.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, it is now bloodied.
Kenzo: Which one? The other one.
DM: So whatever, the first one.
Wellby: This one.
DM: Uh, and it fails its save.
DM: [die rolling]
Wellby: Awesome. Blinded again.
DM: So it's still blinded, as Kenzo says.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: You take the I again.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Hits the I again.
Wellby: The other eye.
Delwath: It's like, I just got the arrow out.
Unknown: [imitates arrow firing]
DM: [laughs] Uh, and that's Kenzo's turn, so you still have advantage against the blinded one.
Kenzo: Dude, this is like... It's crazy.
Kenzo: Like, I can't... Nothing can damage me unless they do more than 20 points of damage.
Unknown: You only get one reaction a turn.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: So they have, if they have multi-attacks.
Unknown: But still, that's like... Yeah, fuck, man.
Kenzo: All right. Well, all right, I'm gonna...
Kenzo: I'll, I'll try to kill the thing that...
Delwath: Yeah. You get advantage.
Unknown: [sighs] All right, let's fucking go.
DM: Take, take it down, Kenzo.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, 17?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: 17 hits.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
Unknown: Man, the AC's not that good.
Unknown: Where's the d10?
Delwath: Right next to you. Here, you know, as just a-
DM: Tim, roll your damage at the same time
Delwath: ... roll all them together.
Kenzo: Ah, nice, nice, nice. Smart.
Kenzo: Okay. Uh, s- seven.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Seven, and now this is the second staff attack.
Kenzo: [die rolling] Hits, uh, plus six, 13.
Unknown: Got it?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: But does he do three attacks?
Kenzo: Yep, yep. And now, uh, first, uh, blow [die rolling] hits.
Kenzo: That does 13.
Kenzo: Second [die rolling] hits.
Kenzo: Does another 13.
Kenzo: And then the third one [die rolling] hits and does 15.
Wellby: Do you have more attacks than these two?
Delwath: No, he's, uh, he had five to start.
DM: Yeah, that's all.
Delwath: I mean, you have to spend a ki for each time he does it.
Wellby: Yeah. So much damage.
DM: Now the, the blinded one is gonna turn and punch up at Kenzo.
Unknown: Wait, uh, I didn't kill it?
DM: You didn't kill it. It's-
Unknown: The fuck?
DM: ... it's close to dead.
Kenzo: All right. Well, let me make a hit.
Unknown: [die rolling]
DM: Uh, that's gonna be a 23 with disadvantage.
Kenzo: Ah, so it hits. Okay.
DM: Yeah. And you take...
Kenzo: Come on, hit me. Hit me.
Unknown: [die rolling]
DM: Uh,
DM: 20 points of bludgeoning damage.
Kenzo: Which I don't take 'cause I deflect the attack.
Unknown: [die rolling] Um-
DM: Kenzo like, whoosh-
Kenzo: And now, now I will r-
DM: Screams in pain
Kenzo: ... I will, um-
DM: Yep. So it's a dex save
Kenzo: ... uh, redirect attack.
Kenzo: Yep, dexter- dexterity or to, uh, yeah, dexterity s- saving throw.
Unknown: [die rolling]
DM: Um, what's the DC?
Kenzo: Uh, it doesn't say. It just says the creature moves-
DM: Oh, it's whatever your... It's 16, I think.
DM: So that, it succeeds.
Kenzo: Wait, wait, why is it 16?
DM: 'Cause that's your normal-
Delwath: That should be DC
DM: ... bonus DC.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: It should be your proficiency plus your-
DM: Plus wisdom
Delwath: ... wisdom. You have plus three wisdom?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: No.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: If he has plus three wisdom, it would be, oh, eight plus.
DM: Eight plus five plus three is 16.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. 16. Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: All right. So I don't-
DM: So it manages to dodge out of the way, but you take no damage.
DM: It, however, is gonna punch you again.
DM: [die rolling] Uh, that's a
DM: 20.
Unknown: That hits.
DM: This you can't deflect. [die rolling] And that's gonna be 11, 16, 23 points of damage, and you are punched 10 feet away.
Wellby: Ooh.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: So let's move Kenzo into the room.
Delwath: Well, can he... He goes flying past the ladder.
DM: He goes-
Delwath: He's, like, in the... He's flying.
DM: He's in the air, yeah. And you have to make a con save-
Kenzo: Hold on. Hold on
DM: ... for the flying
Kenzo: ... I still need to do 115 minus 23?
DM: 23.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Just type, uh-
DM: 23 and hit damage
Delwath: ... 23 and hit damage.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: And then make a con save.
Unknown: I didn't know you could do that. Oh, nice.
Kenzo: Okay. And now I make a con save, which is-
DM: Plus six.
Unknown: Plus six.
DM: And if you fail, you fall because the l- the whistle gets knocked out of your mouth.
Kenzo: Wait, but what do you mean, when, uh...
Kenzo: I'm, I'm doing what, plus six?
DM: 1d20 plus six.
Kenzo: 14.
DM: Uh, you succeed.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Plus you have inspiration hanging around if you want.
Kenzo: I do have inspiration.
DM: So you get knocked up against...
DM: You're knocked 10 feet, like, basically into the air 'cause it's just straight away from how it's punching.
Delwath: So you're, like, diagonally up.
DM: You're, like, up against the ceiling, basically.
Unknown: All right. That's fine.
DM: Um-
Unknown: But you can fly back if you need to.
DM: And,
DM: uh, the other one,
DM: stuck shooting darts.
DM: Um-
Delwath: It's not gonna... Oh, no, it can't.
Delwath: Right, it can't get past the ladder.
DM: And really, the only thing it's gonna do
DM: is shoot at Kenzo.
DM: [die rolling]
Unknown: Oh, that means I get plus.
DM: Oh, this one doesn't have disadvantage.
DM: This'll just be both of its, both of its attacks hit.
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: Uh, you take another 20 points of force damage.
Unknown: Geez.
DM: Boom, boom as the two darts hit you.
Delwath: Does, does that with disadvantage?
DM: This one is not blinded.
Delwath: Or no, cover?
DM: Yeah, but that was a 20 from one of the-
Delwath: Enough to hit, right
DM: ... 30s.
Delwath: Half cover gives you only plus two, right?
DM: Plus two.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, so I can o- I can only deflect attack once per turn.
Unknown: Once, yeah.
DM: Otherwise, you would be totally invincible.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Which-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... I mean, so. [laughs] So 28 more damage?
DM: 28 more damage.
Delwath: But you remember to add the 20 hit points originally.
Unknown: I had that, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But I also had 13 damage from the other guy.
DM: And that ends the golem's turn. Down a lot.
Kenzo: Damn. I don't f- I lost half my hit points.
Unknown: That's, uh-
Delwath: Um, can I-
Kenzo: ... that was very painful
Delwath: ... can I move into where Kenzo was now?
Delwath: Is there space-
DM: Uh, if you wanna jump-
Unknown: ... in front of the ladder?
DM: ... down in between the two of them, you can.
Delwath: Okay, that sounds a little rough.
Seeker: In between the two.
DM: They're, like, spaced. There's probably, like, five feet-
Unknown: No, but-
DM: ... in between where the two golems are, where Kenzo was up.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: You could run. You could jump down the stairs 'cause the space is clear by Kenzo having moved.
Seeker: That's what Seeker would do.
DM: But you would be-
Wellby: Totally
DM: ... you would be...
Wellby: Totally could and then finish off the guy who's almost dead.
DM: There is one who's almost dead.
Wellby: And be in... You'll only be in melee with one.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, fine. Okay.
Unknown: What the hell?
Unknown: Be-
Delwath: I haven't taken any damage yet
Wellby: ... so, so it's the character who never gets in melee combat.
Seeker: Be, be brave like the rest of us.
Delwath: Okay, that's a mood.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Um, like the rest of us, he
Seeker: said. [laughs]
Seeker: I touched those manacles.
DM: You did
Delwath: ... and-
DM: That was almost very bravery
Unknown: ... it's over.
Unknown: Yeah, but you're like... But there's something like [laughs]
Delwath: What are the chances?
Delwath: Well, well
DM: This is with a [laughs]
Delwath: Might last slightly.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: okay. So wait, I don't have advantage on this guy, right?
Seeker: That's really, that's really not courage.
Unknown: You... Nope, you have advantage on like, on the blind one.
Unknown: I do. Oh, no wait, it's turn ended.
Seeker: It's not bravery [laughs].
Delwath: It's like, so you don't have to... Okay. But I'm gonna attack the blinded one.
Seeker: Mixed with like-
Delwath: So first attack
Unknown: ... still involved in curiosity or [laughs]
Unknown: Hits. Um.
Seeker: Definitely bravery.
Delwath: Oh, but I don't have any...
Delwath: I do two D8.
Kenzo: Well, there's like these different meters, like your curiosity meter like supersedes like all the other things.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So like...
Delwath: So that's 10, 15 damage.
Delwath: Second attack would only hit a 14.
DM: That misses.
Unknown: That's unfortunate.
Delwath: Third attack hits.
Delwath: I assume a-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... 18, 19 hit. 18.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, I guess I have o- one left than I thought 'cause, 'cause we took away my plus one.
DM: You, you know a 17 hits.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. Uh, do I wanna...
Delwath: How bad, how damaged is this guy?
DM: Pretty damaged. I mean, not like-
Seeker: We haven't touched the other one at all
DM: ... clinging to life, but it's definitely well past like-
Delwath: There's no reason that to think that divine smite would not work against this, right?
DM: No, no reason to think.
DM: So far it seems like it just succeeds saving throws automatically and-
Unknown: Deflects
DM: ... deflects attacks automatically.
Unknown: Right. Okay.
Unknown: Um-
DM: It's not immune to magic damage.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: But I'm not... Oh no, I am concentrating on something.
Delwath: Uh, uh, but that's 5 to 10.
DM: When you concentrate... Oh, a- the concentration-
Unknown: Concentration
DM: ... would do literally nothing
Delwath: ... would do nothing.
DM: So why would you keep going?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: The fire doors might be good. The fire doors might be good too.
Delwath: Okay. I'm gonna, I'm gonna smite this guy.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Drag him, drag him.
DM: Well, you could always elder smite if you don't want to give up concentration.
Delwath: I know, but what's the point? Plus this could banish him, which would be nice.
Delwath: If I don't quite kill him, he has to make a charisma save.
Delwath: Okay. Seven fift- uh, seven plus five, thir- 12 damage.
Delwath: I assume the 12 doesn't kill him.
DM: The 12 does not kill him.
Unknown: One.
Kenzo: Out of this whole thing, there's only like two doors.
Delwath: Okay. What about 10,
Delwath: 19?
Wellby: But we have-
DM: Another 19 total?
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: Move around.
DM: Um, that does not kill him.
Unknown: Can people have 50?
Seeker: Does he have to make a save?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Taster.
Delwath: Does he automatically succeed saves against all magic?
Wellby: Taster was like the-
DM: Yes
Unknown: ... the spiritual forebearer of the ladder.
DM: He is very-
Unknown: Okay, then
DM: ...
DM: dead. But not-
Unknown: He's still not dead yet?
DM: Not quite.
Seeker: How much damage did you do?
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: 15, 40, something like that.
Seeker: What the fuck?
Delwath: I rolled kind of crap on...
Delwath: Maybe I should use heroic inspiration to re-roll one of the dice.
Unknown: It's probably-
DM: You should really use heroic inspiration to re-roll the missed attack.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: That would've been the time to use it.
Delwath: Can I use that?
DM: Yes.
Delwath: Can I do that?
Seeker: Nice.
Delwath: I still missed.
Seeker: Yes. Oh.
Delwath: Can I have bardic inspiration?
DM: No.
Unknown: Oh, no.
DM: He's a bird.
Delwath: Oh wait, does... Oh, no, 14 still misses, right?
DM: 14 misses.
Seeker: I am, I am
Delwath: I have no way of boosting-
Seeker: And Kenzo-
Unknown: But Seeker's gonna kill it in bird form
Seeker: ... has four good attacks here.
Delwath: I have no way of boosting, uh, my to hit at all, do I?
Unknown: No.
Seeker: Heavy beak.
Kenzo: Taking 64 damage is not a lot.
DM: Okay, Seeker. Bird Seeker.
Unknown: Um-
DM: There's one that's barely clinging to life.
Seeker: Finish it off
DM: ... one that's untouched.
Seeker: Finish it off. I, I will go to the one barely clinging to life and use my dire bird of prey multi attack to attack with heavy beak.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Plus five to hit.
Seeker: Oh man.
Seeker: So I just, what am I-
DM: Just roll a D20 and add five
Seeker: ... yep. [dice rolling] That's a-
DM: Misses
Seeker: ... 5, 10.
DM: That misses.
Seeker: And then I'm gonna tr- so I slash out with the beak and miss.
Seeker: I'll try again with the beak.
Seeker: [dice rolling] 13.
Seeker: That's an 18.
DM: 18.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: That hits.
Seeker: So the beak punches into the body of this thing.
Seeker: Uh, it's 1D8 plus three slashing damage.
Delwath: I mean, that might not kill it, but let's see.
DM: That might not kill it.
Wellby: Possible Seeker.
Seeker: [dice rolling] That's fi- eight.
DM: Eight.
Seeker: Uh, yeah.
DM: Eight damage.
Seeker: Or sorry, 1D8 plus three piercing damage.
DM: Eight damage does not kill it.
Seeker: Ah.
Wellby: God.
Kenzo: Fucking boring, man.
Seeker: So I'm now-
Delwath: But you can fly away.
Seeker: Oh, nice.
DM: You can fly by, you can fly away without suffering a-
Seeker: I fly back to where I was [laughs].
DM: Yes. Uh, but the ladder still gets to attack.
Seeker: And the ladder-
Kenzo: Of course. Of course, the ladder, ladder can heroically finish this thing off.
DM: Yeah. I mean, it, it-
Seeker: But it just has the like force attack.
Delwath: So what? It still takes damage.
Seeker: Ha ha.
DM: But it still does damage.
Seeker: All right. Let me, I gotta always look up the character sheet for that thing.
Seeker: How I do that? Uh,
DM: not that one, not that one.
DM: It's actually pretty good. It's like 1D10 plus 5.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: And then what do I roll against?
Seeker: Oh, that's myself.
DM: It's a plus 10 to hit.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Plus 10?
DM: Yeah, 1D10 plus 5. It's decent chance of doing some damage.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: [dice rolling] So that's a five.
Delwath: 15.
DM: 15 misses.
Unknown: That misses.
Seeker: The ladder misses.
DM: The ladder struggles and does not succeed, but Wellby.
Unknown: Ah.
Seeker: Having... Just hit it in the head.
DM: I mean, Kenzo can easily finish it off.
Unknown: Yeah. You should, you should go-
Wellby: I should-
Unknown: ... you should go for that one.
Wellby: I'm gonna do the other one.
DM: The other one's g-
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Well, you don't care about cover 'cause you have-
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Go blind, blind the other one.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Nice.
Wellby: All right. [dice rolling] Number two.
Wellby: That's a hit.
DM: Yep.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: that is 12, 15, 18, 29 points of damage and DC18 dex save.
DM: [dice rolling] Nope.
DM: Also blinded. Wellby's getting really good at aiming for the eyes.
Wellby: True three.
DM: Man And Kenzo
Kenzo: Fucking finally, you motherfucker.
Kenzo: So now I get... Oh, I don't get advantage on, uh, the-
DM: If you want to try and finish off the wounded one-
Delwath: No, I finish... I want to finish off the wounded one
Wellby: No, no. You still do have advantage because it's blinded because its turn-
DM: No, no, it's after you. It's in between you and-
Delwath: But it's until the end of its turn.
Wellby: It's blinded until the end of its turn.
Delwath: It hasn't gone yet.
Delwath: It attacks after me. Oh, wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
DM: No, no, no.
Wellby: Oh, never mind. You do have it right.
DM: The wounded one, the wounded one is not blinded.
DM: The-
Wellby: Got it
DM: ... unwounded one is blinded 'til the end of its turn.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: Right. Got it.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: So the wound, the wounded one which I'm attacking, I have to use my regular attack on?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: No advantage.
Unknown: But I still have advantage.
Delwath: Because of where we are in the initiative order, I never get advantage on the blinded ones 'cause they're always-
Unknown: Right.
DM: But it does have disadvantage on its attacks against you.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah. All right.
Seeker: Well, I hit it.
Wellby: That hits.
Seeker: Nice.
Kenzo: And I kill this motherfucker.
Kenzo: Uh, 12 damage.
DM: That kills it.
Kenzo: Fucking finally. All right.
DM: And boom.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It crumbles to dust.
Seeker: One less to stress.
Wellby: Takes it down.
Kenzo: All right, and you die. All right.
DM: Now you can attack the advantaged one.
Kenzo: All right, cool. So now-
DM: So, well, to attack this...
DM: So this one's down the stairs, so you're...
DM: You... Delwath is here, then there's it.
DM: You can't be above Delwath really, but you could conceivably
Kenzo: Just drop down in front of it?
DM: Drop... Well, that's where-
Kenzo: Or behind it?
DM: That's where, that's where...
DM: It's like this.
Unknown: And the ladder is still up between
DM: You could fly over everybody and you could drop down behind it.
Unknown: Well, you've got the ladder.
Unknown: Okay. Let's do that.
Delwath: Here. It's much easier to see.
DM: This is double size.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Right? But Delwath is here, it's here, right?
Unknown: And I'm like right there.
Delwath: You fly all the way down and drop down there.
Unknown: All right. Perfect.
DM: And land on the stairs beneath.
Kenzo: Second, second staff attack.
Kenzo: Uh, I hit...
DM: That hits. Yeah
Kenzo: Oh, sorry. Sorry. Should roll damage here.
Kenzo: Um, 14?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: All right. And now, um, three...
Kenzo: First, first unarmed strike, flurry of blows.
Kenzo: That hits 12.
DM: 12 damage?
Unknown: Yep.
Kenzo: Second set of blows, that also hits.
Kenzo: That does another, uh, 12.
Kenzo: Oh, no, that does, uh, 13.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: And then my final attack,
Kenzo: um, oh, oh, that also hits.
Kenzo: And that, it does another eight.
DM: Okay. Kenzo lands behind it and begins pummeling this blinded creature with its fists.
Delwath: Damage. Yeah.
DM: It, it looks around, it's not really sure who to attack, so it just reaches out with its fist and it punches one of each of you with disadvantage on both attacks.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Huh.
DM: Um, that's a
DM: 21 on Delwath.
Unknown: Shield.
DM: Bounces off a wall of magical force.
DM: That's a...
Seeker: Shield handles ties, doesn't it?
Delwath: Uh, shield gives you plus five to AC.
DM: That's, that is-
Delwath: But it can cast as a reaction.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: No, um, 19 on-
Unknown: 19 hits
DM: ... Kenzo.
Unknown: 19 hits. Oof.
Unknown: Well, but no.
DM: Right. But he has a reaction.
Delwath: I get my reaction back. Ah, right. Ah.
DM: Uh, so that's gonna be, ooh, 19, 24, 29 points of damage.
Kenzo: That's fine. So I can deflect, uh, D10 plus 20.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: So I roll D10-
DM: Roll your D10.
Unknown: What?
Kenzo: And then I can add an inspiration to this?
DM: You can-
Seeker: Which is now a D12.
DM: You can, uh...
Unknown: Ah.
DM: No, you can only add inspiration to D10.
Delwath: No, no. They're only D10 inspiration to D20 checks.
Unknown: You can't add it to damage. That would lose.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: So I just-
DM: Wait, if you get- If you roll a nine or a 10, you reduce it to zero
Delwath: But if you get less than that it doesn't affect...
Delwath: You don't get anything, right?
DM: No, no, you reduce it by the amount you roll.
Unknown: Ah. Oh.
DM: You just can't deflect the attack-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... unless you reduce it to zero.
Kenzo: Hold on. I feel like there's... I have so many random, like, plus five, just do the like...
Kenzo: You know, is there something I can do here to bump up my-
DM: There's nothing you can do to bump that up.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Just roll.
Unknown: All right.
DM: You're not gonna take very much damage, you just might not be able to reflect it.
Unknown: Nine or 10. Nine or 10. Nine or 10.
Wellby: Nine or 10. 10.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah, 30.
DM: You knock it down to zero and you reflect.
Kenzo: Holy shit.
Seeker: Nice.
DM: Uh, that fails its dex save.
Kenzo: Wow, so I just did 30 points of damage to it.
Unknown: No wait, does it half?
DM: No, you roll two D- two D10.
Unknown: Do we have that extension cord somewhere?
Wellby: Uh, it was-
Unknown: Oh, I guess this one will reach.
DM: You roll two D10 damage.
Unknown: My laptop's just over there.
Seeker: Hold on. Let's pull it up.
Delwath: Eric, can I switch with you actually? Is that annoying?
Unknown: No, that's fine.
Wellby: So the other one won't reach.
DM: Yes. If you deflect it, it's, like, two rolls of your martial arts.
Unknown: Two D10 plus five.
DM: Two D10 plus five, yeah.
Unknown: Okay. All right.
Wellby: Here's a possible Seeker right there.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Awesome.
Wellby: So close.
Seeker: Looks good.
Seeker: I'll just leave that right there.
Unknown: There's a D10 up top.
Seeker: Oh, there we go.
Kenzo: All right, two D10 plus five.
Kenzo: Uh, 13 plus five, 18.
DM: So it, this pneumatic fist flies out and hits you, and you just grab it and twist and, like, rip on its arm as it's trying to hurt you.
DM: Um, and it's now getting pretty close to bloody.
Kenzo: Kenzo is so nasty. Fuck.
Seeker: It's funny 'cause really I need a giant bird.
Delwath: Okay. Delwath.
DM: And that brings up Delwath.
Unknown: Which...
DM: Uh, yeah, yeah, that brings up Delwath 'cause it's his turn.
Seeker: Were there any birds in the mixed thing?
Delwath: 'Cause the other one's dead.
DM: The other one's dead, yeah.
Wellby: Um, yeah.
Delwath: Okay. I'll just attack it.
DM: It's temporary, so...
Delwath: Attack one hits.
DM: You gotta take your own advice, Mike.
Unknown: Oh yeah, that's true.
Unknown: Where was the drizzle?
Delwath: Oh, there's the drizzle.
Delwath: Six plus six is 12.
Unknown: Usually.
Delwath: Attack two hits.
Delwath: [laughs] I gotta take my own advice.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: Except for very large cases of six.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Uh, eight plus six is, um, 14.
Kenzo: Not here, but here in spirit.
Delwath: Uh, attack three miss.
Delwath: I'm rolling terrible.
Delwath: Attack three misses.
DM: Okay. Two of Delwath's sword strikes clang against its, its stone, and the third just scrapes harmlessly as
DM: Seeker, uh, in his bird form-
Unknown: Still more of them pretty good ones
Seeker: I'm just gonna attack again.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Yeah, there's a few more
DM: The ladder now is not able to get into melee.
Wellby: Sure. Yeah. There's-
Unknown: Oh, shit
DM: ... 'cause Delwath and Kenzo... You can 'cause you're flying, but Delwath and Kenzo are on the ground.
Delwath: Okay. Camera bag attack's now a bonus action.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: That's interesting.
Seeker: So I literally can't.
Unknown: The ladder probably can't really do anything at all.
Seeker: But it can fly.
DM: But it, it's large.
Wellby: So it's like dwarfed you guys.
DM: So it can't get down into the steps where Delwath is.
Seeker: I'll have it move around to be-
DM: But you're only medium, so you can fly down.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. Um, all right.
Seeker: So I do my...
Seeker: Um, oh, I could try...
Seeker: Um, I don't... Hmm.
Kenzo: All this is annoying that you do to the bub, but it's, uh, null.
Seeker: Okay. Heavy beak. [dice rolling] That's a 19.
DM: That hits.
Unknown: Is there a better Seeker here?
Seeker: Um, it's plus five is a 24 to hit.
DM: Yep.
Seeker: And it does 1D8 plus three.
Seeker: I need a D8.
DM: [coughs]
Seeker: D8.
Kenzo: Ooh, this might be a better Seeker.
Seeker: Um, [dice rolling] that's four plus three is seven.
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Seeker: And then I'll do another beak attack.
Seeker: [dice rolling] That's a 19 plus five.
DM: That hits.
Seeker: Again a 23.
Kenzo: Are you, um, punishing it as a bird?
Unknown: [dice rolling]
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Two plus four, five damage.
DM: Five.
Seeker: Not huge damage, but-
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Uh, and then I fly back again, and then I'll have the ladder
Seeker: come up closer to where I am.
DM: Okay.
DM: That, and Seeker's turn. Wellby is up now.
DM: You have a obscured shot, but it doesn't matter because you have sharpshooter.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Um.
DM: You gonna keep trying to blind?
Wellby: Yeah. Same.
DM: It's been very effective.
Wellby: [dice rolling] Uh, I hit.
Wellby: It's, uh, 18.
Wellby: That's a funny roll.
Unknown: Um-
DM: Three sixes and three ones.
Wellby: Yeah. So that's, uh, 32-
DM: 20-
Wellby: All together
DM: Wait, 21.
Wellby: 'Cause I'm 21 plus 11.
DM: How do you have plus 11 to damage?
DM: That's to hit.
Wellby: It says that on there.
Unknown: Oh, do I not have that to damage?
Delwath: Yeah, that would be a lot to have plus to damage.
Wellby: Okay, it's a six to damage.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. 21 plus 6.
DM: Okay. Oh, and-
Unknown: And-
DM: Don't forget about weapon masteries.
DM: So vex gives you advantage on the next attack you make against this target, which hasn't mattered because it's always been blinded.
DM: Or no, it does matter.
Seeker: And... Oh yeah.
DM: 'Cause-
Seeker: No, no, no, no, no, it hasn't.
Seeker: The next advantage who makes?
Seeker: Wellby.
DM: Wellby makes.
Seeker: He always has advantage. He's steady aim.
DM: Oh, you always have advantage. So, so you don't have to steady aim.
Unknown: Oh, that's great. That's great.
DM: You can move around.
Wellby: I misread that as having to be your next attack on your same turn.
DM: No, no, it's just your next attack.
Wellby: Oh, that's so good.
DM: So you don't constantly have to steady aim.
Wellby: Ah, that's really, really nice.
Seeker: No, well against that creature.
DM: Your next attack against that creature.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: But not on your turn.
Unknown: Cool. Yeah.
DM: So if he wants to move around-
Seeker: Before the end of your next turn.
Unknown: That's great.
Delwath: So it's on your next... It's not, you can't hold it, but your next turn you can keep it.
DM: Anyway, sorry, how much damage did you do?
Wellby: 27.
DM: And [dice rolling] fails again.
DM: Wellby has gotten-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... gotten the aiming at the eyes down extremely well.
Kenzo: Might be a good Seeker out here.
DM: [coughs] As that ends Wellby's turn.
Seeker: That was a-
DM: And Kenzo.
Unknown: Huh?
DM: Standing behind the now very blinded stone construct.
Kenzo: All right, let's go, fucker.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] First staff attack.
Kenzo: Oh yeah, uh, that does eight damage.
Kenzo: Second staff attack [yawns] does, ooh, um, 16 damage.
Kenzo: First, uh, flurry of blows, natural 20, so I-
DM: Nice
Unknown: ... I, what do I do?
Seeker: Roll attack twice again.
DM: D10.
Kenzo: So roll it again.
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: So I have one plus [scoffs] three plus five, eight damage.
Kenzo: Uh, was that my second or third?
DM: One more.
Unknown: One more, okay. [dice rolling]
Unknown: That's-
Seeker: Six... 11.
Seeker: [dice rolling]
DM: Kenzo again with a flurry of blows.
DM: So this is four ki to mark off by the end.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: s- staggers this one back. It's now well past bloodied and looking pretty shaken as Delwath, or no, it-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... again
DM: punches out at both of you in its blinded stupor.
DM: [dice rolling] Uh, shield is off, right?
Seeker: Shield's off.
DM: So that's a...
DM: Oh, it has disadvantage.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: That's a 17 to hit Delwath.
Seeker: Yes.
DM: [dice rolling] Um, that's a 28 to hit.
DM: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Ooh, Delwath, damage.
DM: [dice rolling] Uh, that's a 14, 20, 27.
DM: [dice rolling]
Seeker: So seven or higher.
Unknown: Seven or higher.
Unknown: You can deflect it. [dice rolling] 10.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: Nice.
Seeker: Nice. [laughs]
DM: Once again. [laughs]
Unknown: Mm.
DM: If it wasn't blinded-
Seeker: The power of visualization
DM: ... and it could see [laughs] what was happening...
DM: So-
Seeker: Roll damage
DM: ... Dex save.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah. Uh, 2D-
DM: Fails its Dex save.
Unknown: It failed its Dex save?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: All right, so now 2D10 plus 5.
Unknown: [dice rolling] 24 damage.
Seeker: Wow. Wow.
DM: Delwath-
Seeker: It's, it's past bloodied, isn't it?
DM: Well past.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: All right.
Seeker: That's so fucked up, man.
Unknown: Jesus. [laughs]
Unknown: They get all fucked up when they attack me.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: What's up?
Delwath: And I have, I rolled a three.
DM: Oh, 19.
Seeker: There you go.
DM: That's better.
Seeker: What's happening here? Are you rolling those?
Delwath: I'm just rolling to see how many D4s I should roll.
Seeker: How many what?
DM: D8s.
Seeker: I hit twice. [dice rolling]
DM: Eight, nine,
Delwath: uh, and 18 plus 10, 20, 28.
Kenzo: This is just, what kind of attacks were you doing?
DM: Just, I mean, I- Delwath's last sword strike slashes it, and its body collapses in half with the hit.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: And it crumbles and falls,
DM: and there is for a moment quiet.
Seeker: Who, how badly are people hurt?
Kenzo: Uh, I'm hurt pretty bad.
Kenzo: 64. I've lost half my hit points.
Seeker: I turn back to a dwarf.
Delwath: [laughs] The ladder's pretty badly hurt too.
DM: The ladder's very badly hurt.
DM: The ladder s- took a lot of blows for you at the beginning there.
Seeker: The ladder has 18 out of its 85 remaining.
Seeker: But we can't really heal the ladder, right?
Seeker: I don't know.
Seeker: That's an interesting question.
Seeker: Can it be healed?
Delwath: I mean, probably we don't wanna take a short rest here, or do we?
Seeker: I think not.
Unknown: I don't think so.
Seeker: No, we should, um-
DM: There's nothing that says it can't be healed.
DM: It's a construct, so as long as your spell can heal constructs.
Delwath: Right. I don't have any good way of healing constructs.
Delwath: Do you need some healing though, Kenzo?
Kenzo: I need some healing, yeah. That'd be nice.
Seeker: I'm basically fine. I will-
Wellby: I'm basically fine too
Seeker: [laughs] Should I... Who knows what else we're gonna encounter in this tower.
Delwath: I mean, I could, I could get back two slots with a...
Delwath: Or wait, hold on. Once per day I get back two slots.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I get back all three of my slots if I use, wait, the-
Seeker: Ice cream?
Delwath: Oh, hey. We have ice cream.
DM: She's getting the hold of these guys, but-
Kenzo: Oh, that's cool too.
Unknown: What?
Unknown: I like that.
Delwath: Okay. I could get all of my slots back.
DM: Okay, well n- what are you doing in this immediate moment?
Kenzo: Somebody's healing you, right?
Wellby: I'm searching the construct bodies.
Wellby: In particular, I would love to get Hostile Fly number two to add to the collection.
DM: [laughs] Uh, yeah.
DM: Okay. Um.
Seeker: [laughs] Yeah.
Seeker: Is that still in physical form or anything?
DM: Bag.
DM: Uh, yeah, I mean technically none of you noticed it, but I just like dropped it there.
Seeker: Oh.
DM: Um,
DM: but you can search the-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... the crumbled bodies.
DM: Make a perception check.
Seeker: Um, so I, I'm gonna cast a Healing Word.
Delwath: Well, do you want me to cast it instead?
Wellby: 23.
Seeker: I mean, I have a bunch of... I haven't used any slots.
Delwath: I could just get them all back.
Seeker: How?
Delwath: Well, I can, once per day I can get back two slots,
Delwath: and then I can use my magical it- magic item to get back a third.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: So I could do 10 D4.
Seeker: Yeah, so it's-
DM: Okay. So Wellby's searching the rubble.
Delwath: Um, so Tim, I think this is too cheesy to do right now, but I really do think Prayer of Healing would be the better spell.
Kenzo: [laughs] Fucking, like how is there zero halflings or anybody in the fucking rainforest?
DM: Okay. But yes, that's too cheesy to do right now.
Delwath: But when we come out of the tower-
Unknown: Yes, that would be very useful because you could do 10 D2 rests
Seeker: ... random pure little things in there
Delwath: ... when we leave the tower that would be useful
DM: ... the target would be gone and you're like, "No."
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Well, I said it probably would be useful, but when we leave the tower, could I swap?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Next long rest you can swap.
Unknown: Yeah. Thank you.
Kenzo: So are you healing me?
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. I'm getting to other dice.
Unknown: I'm...
DM: Uh, what's Seeker doing?
Seeker: I guess I'll heal the ladder.
Delwath: Well, let's see how bad Kenzo-
Wellby: Maybe three more
Seeker: ... we should probably prioritize Kenzo getting healed.
Seeker: Yes.
Seeker: 5,
Seeker: uh,
Unknown: 10, one, two, three, four, five.
DM: Um, and Kenzo, so you're healing.
Seeker: 14.
DM: So We- uh, Wellby, you, you search around.
DM: Um, they're, they've mostly just kind of crumbled to dust as they fall.
DM: Um, but you do find-
Seeker: 14, 15, 16
DM: ... like in among the dust you find a couple things.
DM: One is, um-
Seeker: 18
DM: ... each one of them-
Seeker: 29
DM: ... in the center of the pile of dust is like a, a,
DM: a sort of
DM: strange m- like metallic shard that's like cracked now in half and seems totally inert, but probably was infused with magic at some point that powered them, or possibly
DM: like reflected spells.
Unknown: What did you just cast?
Seeker: Healing Word.
DM: And then-
Unknown: That's right
DM: ... um, you do find two little like small, like this big, intact flies, like metallic flies.
Seeker: Take those flies.
Wellby: Awesome.
Wellby: They're gonna be friends with the other flies.
Seeker: And maybe Faldrit could repair that spell reflector thing.
Seeker: Probably not, but.
Wellby: You end up like building them too.
DM: You do have a manual of the golem if you ever-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... want to unlock it.
Seeker: Oh, right.
Kenzo: Faldrit's an artificer, right?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Sweet.
DM: Cool, cool, cool.
DM: So
DM: having healed and searched-
Delwath: I mean, do you think, do you want more healing?
Kenzo: No, I'm actually good.
Unknown: You're okay?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Um, so I will cast a low level Healing Word on, uh, the ladder.
Seeker: [laughs]
Kenzo: I can do Uncanny Metabolism.
DM: Which I've never used.
Kenzo: Once per long rest when I roll initiative I regain all my ki and then regain 1D10 plus 15 hit points.
Delwath: And you should wait till your ki's a little bit lower.
Kenzo: Well, it's just next time we get into a fight.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I'll, I'm gonna do it.
Delwath: I guess you may as well do it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: How much ki do you have right now left?
Kenzo: Just, uh, just... A lot.
Unknown: 11.
Unknown: So
Delwath: you don't even need to do it next fight, right?
Kenzo: Right. Well, it's just nice to get the back 25 hit points.
Unknown: That's true.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [laughs] Well, there could be more than one more fight in the tower.
Delwath: Yeah, that's what I'm saying is you might wanna wait.
DM: Or there could be less. Or there could be less.
Kenzo: There could be no more fights.
DM: You guys-
Delwath: Right. So here's the question: Are we doing the mirror now?
Delwath: It doesn't take very long, right?
DM: No, it just takes a few minutes.
DM: I mean, it takes you a couple minutes to get it out of the hole, right?
Unknown: 10.
DM: Probably takes 10 minutes all told to-
Wellby: So I'm, I'm super into this.
Wellby: Doing this means we can't do it to Ra's hand.
Delwath: Yes, we still, we-
Wellby: Really.
Delwath: We can. We have-
Seeker: We just have to wait
Delwath: ... we have 10 days.
Wellby: It just, it cuts it real close-
Delwath: It means three days
Wellby: ... if we don't get what we need from this.
Kenzo: No, but no, Ra- Ra's hand is gonna give us a vision anyways once we like put it all together, 'cause every time we get a piece it gives us a vision.
Delwath: Also true.
Kenzo: So when we put the, when we put the whole hand together it's-
Wellby: Was Ra's hand... Why do we think Ra's hand would know, would be connected with the phylactery?
Delwath: 'Cause Tim told us.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: But, but...
Kenzo: No, no, no. Wait, but this is gonna tell us what the phylactery is.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It's not gonna tell us where it is.
Delwath: Right. But I think it'll tell us-
DM: Well, Ra's hand might not tell you that either.
Seeker: Right.
Delwath: I think it'll tell us something useful.
Delwath: Like here's the theory: We can't get these manacles,
Delwath: we can't take them with us.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? And
Delwath: it's gotta be useful.
Wellby: Right.
Unknown: Right?
Wellby: Right, right, right.
Delwath: And we have time.
Wellby: If Ra's hand doesn't give us what we need, we can't then look at the manacles.
Delwath: Correct. Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. And we have enough time to do both.
Delwath: We just have to let Apollyon get almost out, but Kenzo really wants to let him escape to make it more fun to kill him anyway.
Unknown: I think so.
Seeker: Right?
Kenzo: Like what if he like doesn't escape in this whole time?
Seeker: It's just like he's never gonna kill Apollyon.
Wellby: He's gonna be so disappointed.
Unknown: He doesn't get a chance to flex at all.
Unknown: You know?
Delwath: So I think we're fine, 'cause like honestly-
Kenzo: Hold on. Is there anything else...
Kenzo: 'Cause the mirror is 7D. Is there anything else that we want to show this thing?
Delwath: I mean, the only other thing that I could think of would be the Divine Forge itself.
Delwath: [coughs] But I think this is better.
Seeker: But the... oddly,
Seeker: the anvil in this room is not magical.
Seeker: So when you say Divine Forge itself, do you mean there's another one?
Delwath: I assume somewhere else in this workshop there's like...
Delwath: Maybe the Divine Forge is this.
Wellby: But, but this is, this is...
Wellby: Whether or not this is the Divine Forge, this is specifically the phylactery empowering room.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: That the f- we know-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... from the Identify spell that the phylactery was definitely here.
Seeker: We, yeah. Yeah, we should, we should use the mirror.
DM: We should use the mirror.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Mostly from Seeker rolling a natural 20 on her-
Seeker: 'Cause, 'cause like-
Unknown: ... Con when it busted.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. We should totally use the mirror.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Or do we finish search, just killing everything in here and then-
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause we might not be able to come back here.
Seeker: Yeah, that's true.
Delwath: For all we know, if we're gonna finish killing everything, which will involve-
Seeker: [laughs]
Delwath: ... flying out a window as birds.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Flying, flying.
Seeker: Most, most likely scenario.
DM: Birds.
Delwath: Or teleporting back to Dimitar as, like, we can escape.
Unknown: Like-
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah. All right, fuck it. Let's do it.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: Fuck it.
Delwath: So we finish as, like...
Seeker: Yeah, let's fucking do it.
DM: Wait, that teleport spell slot.
Wellby: Should we... As long as we're pulling the mirror out, should we talk to the-
DM: We still have that.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: We used your 8.1.
Seeker: Oh, but wasn't it your seventh?
Unknown: No, this has Tremor.
Seeker: It's his seventh. All right.
Wellby: Oh, you're right.
Seeker: [laughs]
Wellby: You're right. Too many fucking mirrors.
Seeker: Wait, what?
Unknown: But we should talk to the...
Wellby: As long as we're pulling mirrors out.
Unknown: We should have talked to the hob-
Seeker: [laughs]
Kenzo: I mean, I don't know if we should retcon talking to the hobgoblin, 'cause we would've talked to the hobgoblin probably back when we long rested.
Seeker: Up at the, up at the castle.
Delwath: No, no, no, 'cause we're doing the dragon...
Delwath: We're gonna have a regroup-
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... before we do the dragon. We'll talk to the hobgoblin then.
Seeker: Okay. Okay.
Delwath: The problem is we haven't decided whether we want to try and get the hobgoblin to help us kill-
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... right. We have some-
Seeker: We'll figure that out.
DM: Right. It's hobgoblin help you kill dragon or dragon help you kill Apollyon are
DM: incompatible choices.
Delwath: Right. We can't do both.
Seeker: Okay. How about I do, um, while we're getting the mirror out, I'll do Tremor Sense again just to see if there's anything else within 60 feet.
DM: Nothing else within 60 feet.
Seeker: All right. That's good.
Seeker: [laughs] This is great.
Seeker: It's like we-
Unknown: Now... Huh
Seeker: ... we think we've taken out all the security systems of Apollyon's Tower.
Seeker: What do we, what do we, what do we, what do we do?
DM: Well, there's a whole 'nother tower below this tower.
Seeker: There sure is.
Kenzo: I mean, I think maybe we say, uh...
Kenzo: We, after the mirror, we, we literally just say, "Show us Apollyon's phylactery."
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Somebody roll a D20.
Wellby: With-
Unknown: With what?
Wellby: ... inspiration. With runic inspiration.
Kenzo: All the things. Who's, uh...
Delwath: Well, somebody who's been rolling. I've rolled like nothing.
Wellby: You have heroic inspiration.
DM: You roll.
DM: Kenzo. Kenzo's, Kong's rolled really well.
Unknown: Kong's hands are hot.
Wellby: I have been rolling well. But, uh-
Seeker: Roll a D20
Kenzo: ... wait, wait, hold on. Uh, this is, it's wisdom or what is this?
DM: You add, it's just add your straight wisdom, so plus three, plus bardic inspiration, which you already have.
Kenzo: Does anybody, does anybody else have, um, uh...
Seeker: I still have heroic inspiration.
Delwath: And you still have heroic inspiration too.
Wellby: But that, that only works for...
Wellby: What is that?
DM: No, it works for anything.
Delwath: Any roll that you don't like you can re-roll.
DM: You can do both heroic inspiration and bardic inspiration on this roll.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: All right. Well, let's do one at a time.
Wellby: Let's just, let's see this guy first.
Wellby: So
Wellby: show us the phylactery.
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Hot.
Wellby: Uh, uh.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Hot.
DM: Kenzo.
Unknown: Add a D12 to that?
DM: You may as well add the D12 because-
Seeker: Do it. Do it. Do it
DM: ... you know, the inspiration's not gonna last.
Wellby: All right.
DM: You roll it twice and take the higher one.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: That's a four.
Seeker: Second one is
Seeker: an eight.
DM: It's an eight. So that's a-
Unknown: So 12.
Wellby: 27.
Kenzo: 27.
Unknown: No, plus his three wisdom.
DM: Plus three. That's 30.
Unknown: Yeah, 30.
Wellby: Wow. [laughs]
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Fucking show us the phylactery.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: So Kenzo takes out the mirror.
Seeker: Nice.
DM: And for a minute the room goes dark and you see, um,
DM: Apollyon with his back turned.
DM: Like, again, it's from the perspective of the manacles.
DM: Apollyon with his back turned, standing by the forge.
Kenzo: What does he look like? Is, is, he's a human right now.
DM: He's a human right now.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: He's, like, wearing, um, he's wearing the, the crown that you seen Fastil have,
DM: and he's wearing the cloak.
Seeker: What does that crown do again?
Seeker: We don't know.
DM: We don't know. But it makes the cloak.
Unknown: Oh, wait. Did he ever get the cloak?
DM: Yeah, he still has the cloak from Yorx.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Does it... The ring. Did he get the ring?
DM: Nope. He never had the ring.
Wellby: He never got the ring.
Kenzo: What was the ring?
Delwath: The ring was not one of Apollyon's three artifacts.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: It was just a separate ring we found.
DM: It was a separate ring. It was made, like, long ago by some...
Kenzo: And that was Grash's ring.
DM: That was Grash.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: And the cloak is all rainbowy.
DM: The cloak is all rainbowy.
Kenzo: So he looks kind of gay.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Just, like, kind of like-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... he's, like, a little flaming, a little...
DM: Um.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: But-
Unknown: I like that
DM: ... but when he's wearing it, it actually looks like there's color in it, yes, you can't stop the color, but there's also shadows running through the color.
Kenzo: Yeah, I want him to be like a rave lick, you know?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um.
Seeker: It's dark rainbow.
DM: Yeah, it's a dark rainbow.
DM: And he's, he's banging on something.
Kenzo: How old is Apollyon here? Does he like-
DM: Uh, he's like mid-40s.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Hmm. [laughs]
DM: Maybe, maybe a bit older, maybe like mid-50s.
DM: It's hard to say. Somewhere, like, not old, not young.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Somewhere in that age.
Kenzo: Is he strong looking?
Wellby: Take care of himself.
Unknown: Is he like, you know?
DM: He's... Yeah. He's, I mean, he's pr-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: He's, he's hammering something behind him on a forge, right?
DM: He's hammering, he's working the, some sort of metal, and he'll, every now and then he'll turn around.
DM: He's holding up, like, a partially forged dagger, and it looks s- it looks very plain.
DM: Like, there's nothing...
DM: You know, the hilt is super plain.
DM: It's just
DM: straight iron.
DM: The blade, um, looks like it's, has layers and layers of metal that's been beat into it, and there's, there's writing on
DM: the blade.
DM: Um,
DM: and then-
Unknown: Can we read it?
DM: Yeah. It's, um,
DM: it, it seems to be part of some incantation or spell.
DM: It's like, you know, there's no...
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It, it's not, like, saying anything specific.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um, and then he's banging again, and then he stops and he takes, like, the sheet of this...
DM: ... strange looking metal. Actually, Seeker would recognize it.
DM: This is like adamantium.
DM: It's the-
Seeker: Oh, yeah, we had some once.
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... metal you had. It's what power, well, it's what holds the binding stone...
DM: Or sorry, the-
Seeker: The phasing stone
DM: ... phasing stone in place.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. And he's like tracing with his hand, and as he does, um, letters appear on this like thin sheet of this metal.
DM: And then he puts the dagger down and he like wraps the metal around it and he starts beating it again.
DM: This goes on for,
DM: you know, a while. It seems like he's just doing layer after layer where he's putting some spells on it and then beating something into the dagger.
DM: And then the scene shifts, and it seems
DM: some time later,
DM: and there is, um, like you can't quite...
DM: You can't see what it is, but there's clearly a person chained in the manacles.
DM: But your, your perspective is looking down-
Unknown: Yeah, so you-
DM: ... at the manacles, so you basically just see wrists.
DM: And then the wrists go limp and you can see like slashes, the dagger slashing the wrists, and the blood
DM: runs down into the floor, like running down the arms.
DM: But
DM: there's some like spark that runs into the dagger from the manacles, and this happens again and again, and the floor now you can see this like well in the middle is filling
DM: up with blood of like 10 people.
Unknown: Oh, God.
DM: And it gets... It's drying out and it gets darker and thicker as it dries out.
DM: And the mirror shifts again, and you can see now Apollyon standing.
DM: The manacle's empty, and he is kneeling on the floor.
DM: The blood all dried except for in this very well in the very center, which now looks black, and he draws a
DM: clear vial, like a potion vial out from his, from his robes, and he begins...
DM: The, the, the gems in the crown, there's like shadow flowing out of the crown into the blood.
DM: It begins to swirl, and this sort of dark black viscous liquid floats up and pours itself into the vial, which he then
DM: stoppers.
DM: And Seeker recalls that the lore of licks is typically that they are...
DM: To become a lick you need to create a phylactery, and then you need to make a potion somehow, the rituals are not known, from
DM: involving somehow the souls of the people who fed your phylactery.
Delwath: It's the dagger.
DM: And when you drink the potion, you turn into a lick.
DM: But the dagger is clearly the phylactery.
DM: Plain, unadorned-
Unknown: Hm
DM: ... uninteresting dagger.
DM: The only notable fact is its blade is made out of adamantine.
Delwath: Seeker can find adamantine, can't he?
Seeker: That's a good point.
DM: I believe he can.
Delwath: Yeah, it's probably not that common of a metal.
DM: Possibly not.
Seeker: No. It's... No, it's not.
Kenzo: How do you find adamantine?
Seeker: Well, I have my stone sense, which can-
Kenzo: What's the range?
DM: 1,000 feet, so it's not super wide.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But you can amplify that with your, uh-
Seeker: No, that's not for spells I think
Unknown: ...
Unknown: amplifier.
DM: Um, yeah.
Unknown: The glyph.
DM: Well, and that's... So that's a spell that targets the range itself, and it gives you an ability to sense 1,000 feet.
DM: So you-
Delwath: You can only increase where the range of the spell.
Delwath: You can't increase the range of-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... the effect of a spell that you cast on yourself.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Wellby: You couldn't double the radius of a fireball.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You couldn't... Like a fireball's a 20-foot radius.
DM: You couldn't make it 40 feet.
Delwath: But you could make it appear-
DM: You could make it appear farther away
Delwath: ... farther away.
DM: Right.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: All right.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: I mean-
Wellby: Have we ever seen this dagger before?
DM: I mean,
DM: you've seen hundreds of daggers that look very similar to it, right?
DM: Like part of the...
DM: It's clear that part of the design is to make it look as uninteresting as possible.
Unknown: Right.
DM: It just looks like a normal dagger.
Seeker: Well, 1,000 feet of stone sense would cover the entirety of the tower that we're in now.
Seeker: It's probably not here though.
Unknown: No, no.
Delwath: No, it's more Drankorian.
Kenzo: It's Drankorian.
Unknown: But-
Delwath: 'Cause 1,000 feet in all directions.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: I mean, it would be ridiculous if it were literally here and we could kill
Unknown: Apollyon right now.
Delwath: I mean, is your stone sense a free action?
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: It's just a spell. It's like an action.
Delwath: But I mean, how many times-
DM: And so you, you just hold up the ring and-
Delwath: How many times can you do it?
DM: Three times a day.
Seeker: Three times a day, yeah.
Delwath: You, you may as well see if there's any adamantine in this tower.
Seeker: I'm gonna just do that. I will just right now.
Delwath: Right? Like what's the harm?
Seeker: Um, here, I'll pull up the stone sense.
Kenzo: Do we have any sense of when the... So he was 50 years old, so he w- this would've been like-
DM: This was probably tw- close towards the end of his reign.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Like not at the very last moment, but within the last 10 years.
Kenzo: Yeah, 'cause he was in civil war with Shemut, or he was in conflict with Shemut.
DM: He, yeah, he was in conflict with Shemut.
Kenzo: And probably know that it was not going well 'cause Shemut like was about to wipe him out and put him in prison.
DM: Do you want to sense it?
Seeker: I will use stone sense to-
DM: Okay
Seeker: ... search for adamantine.
DM: Okay. There are, there is adamantine.
DM: There's scraps of it on the floor in front of you.
DM: That's the only adamantine in the tower.
Unknown: Yeah, that makes sense.
Unknown: Wow.
Seeker: Just verifying. Well, that was a good use of the mirror I think, everybody.
Unknown: That was, that was-
DM: Oh, yeah. Excellent. [laughs]
Kenzo: That, that was, that, that was one of the best.
Seeker: We learned something absolutely crucial.
Kenzo: That was, that was, that was one of the most important uses ever.
Unknown: All right, so downward, right?
Kenzo: Do you want to take the scraps of adamantine?
Delwath: I mean, you may as well. Honestly.
Seeker: They, they might be tiny, tiny fragments.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, you could gather up like-
Delwath: But like-
DM: ... half a pound or something.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: That's significant.
Kenzo: But isn't this also useful for some other shit?
Kenzo: 'Cause like now 'cause it's part of the same adamantine as the dagger so-
Delwath: I was just gonna say like-
Kenzo: ... can you like teleport to it or like... You know what I mean?
Unknown: Like-
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Is there some weird like-
DM: Yeah, I didn't think of that
Delwath: ... like there's all kinds of potential abilities.
Delwath: Like who knows what it is right now, but it's-
Unknown: Yeah, definitely save this
Unknown: ... good to have.
Kenzo: Adamantine scraps from, from, uh, Apollyon's phylactery feels like a useful item.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yep.
Delwath: What if we showed them to the mirror?
Delwath: But we can't. I know we can't, right?
DM: I mean, you'd probably just see a worse version of what you just saw.
Unknown: Right, we probably would.
DM: You'd see the forging, but not what happened later.
Seeker: I will add those to my-
DM: Yeah
Seeker: ... inventory so we don't forget.
Wellby: All right, this was definitely worth coming to.
Unknown: Let's go down.
DM: Descend the stairs.
Wellby: Wellby scouting carefully, alertly.
Kenzo: And, and now we, we just like leave if we feel it's really threatened at all.
Unknown: Or do we just...
Wellby: Just gotta move stuff.
Delwath: I mean, the treasure, right? The treasure.
Kenzo: Yeah, there's, there's, there's-
Delwath: Think of the treasure.
Kenzo: Of course, of course. Well, 'cause the other thing too is this is where he made the, um, made, uh, his flappy.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But where the fuck did he make the scepter?
Kenzo: And where else did he make the crown?
Delwath: That's what I mean by divine forge.
Unknown: 'Cause that's also definitely where it is.
Wellby: It's not in this room, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, it's probably not in this room.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: It's down.
DM: The stairs go...
DM: Make a perception check.
Wellby: Uh, 23.
DM: Okay. The stairs go down the entire length of the spire with no breaks or stops or doors.
Kenzo: Can't you detect underground stuff?
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: Okay.
Wellby: So this whole second spire is just a room and a very long flight of stairs.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: All right, so we come out-
DM: That's it
Delwath: ... we come out on the, like, middle section.
DM: You come out in the middle section.
DM: There is a, there is a, uh...
DM: So you come out to a landing that has a door out to the middle section and then more stairs that go down.
Delwath: And is the door, like, out...
Delwath: Is it this door?
DM: It's that door. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: So, like, you're at a landing where you could exit to the middle section or you could continue down into the main tower.
Unknown: Let's just go down.
Seeker: There was nothing on that middle section aside from-
DM: There's-
Unknown: ... the two statues we killed
Wellby: Yeah, nothing else out there.
Delwath: I mean, we didn't search it.
DM: Well, you haven't gone out there.
Seeker: We saw it from the air.
DM: You saw it from the air.
Unknown: You wanna go out there? You wanna go out?
Wellby: I don't like the idea of something being behind us.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, no.
Wellby: So we don't.
Unknown: Down.
Seeker: Fair.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: So I'll go out.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Maybe assist. We'll take a perceptive walk around.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: See if there's anything else out there.
DM: Okay. Um, make a perception check with advantage.
Wellby: 19, 32.
DM: Um, nothing.
Wellby: [laughs] All right, I'm reasonably confident there's nothing there.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: All right, cool. Down.
Delwath: All right, onward.
DM: Uh, you descend down, um, and you come...
Kenzo: Weren't there four statues at the start of this thing?
Unknown: Two.
Wellby: There were only two, yeah.
DM: Yeah, there was only ever two.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um,
DM: you come down, um, into
DM: a, the, the, the next room down of the tower is just one large open room.
DM: There are stairs that continue down.
DM: There's windows. There were no windows in the room at the very top.
DM: The windows are open and you can smell the salt air of the sea blowing in.
DM: You can hear the waves crashing.
Wellby: That's suspicious.
Unknown: Sounds pleasant.
DM: Um.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh, there is almost nothing here.
DM: Um, there are
DM: perhaps once, like, a desk, but the wood, wood has over many, many years has almost entirely rotted away.
DM: Um, there are,
DM: uh, yeah, there's like dust on the floor where one might have
DM: once had
DM: shelves or chairs.
DM: Um, there's stairs going further down.
Wellby: Just everything is disintegrated.
DM: Everything is disintegrated in this room.
Kenzo: Nothing magical?
DM: Nothing magical.
Wellby: No disturbances in the dust.
DM: Make a perception check.
Wellby: Uh, 25.
DM: No footprints in the dust.
Delwath: Um, what... So the only exit is the stairs down still?
DM: Stairs down, yeah.
Delwath: So this is like... I'm envisioning this as the spire was narrower.
Unknown: Is that right?
DM: It is, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: This is much wider. This is-
Unknown: So like we've come-
DM: ... 50 feet in across, in diameter
Delwath: ... so the spiral staircase come down in the middle of a room?
DM: The spiral staircase comes down to the landing, and then, yeah, it's descending down the center of the tower.
Delwath: Okay. So like from the landing we went down the same staircase, but now instead of on the...
DM: No. The land- the staircase on the land- in the middle part is along the edge of the tower, and then there's another staircase that spirals down the center, like with a pole that is winding down, all the way running through probably
DM: the entire length of the tower.
Delwath: Right. So it... But that was along the...
Delwath: That was effectively... So now that we're in the bigger section, we're coming down the middle section.
DM: Yeah, now you're coming down the middle.
Seeker: And then are, coming down, are we now at the ground level?
DM: No, no, no.
Unknown: No, we're still-
DM: We're still quite far up
Delwath: ... 100 something feet up.
DM: There's stairs that, the mid- the staircase that runs in the middle continues down.
DM: It's like there's a pillar through the middle of the tower.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Right?
Seeker: But there's more, there's more levels below the ground.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: We've just seen. Okay.
Wellby: Next floor.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, the next floor,
DM: uh, has a very similar vibe.
DM: Um, windows open, the smell of the air.
DM: You can even hear a few birds far in the distance.
DM: Um, this was probably once a library.
DM: You can see like scraps of the covers of books.
DM: You can see like metal bindings where books were held, but everything that's, um, uh, you know, leather or paper or
DM: wood has decayed, exposed to the salt air of the sea over the past 700 years.
DM: Except for two books.
Wellby: Oh?
DM: That seem to be completely intact and untouched by time.
Unknown: Are they magical?
DM: Yes.
Wellby: What are they?
Unknown: What sort of magic?
DM: Uh, one is, um, necromancy.
DM: Um, the other is,
DM: I guess like
DM: divination.
Kenzo: I dare Seeker to lick the necromancy book.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Literally it's already on the cover.
Wellby: The necromancy book licks you.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah. Um, the, the necromancy one, uh-
DM: ... has just a, a cute, like a deep crimson red cover.
DM: Absolutely no markings on it anywhere, just crimson red.
DM: Um, the other one, the, hard to say what, it's not really a precisely a school of magic, but maybe divination, um, has
Unknown: a,
DM: a metal sort of clasp.
DM: Like, it's almost like there's two hands, like holding it like this.
DM: There's like lines of metal that run across and run, and there's a lock-
Unknown: Hmm
DM: ... um, that keeps the book locked shut.
Unknown: So my vote, open the portable hole, drop them in the portable hole with Mei Chen, deal with them later.
DM: Feels wise.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Also.
DM: You say that
DM: like, like what are you talking about?
DM: Wise?
Unknown: Feels, feels-
Seeker: Right, right. Yeah. We'll, we'll do that.
Seeker: But just quickly before we do that-
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: I'll just, I'll just put the goggles back over my face and just have a look-
DM: Yeah
Seeker: ... using my, not using identify-
DM: No
Seeker: ... 'cause I did that again today, but just, just-
Wellby: Not like o- opening or that
Seeker: No, I'm just looking at the outside of the book.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: And just kinda like... [laughs]
DM: Which, which, which, which one are you looking at first?
Seeker: I'm gonna look at the necromancy book.
Wellby: Like that thing is gonna eat you if you open it.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Like, for sure, right?
Seeker: Well, I'm not, I'm not, I'm not open... I'm, I'm not even gonna touch it.
Seeker: I'm just, I'm just getting my face fairly close to it.
DM: [laughs] Fairly close.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Seeker's like-
Kenzo: Close enough to lick it, but you know, not, not actually eat it.
DM: Well, use all your senses.
Wellby: Close enough to identify what humanoid skin it's bound in.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Uh, any interesting odors-
DM: Make, um
Unknown: ... sounds that are coming from it.
DM: Uh, make an arcana check with advantage.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Um. [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Oh, that feels good.
Seeker: So that's a 15 plus 15, that's a 30.
DM: Okay. And make a charisma saving throw.
Unknown: Fucking bitch.
Seeker: Oh, man.
Delwath: May I... Wait, wait. Roll and look.
Unknown: [coughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Don't look at the result.
DM: No, no, you can look at the result.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: We should not look at it.
Kenzo: I'm gonna get a heroic save.
Kenzo: Heroic save.
Delwath: Now does he have heroic inspiration?
DM: Uh, do you have inspiration?
Delwath: Oh, wait, everybody should have it, 'cause I...
Delwath: Oh, no, three, one person-
Seeker: I haven't used mine.
Unknown: Oh, no, no, you have it.
DM: Yeah. I was gonna say, you have it.
Unknown: You have it. [coughs]
Kenzo: But he also has a heroic saving throw.
Kenzo: He has a heroic, heroic saving throw.
DM: No, right here.
DM: That's what he's using. [dice rolling] Nope, come here.
Unknown: Wait, wait, what the fuck?
DM: He rolled twice.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay. While, while Seeker's curse is happening, does anyone want ice cream?
Unknown: [sighs]
Wellby: Maybe it's like a great boon that he's receiving.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: That now he needs to eat souls.
Unknown: [coughs]
Delwath: He'd like to be a lich, it turns out.
Wellby: We literally were right there.
Kenzo: We literally were like, "Mei Chen in the portal hole."
Kenzo: We were right there.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: We were right there.
Wellby: It didn't seem safe enough.
Unknown: We were right there. [laughs] We were right there.
DM: Uh, Seeker looks up, and what you...
DM: So there's a few things that you realize looking at this.
DM: Does anybody... Ice cream?
DM: It is-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... definitely made of the...
DM: It's definitely made of human skin that's been soaked in blood-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... and this is almost
DM: certainly the book that explains how you become a lich.
Seeker: Mm, mm, mm.
Seeker: Good thing I looked at it closely.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: uh, yeah, I think you're right.
Seeker: We should probably just, just put it in the, in the hole.
Wellby: You good?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: You, you okay?
Unknown: Of course. Yeah.
Kenzo: You're fine? Nothing, nothing, nothing changes about you?
Unknown: Nothing.
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: You're just totally, tot- Actually, um, I soul sight.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Um, I soul sight him.
DM: Uh,
DM: okay. Make an insight check.
Kenzo: Hold on. Which, uh, w- um, I've got a way to soul sight with, like extra, um...
Kenzo: Oh, I can also cleanse you too, if you, depending on what's going on with you.
DM: Well, you don't... As far as you can tell, nothing's going on with him.
Unknown: Ah, yeah.
DM: You don't know that he had to roll a saving throw.
Unknown: I don't know that. I know anything.
DM: Right? Like what's your, what's your in-game reason for-
Wellby: It, it's Seeker takes Tome of Dark Necromancy-
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: ... and puts it directly in front of his face.
Kenzo: And the last time too, like he...
Kenzo: Something weird. All right. Um.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Insight check?
DM: Yeah.
DM: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Mm, I'll say it's 12, but um,
Kenzo: is it worth using my, um...
DM: No.
Wellby: Do you have inspiration?
Kenzo: This isn't a saving throw.
DM: It's not a saving throw.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Doesn't seem to... I mean, Seeker seems the same sort of-
Unknown: Yeah. Seems like-
DM: ... dangerously curious person he's always been.
Seeker: Who likes frozen treats, just like always.
DM: Who likes frozen treats, just like always.
Unknown: Thanks.
Delwath: Well, I'm gonna Mei Chen them into the portable hole.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Does touching them with Mei Chen do anything scary?
Unknown: I'm 30 feet away.
DM: No.
Delwath: Just like brush them along.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Let them plop into the hole.
Delwath: [dice rolling] It's fine.
Delwath: Should take a remove curse, but it's fine.
Unknown: It's fine. It's fine, right?
Kenzo: Oh, I forgot that I can grapple with unarmed strikes.
DM: That's new. Oh, I forgot to mention that.
Unknown: That's-
DM: It's actually super good.
Kenzo: That's super good.
DM: Yeah. You can drag things around.
Kenzo: The target must succeed on a... What? Oh, it chooses with strength to dexterity, saving throw DC equals 8 plus...
Kenzo: Or has a grapple condition. Wow.
Kenzo: And then is shove also new?
DM: Yeah, shove's also new.
Delwath: Ooh. I forgot, Tim, I can actually make anything huge or smaller automatically prone when I Eldritch Smite.
DM: I thought you vanished and smites.
DM: Yeah, you can do that.
Unknown: I just forgot.
DM: Right.
DM: All right.
Unknown: Well.
DM: Next level?
Unknown: Uh, continue down. You know, I think it's just, uh-
Kenzo: Seeker bouncing from curse to curse, you know?
Unknown: It's kind of his thing.
Wellby: No, uh-
Unknown: Think you, think you said he's fine?
Wellby: Yeah, he's fine.
DM: He's fine.
Wellby: You worry about him too much.
DM: Yeah, he's fine.
Wellby: Well-
DM: The right amount
Wellby: ... maybe we don't worry about him enough.
DM: Worry about what?
Wellby: Seeker. [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: There's a reason it's called a terminal curiosity.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: [laughs] Or irresistible curiosity.
DM: You going down to the next floor?
Wellby: No other, no hidden things, hidden traps, secret rooms, secret doors, patterns in the dust?
DM: Nope.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: Wow.
Delwath: Do we have a wand to find secret something?
Delwath: No, it's detect magic that we have, right?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Which detects interplanar portals also.
DM: Yeah, it's very useful.
Delwath: We could use that to find the dragon's interplanar portal.
Seeker: There, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: All right. But we should use it once we're closer.
DM: Down to the next floor?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay, so, uh, who's, what's the order are you going down in?
Wellby: I think I'm going first.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: I'll go second, Seeker third, Delwath fourth.
Kenzo: That's like our standard order, right?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: I'm usually in back, but I think it makes sense to be in front
Wellby: scouting this place out.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Okay, you...
Delwath: Actually, by Kenzo, I should be in front, you should be in back 'cause you can, you can run a lot more fast.
DM: Okay, that's fine.
Wellby: Mm.
Delwath: So if we meet something, it's a lot easier for you to close with it.
DM: Okay, so, um,
DM: uh, on this floor, you come out and there's like, there's a wall that goes, you come out in the middle of like, the pillar goes down the middle of the room, and the stairway stops here.
DM: There's a wall that runs in the middle, so you, you can only see half of the
DM: floor. There's two doors on either side of like about 10 feet
DM: away from the middle of the staircase.
DM: Um, and the, the side of it you-
Delwath: But so the wall runs-
DM: Just bisects the-
Delwath: But not, but it's on one side of the stair- staircase?
DM: Yeah, yeah, on one side of the staircase.
DM: Um, and the only exits from this room you can immediately see are the two doors, um, each about halfway in between the staircase and the wall.
Delwath: But in the wall bisecting the room.
DM: Yeah, yeah. Um, they're fairly elaborate doors.
DM: Um, like they're, like most of the building is actually just kind of plain black stone, sort of unadorned, anything like that.
DM: Um, and in this room, this also was probably once, um,
DM: some kind of
DM: meeting room or something like that.
DM: Like, there's a spot in the middle where it looks like there was a big table.
DM: Um, the thing that's different here is that there, and there also were probably once tapestries hanging on the wall.
DM: You can see the sort of discolored spots where cloth once was hanging.
DM: Um, there are,
DM: uh, three statues.
DM: One is a statue of Apollyon,
DM: um, carved out of a sort of light gray marble.
DM: Um, well, well made, um, wearing the crown, holding up the scepter, not wearing the cloak.
DM: Um, and he seems to be, he's like raising his hand up in sort of like, um, benediction or something like that.
DM: And the other two statues are other probably Drankorian emperors, not anybody you recognize, but the way that they're, um,
DM: sort of
DM: carved and built, like they seem, they have that sort of imperial, sort of regal vibe.
DM: Um, and written,
DM: um, a- across the, the top o- of the wall is, um...
DM: Okay, I didn't have actually time to get to this.
DM: It's the super cool sounding motto of the Omnis pura that makes it clear it's the Omnis pura,
DM: humans live forever or something like that.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But I never came up with what the super cool motto of the Omnis pura would be.
Delwath: Doesn't translate well from the original Dran-
DM: Doesn't translate from the original Drankorian, right.
DM: Sounds sort of stilted when you translate it into Common, right?
DM: It's like...
DM: Um, but, and this has all, the statues have all survived.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, and-
Kenzo: Are they magic?
DM: This, there's, there's no magic in here, but Wellby you can hear
DM: rattling from the other side of the door, faint rattling.
Kenzo: [laughs] Does it sound like a cuddly bunny rattling?
Wellby: Like metal stone rattlesnake.
DM: Like metal against stone.
Wellby: Do I look under the door?
Delwath: I'm gonna look through the wall.
DM: Ah, with Gutsleige?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Um, there is a...
DM: I want this light.
Wellby: It's a better choice.
Unknown: Okay, from, uh, the heroic inspiration, why do we all get heroic inspiration?
Delwath: 'Cause Delwath cooked a nice breakfast, and every time we short rest and Delwath cooks a meal, everybody gets heroic inspiration.
Unknown: Fucking awesome.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: okay.
DM: Long or short rest.
DM: So what you see is actually a very strange sight.
DM: Um, there is, uh, it looks like, you can't see anything moving it, but it, so the room...
DM: D- oh, Delwath's looking through, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So, um, there's a staircase down from the other side of this statue, or sorry, from the other side of this room, and there's, um,
DM: there's, there's, there's not much-
Delwath: So the staircase, is it like another-
DM: It's against the wall now.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um,
DM: and there is a,
DM: uh...
DM: So again, the room is fairly empty.
DM: Um, there are, uh,
DM: you know, it was probably, who knows what it once was, it's hard to say, but there's like some me- loose like metal or like just scraps of stuff.
DM: Like maybe there was once like- ...
DM: two, like, pieces of armor that-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... stood guard by the doors or something, but they've fallen down now.
DM: But the, but the, these little scraps of metal seem to be, like, floating and scraping against the floor and kind of moving around in these weird chaotic ways in the air.
Delwath: It's a... Huh.
Delwath: While I'm looking through things, what's beneath us?
DM: Ah.
Unknown: Next to what?
Delwath: Well, through the floor, too.
Unknown: Ah, yeah.
DM: Uh, what's beneath you,
DM: um, is what looks like was once a bedroom, but the bed has almost completely rotted away.
DM: Um, there is, like, the iron bindings of what used to be a chest and a pile of tarnished Drankorian coins.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Useful. Useful to know.
Delwath: So it's just, like, little fla- specks of metal floating around in the air basically?
DM: Yeah, like scraping against the floor sometimes and kind of moving in this sort of chaotic, slightly chaotic way.
Unknown: Is it magic?
DM: No.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: I'll describe it.
Seeker: Well, what does that mean that that's not magic?
Wellby: Is it something that's mostly invisible, but parts of it are
Wellby: visible? I wouldn't expect chaotic motion from that.
Seeker: Or something that has been animated but long since-
Wellby: That would be magic though
Seeker: ... eroded.
Unknown: I mean,
Unknown: detect magic doesn't necessarily detect a magical...
Unknown: Although it detected the stone, right?
Wellby: What if there's, like, an air elemental in the, uh-
DM: Which stone?
Unknown: The stone construct. Didn't it detect as magic?
Unknown: I can't remember what you said.
DM: The stone construct did not detect as magic.
Unknown: The manacles were magic.
Seeker: So maybe there was, like, a wood construct with, like, little bits of metal in it.
Seeker: Now all that's left is the metal
Seeker: because it rotted away.
Wellby: Both doors lead... It's a single room, so it means both doors-
DM: Yeah, it's a single room. Both doors lead to the same room.
Seeker: What e- Wait, what else is in that room?
Unknown: Nothing.
DM: Stairs down.
Delwath: Stairs down. The room beneath us is a bedroom with a chest of coins.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: And does that... Does it seem like that would be the ground level, or are we still high?
DM: Nope, you're still probably 40 feet abov- 50 feet above the ground,
DM: 60 feet above the ground. I mean, you could go look out the window if you want to try and judge.
Delwath: Oh, wait, there's windows now. We could just turn back into birds.
Wellby: Oh, yeah, and fly down to the next floor.
Seeker: Yep, that's true. We do not need to-
Unknown: Let's do that
Seeker: ... use the stairs.
Seeker: So I turn everyone back into ospreys.
DM: You just fly down one level?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, why not?
DM: Okay, yeah.
Seeker: Fly out the window.
Delwath: Fly into the bedroom.
DM: Uh-
Delwath: There was windows in the bedroom, right?
DM: Yep, there's multiple rooms on this floor.
DM: The floor is divided up.
DM: So you fly into the window that looks like the bedroom.
Delwath: Well, was there any... I mean, on the half that I can walk around and look through, I want to look through.
DM: Oh, look, you're just, like, walking across the whole-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah, so there's two rooms here.
DM: There's, like, a bedroom and a study, basically.
Delwath: Okay. Um, I'm actually, while I'm doing this with ghostly gaze, this only lasts a minute, I can't do it again, I would like to look through the entire floor here and look to see, like, are there any secret...
Delwath: In the room beneath us where there's a bedroom and a study, are there any, like, secret areas?
DM: Nope, it looks pretty boring, just a bedroom and a study.
Delwath: Okay. There's not, like, a hidden little section against the wall or anything like that?
DM: Nope.
Delwath: All right. Let's turn back into birds and just skip.
Delwath: The, the, the vibe of that chaos thing, I think it's gonna, like, tear into us if we...
Unknown: Let's just skip it.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, we just explore the next... skip it.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: Explore the next floor.
DM: Okay. So you fly into the next floor as birds.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Um, so again, there's, like, a bedroom and a study, and then it connects to a corridor, and then, um, uh,
DM: a corridor where the stairs come down, and then there's another, like, uh, cha- set of chambers on the other side.
DM: Um-
Delwath: So is it, like, divided into four basically?
DM: Yeah, it's like... So not quite.
DM: It's like,
DM: it's like-
Kenzo: I can't believe we skipped the chaos thing.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Seeker, you didn't feel really compelled by that
DM: ... the stairs come down here.
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: Right? So there's, like, there's this sort of dead space.
Seeker: It was a native flesh or anything. [laughs]
DM: And then there's, this comes out into a corridor he- And then there's a- Well, I'm not drawing this very well.
DM: This is, like, where the corridor is.
DM: Yeah, it is basically divided into four.
DM: This is, like, the staircase.
DM: The staircase comes down-
Wellby: There are no tongues
DM: ... and ends in a corner.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And then... Well, actually-
Seeker: It was made of some random body part and the tongues of students
DM: ... this is, the staircase does lead like this. And then there's, like, three rooms like that.
Unknown: Right.
DM: The staircase keeps going down.
Delwath: And so which one's the... We come in here.
DM: The, this is the bedroom and the study.
DM: That's, like-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... that one's, like, servant's quarters or something like that.
DM: It's much smaller.
Delwath: So we come in through the bedroom. And is there a door from the bedroom to the study?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Okay. So-
DM: But not to the servant's quarters.
DM: There's a door from the bedroom to the study, and then from the study to the corridor, and then there's, like, a small room-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... pressed up against the stairs.
Delwath: So is there anything magical in the bedroom?
DM: Nope.
Wellby: Is that the gold Drankorian coins?
DM: There's, there's a f- few hundred Drankorian gold coins.
Unknown: Shove them in the hole. Shove them in the hole.
DM: And about 1,000 Drankorian silver coins.
Unknown: Stick them.
Delwath: Yeah. Choose the hole.
DM: There's bits of metal, other bits of metal lying around.
DM: Like, you know, there was clearly once, like, metal bed posts.
DM: Oh, and there is, there's a, um, a pretty nice, like, silver water pitcher lying, fallen on the ground in the study.
Wellby: What is the adamantium dagger situation?
DM: None.
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: There's no adamantium in the tower.
DM: You already know there's no adamantium in the tower 'cause Seeker would've sensed it.
Kenzo: I think Seeker wants that silver water pitcher, you know, like, for your bedside.
Kenzo: You know what I mean? So you've always got Apollyon, like, a little bit near you.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Just kind of-
Delwath: I don't know if this was Apollyon's bedroom necessarily.
Kenzo: But just, you know, it's like a-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... you know.
Unknown: Yeah. Let's go to the study.
Wellby: We take the pitcher.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Check it all in the mirror.
DM: Should be writing all this down. I'm used to being able to look at the transcript.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Wellby: Hmm.
Kenzo: I guess you could transcript that as a
DM: Yeah, I could.
Unknown: I wouldn't know
DM: Adamantine scraps, silver water pitcher
Seeker: Dracorian coins. I put the scraps on my personal inventory.
DM: Oh, nice.
DM: And, like, um, two magical books.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Sitting, soaking up in the...
DM: Okay, got it.
Kenzo: Soaking up? What does that mean, soaking up?
DM: Nothing. I didn't say anything.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Ah, yeah
Unknown: ... go out into a hallway.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: When we... So but, so but, so wait, when, when we open the hole to put in the coins, the books are not, like,
Wellby: eating the other stuff.
DM: They're still there.
Wellby: They're just sitting there being books, right?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs] They're, they're not soaking anything.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: What do you have in the mir- in the, in the hole again?
DM: You have both mirrors.
Wellby: Mostly just adventure gear, but both mirrors.
Delwath: A bunch of adventure gear, both mirrors.
DM: And some random treasure.
Delwath: And a bunch of our treasure.
DM: But not all your treasure, just the a- appropriate treasure to bribe-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... the dragon with if you need it.
DM: And that's about it?
Wellby: Yeah, and there's, like, shelves built up on all sides.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: And some, like, fluids supplies.
Wellby: Lava
Kenzo: ... adventuring gear. But nothing, nothing worth soaking.
DM: But no other magic items?
DM: Do you, like, regularly carry around the magic items you don't use?
Kenzo: No. Is it gonna fuck with the mirror and make it so we can never use the mirror again?
DM: I'm just curious.
Wellby: If it... Because, hmm, because if the mirror of soul trapping breaks inside of the bag of holding, that would be catastrophically bad.
Delwath: W- would it?
Wellby: Right?
Kenzo: 'Cause dimension stuff inside the bag exists.
Delwath: It would explode.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, that's true. And it's around your neck.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Oh, he's adding plots now.
Delwath: I, do we...
Wellby: I don't think we have other magic items in there.
Wellby: The folding boat would be, but it's not right now.
Delwath: Like, we don't... Yeah, do we have...
Delwath: We don't have a big set of magic items we don't use, do we?
DM: Hmm.
Unknown: 'Cause it... Let's see.
Unknown: But why is it soaking, soaking things?
DM: I mean, you've got, like, the Manual of Golems.
Delwath: Oh, the Manual of Golems.
DM: You've got the Ifrit bottle.
Unknown: The mirror of soul trapping.
DM: You've got-
Unknown: The Ifrit bottle
DM: ... the-
Delwath: Oh, we never did anything with the Longsword of Heroism
DM: ... Longsword of Heroism. You've got the augury mirrors.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right? You've still got another random locked spell book that you've never done anything with.
DM: You've got the Watcher's Dagger that lets you...
DM: Now, some of these you could just carry on your persons.
Wellby: I think the Ifrit bottle we carry on a person.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That's not that big.
Unknown: They-
DM: But what about the Manual of Golems?
DM: Can you leave that behind?
Seeker: But why does, why does this matter?
Unknown: Why are the things in question? I think we left...
Delwath: I don't think we would bring... The Manual of Golems is, like- Oh, yeah ...
Unknown: that's, like, for Vondrad. We would, we would bring that with us.
Kenzo: It's stuck here. Yeah, that, that would be, that would be on the ship.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: That'd be on the ship. Yeah.
DM: So it's basically just all the mirrors.
Delwath: Yeah, we keep the mirrors with us.
Delwath: I mean, that was the thing. Yeah.
Unknown: The mirrors of augury. Fuck, man. Are we gonna lose the mirrors now 'cause of these two stupid books?
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: No.
Wellby: All right, we're good. Searching this whole level also very carefully for hidden-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... rooms and morasses and all that sort of...
DM: Yeah, no, it's pretty much, like, living quarters, but, like, everything's been sitting exposed to the sea air for...
DM: So even metal is rusted.
Unknown: Right.
DM: I mean, any plain metal is sort of...
DM: Gold and silver maybe survive.
DM: The, that's about it. I mean, the silver water pitcher is heavily tarnished.
DM: The coins are all quite tarnished.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Why are the windows all open?
Wellby: Like, was it built with open windows?
DM: I, I mean, probably. It was built with magic windows.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: Hmm. All right. What's, is-
Kenzo: Why, why, why isn't the dragon gonna do this place?
Unknown: Scared of it.
Wellby: But why?
Delwath: Because of the two bo- two, two- Nah, 'cause of the scarier thing we haven't met yet.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Yeah.
Wellby: Okay, next level.
Delwath: Anything in the servant's quarters?
DM: No.
DM: Uh, the next level is very similar to this one.
DM: Uh, it looks like just more living space and private quarters, and the next one down after that as well.
DM: I mean, this is, like, three floors of just the heart of the living space of the tower.
DM: Uh, you know, another, like, 200 gold coins and, and 2,000 silver coins.
Unknown: Pocket 'em.
DM: Um, uh, a couple more, like a,
DM: a gold
DM: platter that you might, like, serve on.
DM: Um, and,
DM: uh,
DM: a- three, like, sort of n- relatively
DM: unadorned but nicely made gold rings.
Unknown: Take 'em all.
Kenzo: Hey, um, this is just thinking about things we can trade with the dragon, um, but also, like, maybe it'll, like, be really horrifying later.
Kenzo: Um, what if we gave or traded the dragon, um, the how to turn into yourself into a lick book, and then if you turn into a dragon lick, what does that mean?
Unknown: Are there dra-
DM: Then you would all die
Kenzo: ... are there dragon licks?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Really?
DM: I mean-
Kenzo: Theoretically, it's possible
DM: ... theoretically, it's possible.
Delwath: That would be crazy. That'd be a good 20th level, uh-
Unknown: We're gonna kill the dragon, though, right?
Kenzo: We're gonna kill the dragon, yeah.
Wellby: We're gonna kill the dragon.
Unknown: But, but if, but wouldn't a dragon lick be pretty cool?
DM: Are we gonna kill the dragon?
Delwath: We're gonna kill the dragon.
Delwath: I guess we gotta do something tomorrow night, right?
Unknown: [laughs] Make friends with the dragon.
Seeker: We're gonna try and make friends.
DM: There was lots you could still do.
Wellby: All right, next, next floor.
DM: You can always teleport to Charday.
DM: Man, how long have this ends?
Delwath: Dragon lick. Oh, man. We go kill Fausto.
Seeker: Dragon lick. That'd be fun.
Delwath: Dragon lick. No, I'm actually not totally against your idea of trading the, the- But, but, but, yeah.
Unknown: I mean, he might be into that, or she might be into that.
Unknown: She might be into that, right? Yeah.
Kenzo: It's like, actually, to convince her if she wants to kill Apollyon- She should become a lick ...
Unknown: she should become a lick.
Delwath: To kill him. It's kind of a bad thing to, like, let her do, though, right?
Delwath: She's gonna, like, kill all the dragonettes, like every single one of them.
Unknown: She's gonna, like, suck their souls.
Kenzo: Oh, she's gonna ravage Taular completely as a dragon lick.
Kenzo: Like, that would be like- Oh, my God ... it'd be so dumb.
Unknown: [laughs] But in the sh- in the long term, dumb.
Unknown: Short term [laughs] Short term, short term, helpful.
Kenzo: Right. Okay. It's like the Panom- Panomarian scroll thing, you know?
Unknown: Hurts us later, but eh
Unknown: Onward.
DM: Uh,
DM: going through the living quarters, you come down finally to the ground floor.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um.
Delwath: Wait, can you do that sense underground things every, all the time?
Seeker: Uh, um, Brennan, I can, I have more tremor sense.
DM: You can do tremor sense all the time, or proficiency, but how many?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Is it unlimited?
Unknown: I think it's proficiency.
Seeker: No, I have five.
DM: Right.
Seeker: I've used two.
DM: So you could do that again.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: Is that what lets you sense underground?
Delwath: No, what was the thing you did that let you sense-
DM: That was stone sense.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: Stone sense, I have-
Unknown: And you have two more of those
Seeker: ... I have two more of those also, yeah.
Delwath: We should do that.
Seeker: I missed it. Where are we now?
Unknown: On the ground floor.
DM: You're now on the ground floor, which I'm about to describe what you come down into.
Seeker: Okay.
DM: Um, so you, you come down-
Kenzo: Plastic ball pit
DM: ... hmm?
DM: Plastic ball pit.
DM: Nope. Um, you come in [laughs]
Seeker: Pauline ships.
Seeker: Incorrect.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Nope. Um-
Wellby: Close, cl- partially correct.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: You, you come down,
DM: um, into-
Unknown: Skull ball pit
DM: ... what looks like a grand entrance foyer.
DM: So the ceilings on this bottom floor are, like, 20 feet tall, and the stairs come down, um, right on the side, like, almost right next to where the two big doors that
DM: clearly open to the outside, um, are.
DM: And there's this, like, high sort of arched, almost like there's, like, pillars that come down forming, like, a column that leads in this sort of grand entrance space
DM: to another set of double doors on the far side.
DM: This, this corridor is probably, like, 20, 15 feet long, so not quite half the diameter of the tower.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: And there's a... So there's the stairs come down on one side.
DM: You've got this, like, row of these columns, but they're not, it's not empty space, right?
DM: There's, like, walls along them.
DM: There's columns along the side, and there's a door.
DM: There's a small door on the other side directly across from where stairs come, and then large doors right in front of you.
DM: Or not right in front of you, but at the end of this corridor.
Delwath: But are the large doors...
DM: Closed.
Delwath: But are they the outside doors?
DM: Oh, there's outside doors and then
DM: inside doors on either side of this corridor.
Delwath: Okay, so like we're in a... Okay.
Delwath: There's, like, big doors.
Delwath: So the only way out of the corridor is...
DM: There's three exits from the cor-
Unknown: The big-
DM: Four exits from the corridor. There's stairs up.
Unknown: Yeah, which we're coming down, yeah.
DM: There's a small, there's a small door across from the stairs up.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: There's big doors to the outside, or there's big doors to the inside.
Unknown: And the corridor's, I mean, it's not a corridor.
DM: It's not just a corridor where we-
DM: Yeah, it's like an entry foyer
DM: ... an entryway.
DM: Okay.
DM: There's, like, carved arches along the side.
DM: Like, um, this is all this sort of light gray stone as opposed to the darkness, the black of the actual tower itself.
Seeker: Let's go check out the little door.
Seeker: Like the-
Kenzo: Is there anything underground, though, below us?
Seeker: Oh, yeah, that's what, let's do that first. Tunnels?
Seeker: So I could, I could use the, um,
Seeker: stone sense
Seeker: to check for tunnels.
DM: Yep.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Um, there is,
DM: there is a, a extensive basement.
Unknown: Fuck.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: But no, um...
Seeker: That's two out of three of those.
Seeker: No stairs down to it.
DM: Well, not that you can see-
Seeker: On this side
DM: ... right here, but possibly through a doorway.
Delwath: Right. Let's check out the little door.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Um, there are stairs down, and what looks like a small sort of
DM: guard room that could, like, watch out.
DM: There's, like, a ar- a lookout so that you can look out to the, you can see out.
DM: There's, like, peepholes so you can see out to the outside, and then there's stairs down.
Seeker: The outside of the tower or the basement?
DM: Of the tower, so you could see anybody who's approaching the door from here.
Seeker: Okay.
Seeker: And we're looking inland.
DM: You're looking inland, yeah. You're looking across this broken, jagged terrain.
Seeker: I think we just go straight down.
Delwath: Yeah, but Wellby doesn't like leaving with the-
Wellby: Oh, yeah. I'll stay behind us.
Wellby: Let's, let's go through the interior doors, see what's there.
Seeker: The big interior doors, okay.
DM: Okay.
DM: All right.
DM: Um,
DM: you open the doors.
DM: there is, uh, this looks like a grand,
DM: uh, audience chamber.
DM: Um, there's a throne,
DM: uh, with, that's decorated with gems.
DM: Um, there's a set of, uh, like, s- there's a stone table in the middle that's, and then, like, seats
DM: that kind of are, uh...
DM: Uh, sorry, I guess it's not really a stone table.
DM: It's, like, stone seats that are sitting, like, so that an audience, so that you could talk to the person on the throne.
DM: And there's probably about
DM: 40 skeletons kind of sitting all, like, dead.
DM: Like, some, there's one sitting on the throne.
DM: There's about 20 or so that are sitting in the pews.
DM: Um, one's head turns.
Seeker: Oh.
DM: Another one starts to stand up.
Wellby: I use the door that closes again.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Uh, what was that all about?
DM: You hear movement.
Wellby: Can we lock the doors real quick?
Wellby: Can the ladder wrap itself through the handles and, like, hold the doors closed?
Seeker: Uh, the, the ladder has gone back to sleep, I think.
Seeker: Oh, no, actually, it's been an hour.
Unknown: It hasn't been an hour.
DM: It hasn't been an hour.
Wellby: Wait, wait, wait. What's the door situation?
Wellby: How are the, how do the handles work?
Wellby: Because can we put the immovable rod in front of the door to prevent the door from opening?
DM: [laughs] Yes, you could. The handles, there's two big handles, and they pull out like this.
Wellby: Uh-huh, that is exactly what we'll do then.
Seeker: Okay.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Just click that-
DM: The door will not open-
Seeker: ... immovable rod
DM: ... until somebody clicks the immovable rod.
Wellby: For the record, it's really good that we didn't come back up to these guys.
Seeker: That's true.
Wellby: The plan worked to check-
Seeker: Yeah
Wellby: ... for skeleton.
Wellby: Always check for skeletons.
Wellby: But-
Seeker: It's a good, good advice
Wellby: ... what I learned as a child
Seeker: And, and so what you're saying is now that we've, now that we know there's skeletons there, we can go in the basement?
Wellby: Yes, because the threat has been neutralized.
Unknown: Oh, wait, wait.
Seeker: I see.
Kenzo: We're, we're still gonna come back and kill the skeletons and get the, uh-
Wellby: We'll just grab the rod and go real quick.
Seeker: The throne-
Delwath: No, no, the gems on the throne.
Unknown: I think Kenza wants the gems.
Seeker: The throne would be a nice bargaining chip
Unknown: ... throne like a, like a cool, you know...
Kenzo: Is, was there anything magic in that room?
Seeker: We... Oh, yeah. Was there anything magic?
Unknown: Uh, nope.
Seeker: Imagine offering-
DM: But the throne looked pretty valuable, although there was a reason why I was asking you how much stuff you had in the portable hole.
Kenzo: Ah, how much would fit in there if we wanted to, like, stuff it.
Wellby: Could we fit a throne in there?
Seeker: I mean, imagine offering a dragon the throne of Apollyon.
Kenzo: Pretty fucking sweet.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Ah, actually, that would be a pretty good trick.
Wellby: Can you Sickening Radiance and just kill all of them while we wait?
Seeker: We don't even have to go inside or see it happening.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: [laughs] Um, we could.
Kenzo: Sickening Radiance work on skeletons?
Delwath: It's radiant damage.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: It should do extra damage to them.
Unknown: Hell yeah, do that.
Seeker: And, and does it work through the door?
Delwath: I would have to open the door briefly to cast it.
Seeker: You could go outside. There's windows probably.
Kenzo: Can't you just peek it?
Unknown: Yeah. You just like peek it and then...
Delwath: [laughs] We have to, I mean, do that now or later?
Wellby: Can you use your see through walls sense to target-
Delwath: I need to short rest to use it again
Wellby: ...
Wellby: yeah.
Seeker: I could Clairvoyance to see if it was working.
Unknown: But that won't, I can't...
Delwath: You can't cast spells without-
Seeker: Yeah
Delwath: ... line of effect anyway.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Like, you can't cast spells through total cover.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, are there windows?
Seeker: From the outside?
Unknown: Uh, you...
DM: Well, let's see. Wellby, roll a, roll a D20.
DM: Wellby's pretty observant.
Wellby: 16.
Unknown: Um,
DM: there were two windows, two big windows in the audience chamber.
Seeker: So we just step outside.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Walk around to the other side.
Seeker: Sickening Radiance through the window.
Delwath: I mean, how big was the room?
DM: It's like, uh...
Unknown: So the,
Unknown: the
DM: tower is 50 foot diameter.
DM: The corridor is 20 feet, so the room is 30 feet from wall to wall.
Seeker: Yeah, Sickening Radiance would cover that.
DM: Well, that's 50 feet on the wide end and 30 feet on the short end.
Unknown: Ah, Sickening Radiance would not cover all of that.
Delwath: So the problem with Sickening Radiance is they would just...
Unknown: They could, um-
Seeker: Just run away
Wellby: Put it on the side closest to the door.
Wellby: We can open the door and pick them off with ranged attacks.
Delwath: It's a 30-foot, 30-foot, no, 30-foot radius.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. That would cover the whole room.
Unknown: Yeah, let's do that.
Unknown: Let's do that.
Wellby: I think you should not go out through the front doors, though.
Unknown: I-
Wellby: I have like a bad feeling about opening the front doors.
Delwath: Yeah, I do too. I...
Delwath: Shouldn't we, like,
Delwath: go see what's down there and then do this?
Kenzo: But also, like, is there any possibility now that the skeletons have wakened and they are seeing us, that they're gonna like, you know-
Unknown: Communicate?
Seeker: Any more sounds happening back there?
DM: Oh, yeah. There's like banging on a door.
Kenzo: I mean, I think, right, it's, you know, spill...
Kenzo: I mean, I, I like the immovable rod.
Kenzo: It's great. I like it. I trust it.
Kenzo: Um, but also, like, is it-
Seeker: They could go out the windows. They could go down the stairs.
Kenzo: Yeah, are they, are they, like, alerting other thing...
Unknown: Enemies
Seeker: They could go up and around.
DM: I mean, there's no reason you have to go out the front door.
DM: Seeker can still turn you into a bird.
Delwath: True. Oh, yeah, that's true.
Wellby: Fly out.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. All right.
Wellby: Perfect.
Delwath: I mean, I just... It's a sp- spell slot I won't get back, but that's okay.
Delwath: Till we short rest.
Seeker: Uh, it's worth it.
Kenzo: I'd like to neutralize this, uh, threat now.
Seeker: Room full of skeletons.
Delwath: All right. But you, can you magic me back into a bird when I'm outside?
Unknown: I don't think so.
DM: Well, what is... Why not?
Seeker: Uh, I thought...
Seeker: I can...
Seeker: Uh, is that line of sight?
Seeker: Let's see.
DM: Well, you might have to go with them.
Kenzo: Just walk a little better now.
Seeker: Right.
Unknown: The room full of skeletons.
Seeker: It's just things that you can see.
Kenzo: Yeah, I'm feeling a little better.
Delwath: Right, you have to come with me.
Wellby: I feel good about the rod.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: I feel good about the rod.
Seeker: Uh, okay, let's go.
Unknown: But also, you know-
Wellby: I feel, I feel better about now.
Seeker: I'll, I'll be a diver.
Unknown: I feel good about it. I feel better about it.
Seeker: You can be an Oscar.
Unknown: Sure.
Seeker: Okay.
Unknown: And, you know, it's just like we cast a spell, like, let's like, um, move on.
Seeker: You can choose.
Delwath: Osprey's fine.
Seeker: Okay.
DM: Yeah, you have to be with us.
Wellby: Put this thing on the to-do list.
Unknown: That's what I'm saying, you know?
Wellby: If you-
Kenzo: And one thing I've been learning is y- you knock things out right away.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
Delwath: These guys are chatting [laughs]
Seeker: Don't put it on, don't put it on the to-do list.
Seeker: We turn into birds.
Wellby: No.
Unknown: 'Cause then it, it, it...
Unknown: Just do it right then.
DM: So you have to, you have to bro- unshift-
Unknown: 'Cause if you put it on the to-do list, what happens later? Other things happen.
Unknown: You get distracted
DM: ... back 'cause you can't shift him back as a bird.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I see.
Unknown: He'll notice.
Seeker: Okay. Okay. I got it.
Seeker: I got it.
DM: Okay. Delwath cast the spell.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Now's your time.
Seeker: No, no, no.
Seeker: Now's your time for what?
Unknown: Friendship [laughs]
Seeker: No.
Wellby: Friendship, right?
Seeker: No. No.
Seeker: Seeker gets a very confused look on his face-
Seeker: No
Seeker: ... and, and, uh, picks up a stone off the ground and, and looks sort of anguished over at Delwath, and it just shoots directly into your torso
Seeker: using the catapult spell.
Seeker: Um...
Wellby: Oh, shit.
Delwath: I knew something like that was gonna happen.
Kenzo: Uh, better here. Better here than the-
Unknown: You don't have to use your highest level spell on your first
Unknown: ... the giant big boss.
Unknown: It's like a fourth level or something.
Seeker: Right? Fourth level-
Wellby: Or dragon or something, yeah
Seeker: ... catapult spell.
DM: And as this happens, like, this black shadow s- flies out of Seeker's face.
Seeker: And there's-
DM: And then he like, yeah, like blinks his eyes open.
DM: Make your... What is it a save?
Seeker: Dex.
Unknown: Make a dex save.
Seeker: 18 DC.
Delwath: Can you bardic inspiration me?
Unknown: No.
Seeker: [laughs] Not right now.
Seeker: Ooh, so that's 68
Seeker: damage.
Unknown: 68 damage?
Delwath: Is this before I cast the spell or after?
Unknown: Before.
Seeker: Okay.
Wellby: There's 5D8. Nope, here's 6D8.
Kenzo: What's, what's all the D8s for?
Seeker: The damage.
DM: The catapult that Seeker did to Delwath.
Unknown: Oh, 68.
Kenzo: Oh, oh, oh. I thought you, you did 68 damage.
DM: No, no, that would be a lot.
Seeker: 6 D8 damage. It's gonna be 20 something.
Unknown: Go ahead and roll.
Seeker: Oh, it's... I'm like [laughs]
DM: You cast a spell
Seeker: ... I don't feel responsible for this, but I am.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: You're not entirely responsible for it.
DM: Um-
Unknown: I mean, you had to lick the book, man
DM: ... that's-
Unknown: You had to lick the book
Seeker: ... eight, 16, 20, uh-
Unknown: 26
DM: ... 26. 26.
Wellby: That's not terrible.
Seeker: You had to lick the book.
Unknown: Seeker.
Seeker: [laughs] Ah.
Delwath: What did you do?
DM: You have no memory of doing this.
Kenzo: So do we have to kill Seeker now?
Delwath: Uh, do I have any way of communicating
Unknown: with these people?
Seeker: I... We're outside.
Unknown: We're outside.
Unknown: Oh, so we can see this.
DM: Well, you've had plenty of time to reestablish telepathy.
Delwath: Oh, that's true.
Delwath: I will shout through the telepathy that Seeker is somehow possessed.
Wellby: Again?
Seeker: It's g- it's gone.
Seeker: It's... That was it.
Unknown: I, uh,
Seeker: I think it, it, it came into me through that book, and then I, I just had to release it, and I did.
Seeker: I think I did. Did it come out?
Unknown: Did something happen just now?
Delwath: Something came out.
Unknown: What, what happened?
Delwath: You, you tried to kill me.
Seeker: Well, I think I, it's-
Unknown: Beyond normal
Seeker: ... it seems clear that I did not succeed.
Unknown: Would you agree?
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: I'm sure you lick a bleeding wound in the side.
Delwath: Well, sort of.
Seeker: Oh, no. How did that happen?
Delwath: You threw a rock. [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Really hard with magic.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I threw...
Seeker: That's- that's terrible.
Unknown: I really-
Unknown: It is [laughs]
Seeker: ... I had no intention of throwing a rock at you, Delwath.
Seeker: I'll tell you that. I could cast a healing...
Seeker: Do you know the healing spell?
Delwath: I, I wouldn't mind.
Seeker: Okay, I'll cast a healing spell on you.
Unknown: Um.
DM: Ah, meanwhile, you hear the sounds of skeletons falling dead.
Kenzo: Oh, you were... You cast Healing Rain.
DM: After you got hit, I assume-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you still cast the spell.
Delwath: Yeah, I still cast it.
Delwath: Lasts for 10 minutes, I assume they just all die.
DM: Yeah, yeah, they all die.
Kenzo: Okay. Um, when we s- I see you again, um, Kenzo will do a cleansing-
Unknown: Mm
Kenzo: ... uh, touch anyways just for, for good measure.
DM: Okay. Um-
Unknown: Did I sense anything to cleanse?
Wellby: Did you ever get sold something?
DM: Uh, you didn't roll high enough on your insight last time.
Kenzo: Let me... Can I do that again then?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: I assume you have a double, double check.
Unknown: It's a d4, so.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, that's fair.
Kenzo: Ah, 14.
DM: Nope.
DM: But you can still cleanse. I mean, you can still try it.
Kenzo: I will, I will cleanse no matter what.
DM: Um.
Seeker: So I heal you 24.
Delwath: So... Oh, well, that's pretty good.
DM: As-
Seeker: It's almost equivalent.
Delwath: That's almost the same.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: As part-
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: As part of-
Unknown: Thank you. [laughs]
Unknown: As part of doing the cleansing touch-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... even though you didn't roll very high on your roll, you can sense, like, that there's nothing still there.
Seeker: Restorative justice.
Unknown: Okay, yeah.
DM: It's a one shot deal.
Kenzo: Okay, good. [laughs] Uh, you're clear.
Unknown: But Seeker-
Seeker: Clear of what?
Unknown: ...
Unknown: being possessed by the spirit of a lich.
Seeker: I, uh, seems like that something like that might have happened, yes.
Delwath: Yeah, and, and Kenzo's fixed you.
Seeker: It's 'cause I didn't look carefully enough at the book.
Unknown: I know.
Unknown: It, it-
Seeker: So next time I'll have to be more attentive.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: sorry about that, guys.
Kenzo: So you're gonna, you're gonna in the future do what?
Wellby: The next time we run into a book-
Seeker: I'll pay more attention
Wellby: ... bound in bloody human skin [laughs]
Delwath: You're going to pay attention.
Unknown: What will be the quiz?
Delwath: There's a right and a wrong answer.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: I mean, I mean, we, we all came through okay.
Unknown: But wait, but wait, you didn't hear the...
Kenzo: You will and the next time this happens, and there's some human bound demonic item-
DM: But wait, we learned all sorts of useful stuff you wouldn't have known if you hadn't looked at it.
Kenzo: What did we learn? That he-
DM: That it was a book that i- you use to become a lich.
Unknown: Oh, true, yeah.
Delwath: Well, we kind of learned that.
Wellby: I feel like that was pretty obvious.
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs] I don't think so. I don't think it was obvious at all actually.
Seeker: Ah, I was, phew, that shadow was in me for a minute.
Seeker: I'm, I'm relieved.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: To have gotten it out.
Unknown: We all are.
Seeker: It looks like it came out kind of forcefully, so that was unfortunate.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: But Delwath is okay now.
Unknown: Yeah, no.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: So am, so am I.
Wellby: Yeah, I think that's good.
Unknown: [laughs] We're all okay.
Kenzo: [laughs] All, all of us are fi- all of us are good.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Woo, so let's-
Wellby: If you want to open the doors to the throne room.
Kenzo: Yeah. Now, now, yeah.
DM: Uh, there's a bunch of disintegrated skeleton bodies on the ground.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: And a giant throne.
Wellby: How big is the largest dimension of the throne?
Seeker: Nice.
DM: Hold on.
DM: I don't know.
Kenzo: We can definitely fit it in the portal hole.
Seeker: I was thinking about what it'd be like to sit on it, but I'm not gonna do that.
Wellby: [laughs] It's not magical, right?
Unknown: 'Cause I-
Delwath: There's no magic in this room, right?
Unknown: I no longer-
Wellby: Why don't you just put your face really close to it?
Seeker: I no longer have the shadow-
Unknown: Just lick the gems
Seeker: ... of Apollyon inside me, so.
Unknown: You can just lick it.
DM: Kenzo checked.
DM: Um.
Unknown: No, no more.
Wellby: Didn't you check before and not see it?
Unknown: No, no, no, 'cause I did a cleansing touch.
DM: You didn't use the cleansing touch before.
Unknown: I, I actually did a cleansing touch.
DM: Which maybe you should have.
Delwath: Well, no, you told us we couldn't 'cause we had no in-game reason to do it.
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. 'Cause he failed it.
Delwath: Which is fair.
Delwath: He failed it. He didn't roll high enough on the insight check to realize.
Unknown: He failed the insight check. Yeah.
Kenzo: All of this is fair. So now I would do it, you know-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... post.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Just to make sure it's all clear.
Delwath: But after trying to kill me, of course.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. I mean, that's a pretty normal reaction, but this was, it felt a little bit intense.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: so the throne, throne's probably about seven feet high and about four feet wide and three feet deep.
Wellby: It totally will fit in the hole.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: 100%.
Unknown: It will fit.
Delwath: We just take everything out, push the throne in, and then pile the mirrors on top of the throne.
DM: So that's 84 cubic feet, so the-
Wellby: Is it something like 10 feet deep by 10 feet in diameter?
DM: Yeah, so I calculated... Hold on.
DM: I calculated this out 'cause I thought this might come up.
Seeker: So the packing problem.
DM: Um, this is great.
Unknown: We might have... And if the dragon doesn't-
Unknown: We'll have to tetris it
Kenzo: ... if the dragon doesn't want it, we, uh, we bring it back to the sky ship and, um,
Unknown: you know-
Unknown: [laughs] It turns it in
Delwath: ... put it, put it in the gaming room. [laughs]
Unknown: Of course.
Seeker: It's, it's wood and gems or, or stone or metal?
Seeker: What's the, what's the main material?
DM: Um.
Kenzo: What are we putting in the ship?
DM: So it's, it's stone.
DM: It's super heavy, like-
Wellby: It's like the Baldur's chair
Delwath: ... wait, the, the, the portal hole's 10 foot radius
Delwath: and 10 foot deep?
DM: Um. [laughs]
Seeker: Doing some math.
DM: The portal hole-
Delwath: Or five foot radius and 10 foot deep
DM: ... is...
Wellby: Well, I don't know. Let's check what the portal hole is.
Wellby: It's a 10 by 10 cylinder I think.
Delwath: 10 by 10 cyl- but 10 radius or 10 diameter?
Wellby: Thing diameter I think
DM: Just check what it says. It should say.
DM: Look up the magic item.
DM: I thought I calculated this out, but I don't think I did.
DM: For some reason I have the memory of like 280 cubic feet
Unknown: What did we put in the skyship?
Delwath: 785 is the volume.
DM: No, it's a 10, it-
Unknown: Five foot ring
DM: ... six foot in diameter.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: It's a six foot diameter, 10 foot deep hole.
Unknown: It's 285.
Delwath: You have an addition chart?
DM: So 285 cubic feet.
DM: I figure if the mirrors are accessible,
DM: like the mirrors, both mirrors are, they're...
DM: Oh,
DM: the Mirror of Souls, I think I calculated it.
DM: I, I, I, I meant to calculate this all out in advance 'cause I knew this would come up, because obviously you're gonna take a throne.
Seeker: [laughs] Yeah.
DM: That was the most predictable thing that happened.
Delwath: But wait, wait. It was seven by four by...
DM: Three.
Kenzo: I mean, it's not just any throne, it's the throne of Apollyon.
Delwath: I mean, that's only 84 on its own.
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, um
Delwath: And it's not a fully filled in square.
Unknown: After we raise the charter.
DM: Exactly.
Unknown: I think we put place this.
DM: Oh, you definitely have the space.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: But I don't remember if the mirrors-
Kenzo: Did I say that out loud?
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Inside the, the, inside thoughts [laughs]
DM: The Mirror of Soul Trapping is only four feet in this dimension, so it can fit on top.
DM: No, I guess they could, they could still make it possible because the-
Unknown: They could probably both just sit on the seat
DM: ... because the throne is not six feet wide.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: They could both sit on the seat.
Seeker: So we have to take everything out and put it back in.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. After the operation.
DM: Yeah, it's a little weird, but it does fit.
Wellby: How do we lower the, how do we get several thousand pounds of throne in there?
Delwath: Can we just open the portable hole underneath it?
Seeker: And drop it in.
Wellby: No, 'cause we have to spread out a physical object.
Seeker: Yeah, we have to tip it in.
Wellby: Just levitate.
Unknown: I didn't take levitate.
Seeker: I have telekinesis.
Unknown: There you go.
Seeker: That, that I could, I mean, it would burn a spell slot to do it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But I could definitely move the throne with that.
Unknown: I mean, should've taken levitate, but I didn't.
Seeker: Is that the only way for, uh...
Unknown: It would be perfect to have
DM: I mean, go look at like beasts of CR4 or less that have huge strengths.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Seeker: 'Cause we can change into those at will.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: Let's just change into really big, big, uh, strong-
Delwath: Oh, that's a good idea. Wait, hold on
Seeker: ... strong, uh, chair pushing- And like between us, if, if we're like grizzly bears.
DM: Oh, oh. I'll have to look it up. I'm sure there is a beast.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, we could just be elephants.
DM: You can just be some big-
Unknown: Four elephants.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Push the throne into the hole.
Kenzo: This, this is another cool image that should, somebody should do a journey of.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I think elephants are probably a little bit too, like-
Unknown: They wouldn't even
DM: ... I don't think four elephants aren't gonna fit in this room.
DM: Maybe they would. It'd be a tight squeeze.
Seeker: I was thinking grizzly bears.
DM: But yeah, like four grizzly bears could easily carry a 1,000 pound stone throne.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: I think it's a lot more than 1,000 pounds.
DM: How much do you think it is?
Unknown: Okay, let's, let's, we got the throne in the door.
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: We got the throne in there. Let's move on.
Unknown: Let's move on.
Unknown: Ask Bullfroak.
Delwath: We'll ask Bullfroak about it.
DM: It's very heavy. Um, but it's not entirely stone.
DM: There's also a fair bit of-
Kenzo: You can ask ChatGPT, what four animals, uh...
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: Well, no, for, for quantitative statistics.
Delwath: No, why wouldn't, why wouldn't a couple of elephants be able to fit?
DM: Yeah, elephants would fit.
Delwath: Elephants are CR4.
Wellby: [laughs] I love that the s-
Delwath: Strength 22
Wellby: ... granite is 150 pounds per cubic foot.
DM: Yeah, that's not bad.
Wellby: What are the dimensions of the throne?
Seeker: Seven by four by three, but it's not like a solid block.
DM: Yeah, say it's like 30 cubic feet.
DM: It's 4,500 pounds.
DM: Four elephants can easily push that.
Wellby: Yeah. Yes. I'm not gonna...
Wellby: Why am I disagreeing with you? [laughs]
Unknown: You don't think?
Unknown: I mean, come on.
Wellby: Let's, let's, let's move on, guys.
DM: Four elephants pushing a throne into a portable hole.
Unknown: Let it happen.
Kenzo: Let's, let's, yeah, let it happen.
Unknown: Thank you.
Unknown: Perfect.
Unknown: Thank you. Why, why are we upset?
DM: Who cares if it actually works?
Kenzo: Let's move on. Let's move on. We got Apollyon's throne.
Unknown: Perfect.
Delwath: And we can have five elephants if we need.
DM: Every raise the charter-
DM: That's true. The ladder can be a fifth elephant to help out
DM: ... this is a perfect place to just put it.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: The fifth element is ladder.
Unknown: [laughs] The fifth elephant is ladder.
Wellby: [laughs] The elephant is ladder.
Unknown: The fifth elephant is ladder.
DM: So the stone goes thunk onto a bed of coins at the bottom of the portable hole.
Kenzo: That's a perfect Midjourney question, is like what does an elephant ladder look like?
DM: Yeah. And then you reload the ladders on top and close up the hole, which weighs nothing more than what it started as.
DM: Getting this out of the hole might be a different challenge.
Wellby: We'll need a sixth elephant.
Delwath: Or that's when we need an actual spell.
DM: That's, you could use telekinesis.
Seeker: Telekinesis.
Wellby: Telekinesis only lifts 1,000 pounds.
DM: Oh yeah, telekinesis probably can't lift it.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: But it's not solid granite all the way through.
DM: 1,000 is probably low, but.
Wellby: I think telekinesis can lift it.
DM: [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: Come on. Why, why are you like...
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: All right, basement?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
DM: So the stairs come down and open out into what seems like a sort of storage room and keep going down.
DM: There's one more level.
Wellby: Magic on this floor?
DM: No.
Wellby: Anything interesting on this floor?
DM: I mean, this is underground, so it's less damaged.
DM: Um, but
DM: there's like-
Seeker: It's not interesting.
DM: Yeah, there's, so there's like crates.
DM: I mean, the crates have fallen apart, but you can see there's, um, you know, silks that are molded through.
DM: There's, um...
DM: I mean, nothing here is really salvageable, but you can still see this was, this was prob- There's like barrels of wine that have turned to vinegar long, long ago, right?
DM: This was, uh, mostly like mundane just storage.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, nothing but like the kind of stuff that you'd expect to find, like, in a royal palace or something, right?
DM: Like, it's not magical.
DM: But let me check with-
DM: Anyway, yeah, so you wanna keep going down?
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Uh, that's not bad.
Wellby: What?
Seeker: It's sort of kind of weird and creepy.
Wellby: Huh.
Delwath: I mean, not bad in the sense of at least it's sort of interesting.
Unknown: Um,
DM: okay, so the, the stairs, so the stairs are running along the side of the, of, of the tower, but it's hard to...
DM: Like, who knows whether the tower is...
DM: The circular shape continues.
DM: They actually go down slightly, um, and then turn a sharp corner, and go down slightly more, and come to a solid metal door.
Wellby: No, I'm just tapping this now.
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs] That freaked me out for a minute.
Wellby: Sorry. [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Don't mind me. [laughs]
Wellby: Tap, tap, tap.
Seeker: Um- So there's a metal door at the bottom of the stairs.
Wellby: Trapped? Locked?
DM: Make an investigation check.
Wellby: Investigation.
DM: It is definitely locked.
Wellby: Uh, 20.
DM: It's not trapped.
Wellby: Magically trapped?
Delwath: Is there, uh-
Wellby: Is it magic?
Unknown: ... magic?
DM: Um, that's an interesting question.
Unknown: Um,
DM: there is magic, but nothing you see.
DM: Like, you can sense magic, but you can't see where it's coming from.
Wellby: Should we open the door?
Unknown: No. No. Z- z- get your...
Unknown: Should we, like, disarm it or do anything funky to it?
Wellby: Well, we gonna turn around and go home?
Wellby: Like, what, what are our choices here?
Delwath: Yeah, there's no choices. I mean, we could just dimension door to the other side of the door.
Wellby: We could try opening the door.
Kenzo: Can we go through the door and see what's on the other side?
Delwath: No, if we short rest.
Delwath: Why don't we short rest? I mean, we could short rest.
Wellby: Why don't we just pick the lock?
Kenzo: 'Cause it's gonna set off the magical trap and explode and we're all gonna die.
Wellby: Probably. Yeah, probably.
Unknown: Yeah, let's not.
Wellby: Probably.
Kenzo: Why don't we short rest and then you can, like, look on the other side.
Delwath: Like, is there a reason not to short rest?
Kenzo: Do you get spell slots back?
Kenzo: If we short rest I get them back.
Kenzo: What about, uh, clairvoyance?
Wellby: We get hit points back too.
Unknown: We get... We could get hit points back.
Delwath: Nah. I mean, if we're gonna short rest we should have played...
Delwath: Well, probably should have made him heal me from killing him with the catapult, but that's okay.
Seeker: Yeah, it doesn't matter. Yeah. It's fine.
Seeker: That was, that was more karmic.
Delwath: It was more karmic. That's true.
Unknown: It was more karmic.
Wellby: I'll go short resting.
Unknown: Let's short rest. Well, here's my only question.
Wellby: Yeah?
Delwath: Before we short rest, should we dimension door to the other side of this?
Wellby: Once we get on the other side of this door, like, shit's gonna go bad.
Kenzo: You think so? Yeah, I think there's gonna be, like, ugly, bad thing.
Kenzo: Like some crazy construct, big, giant golem.
Kenzo: Yeah, probably right. Yeah.
Kenzo: We're in the basement of Apollyon's Tower.
Kenzo: We still haven't found a place where he makes fucking crazy, weird, OP weapons.
Unknown: Yeah, well, what's scaring the dragon?
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. That's, that's what sounds like-
Wellby: What's scaring a dragon?
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs] Like, wasn't...
Kenzo: Like, the black acid dragon doesn't wanna come here.
Kenzo: Yeah. Like, there are a bunch of coins and fucking things that, like- Like a gem, like a throne ...
Kenzo: like the giant, yeah, and the gem throne.
Kenzo: Yeah. He didn't wanna come here.
Wellby: Nothing we've seen so far would scare an ancient dragon.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. Black acid dragon would be like...
Wellby: Why are we going towards it then?
Unknown: [laughs] 'Cause that's what we do.
Delwath: That's our shit. We have to prove our mettle before we fight the dragon.
Kenzo: It's like a warmup. [coughs] I mean, this is totally one of those things we could just stop right here, but we're not going to do that.
Wellby: Short resting now?
Kenzo: Let's short rest. All right.
Wellby: Sure.
Unknown: Sure. Sure, let's do it. Okay.
DM: Are you gonna short, like, right here outside the door?
Unknown: No, no, no, no, no, no. Let's-
Wellby: Back up in the throne room?
Kenzo: Let's go back into the throne room and, like- Yeah, where there's full of skeletons and stuff ...
Unknown: with the dead bodies and stuff.
Wellby: Skeleton powder.
Delwath: But it's powdered skeletons.
Unknown: [laughs] Not that one.
Wellby: Oh, did they just disintegrate up?
DM: Yeah. They kind of... That much radiant damage, I figure skeletons just kind of disintegrate.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: I mean, you can use the ashes for, like, you know, it's like a great facial cleanser.
Delwath: Can we, like, immovable rod the- For your skin ...
Unknown: the-
Wellby: No, 'cause the door's opening out
Delwath: ... it, it pulls this way. Yeah, then we fly into the windows and then immovable rod the door and then...
Wellby: But someone who comes up to the door from the outside [laughs]
Unknown: Can destroy it with a immovable rod.
Delwath: [laughs] Yes, of course.
Wellby: [laughs] All right, short rest.
DM: Let's short rest. Okay. Yeah, you can short rest.
Kenzo: Nice. So now we get hit dice or what's this how this works?
Unknown: You can roll hit dice. How does that work?
DM: Just D&D Beyond should handle it for you.
DM: Just, like, click short rest.
Delwath: The only downside to short rest is your thing will go away.
Unknown: Which? Ladder.
DM: Ladder? The ladder... But the ladder's...
Unknown: I think the ladder's pretty much gone anyway.
Unknown: It's probably pretty close.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: It's taking you about an hour to explore I guess.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah. But you've got third level slots, right?
Unknown: You can summon it again technically.
Seeker: Right. And the, um- So just click how many you wanna roll.
Seeker: You probably wanna roll, like, four or something. Animal shape stays active.
DM: 24 hours. 24 hours.
Seeker: What about the max HP modifiers?
Seeker: I still... Do I still have that? Yeah, you still have that.
Seeker: Yep. So I could short rest and boost all the way back up to that?
Unknown: Yep.
Wellby: Yep.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: That's so cool.
DM: Um... I think you gotta click there to roll.
Unknown: Sorry, I don't play that often.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: I don't know if it'll auto-ma-... Yeah, 33.
DM: Yeah. Oh, wow. That gets you pretty much.
Unknown: No, that's perfect. Great.
DM: Then click short rest and you go back.
Delwath: And Delwath is gonna cook a little...
Delwath: We're doing the short rest, we're gonna cook a little meal.
Delwath: Everybody gets heroic inspiration too.
Unknown: Hell yeah.
Kenzo: All right. Nice. Focus points back up.
Unknown: That's 10. Good as new.
Seeker: Six, seven.
Kenzo: Best thing we've done all day. Yep.
Kenzo: And now, and now we get the heroic things back again?
Delwath: Yeah. You... Delwath makes some nice biscuits and tea.
Kenzo: Fucking love these biscuits, man.
Kenzo: Heroic, heroic biscuits.
Delwath: Delicious. Everybody ready?
Unknown: Yep. Okay.
Delwath: Ghostly gaze through the door.
DM: So you go back down to the door, you ghostly gaze.
Delwath: I mean, that's what we should do, right?
Kenzo: Yeah. Um- We don't just dimension door through.
Unknown: We look. Yeah.
DM: Uh, there is,
DM: um... So you see-
Delwath: Also, can I see the magic now?
Delwath: Can I see if there's any, like, mechanisms inside?
Delwath: Like, can I see where the magic that I detected earlier is coming from?
Unknown: Uh, nope
DM: But you do see through the door and you can...
DM: So you're looking into what looks like a relatively
DM: bare room, except in the center there's a circular,
DM: um, it's not really a table, it's like a pedestal.
DM: It's like about, like maybe that big, a little big around, just a
DM: s- stone, um, this sort of dark...
DM: Well, it's mottled. It's like gray and black and there's some browns.
DM: It's like mottled stone shaped into this giant pedestal.
DM: Um, and there's runes that run around the side-
Kenzo: Divine Forge
DM: ... like 10 different languages
DM: that are all incantations about, um, enchantment.
Unknown: It's a forge, but-
DM: Around the sides there's four, um, large holes about this big that sort of bore into the side of the pedestal, evenly spaced around that each go about
DM: one third of the way in.
DM: Um, and there are concentric, silver concentric circles on the top that run just, like, about 10 concentric circles that get smaller and smaller.
DM: Um, and then running down, like coming out through those holes in the side, running down the side of the pedestal and then along the floor, there's silvery lines that trace,
DM: like, a net around the entire room that all converge onto a metal panel on the far wall.
DM: It's about a one foot by one foot metal square.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Um, there are two doors.
Unknown: What?
DM: One on the left, one on the right, and there is a black void
DM: that vaguely looks like a blade hovering on top of the sta- of the pedestal.
Unknown: Wow.
Delwath: And there's magic somewhere, but I can't see it.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: And it's not the blade?
Wellby: I mean, is it the whole room?
DM: Well, I mean, looking through, yeah.
DM: Like, the whole room is highly magical.
Kenzo: Was he in the middle of making, like, some kind of like black void sword?
Seeker: Oh, definitely.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Or the sword that attacks-
Unknown: I'm, I'm gonna,
Delwath: I'm gonna... Since See Invisible lasts for an hour, I'm gonna do that, too.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, let me check one thing.
DM: Um,
DM: that seems wise.
Kenzo: Divine Forge.
Seeker: 'Cause didn't Fausto have, like, invisible
Unknown: defenses?
Wellby: Servants?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Just seems worth being
DM: Um-
Seeker: You'd think Fausto would have sort of followed the lead of his boss.
DM: There are-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ...
DM: uh, hovering against the two sides of the walls, there are large, like, hands of force.
DM: Two of them
DM: just hovering.
Seeker: Are they invisible?
DM: Invisible.
Seeker: Good thing you saw invisible.
Delwath: Like, on the wall... Like, okay, like-
DM: Near where the doors are.
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
DM: But they're about five feet big hands.
Delwath: So there's, um, there's some big fists that will punch whoever comes through the door.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: Or goes to the door.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Tries to enter the door.
Delwath: Why wouldn't you Dimension Door to the far side of the room?
Wellby: Well, they punch us anywhere?
Delwath: Do they look like they could reach the far side of the room?
DM: I mean, they're just floating there.
DM: They're-
Delwath: So if they could move, they could move anywhere.
DM: If they can move, they can move anywhere.
Seeker: They can deathless move.
Kenzo: Can we, can we detel- Can we Dispel magic them and just get rid of them?
Unknown: Can you Dispel magic on them?
Seeker: I could try.
Kenzo: It feels like a worthwhile thing to do.
Seeker: There, it probably would take two attempts.
Unknown: But one-
Seeker: And then Dispel Magic is probably line of sight.
Seeker: Is that true?
Kenzo: But, you know, for the giant floating
Unknown: magical fists-
Unknown: Fists of doom
Kenzo: ... feels like that'd be worth trying to dispel them.
Seeker: It says with-
Delwath: There's nothing through the floo- Like the rest of the-
Unknown: This is it.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So it says-
Wellby: How far does ghostly gaze extend?
Wellby: Can you see through the next doors anywhere?
Delwath: Uh, it's only 30 feet.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Or is it 60 feet? I don't remember.
DM: If it's 30 feet you can't see to the other doors.
DM: If it's 60 you could. So check.
Unknown: 60 feet. 60, 30 feet.
DM: Fuck, you can't see past this room.
Delwath: So I mean, it lasts for a minute, so if I go through quickly I can still use it.
Seeker: Dispel says within range, so not line of sight.
Seeker: So I should be able to Dispel Magic
Seeker: on things I can't see?
DM: Yep, but you still need a, you still need a clear...
DM: They still can't be up behind total cover, so the door would have to be open, but you would be able to target something that's invisible.
DM: You don't have to be able to see it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I could open the door and duck.
Unknown: Huh?
Wellby: Right? If we have to open the door.
Seeker: Just for a second while I cast Dispel Magic on them.
Kenzo: What do you mean a duck?
Delwath: From the fists that are presumably gonna punch us.
Kenzo: But what about the, the fucking floating s-
Unknown: Is it a sword?
DM: It's like, it's like this just intense black void that has, like, kind of a shape of a sword shimmering in it, that's hovering above the forge.
Seeker: So it's the thing that was, uh-
Unknown: With the work in progress.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Apollyon was in the middle of. It would be nice to get through here quickly so that I can walk through the other two doors before ghostly gaze is gone.
DM: Whatever you wanna do, man.
Wellby: Do we have a plan B for the fists?
DM: Other than Dispel Magic.
Unknown: Take seven points of damage each.
Wellby: Seven zero?
Delwath: I don't know, that's my guess.
Unknown: Or more.
Seeker: And Dispel will probably only dispel one of them.
Wellby: Maybe each of them guard one door.
Wellby: Maybe there are three of them
Wellby: and we don't see the one that's on the other side of this door.
DM: No, 'cause Delwath has ghostly gaze.
Wellby: Oh.
Delwath: I can see the whole room. No, they look like they're two fists on either side of this door.
Unknown: No, no, no. The o- on the other doors.
Kenzo: Other two doors. It looks like they're guarding the two doors on the other side.
DM: The doors on the far. They're guarding these doors.
Unknown: Ah.
Kenzo: So opening this door will do something that we don't know.
Kenzo: Oh, oh, oh, I misunderstood then.
Kenzo: That's gonna, still gonna, like, hurt us.
Delwath: Oh, so they're, like, in front of the other two doors?
DM: They're in front of the other two doors.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: So they're more to, like, fuck with you trying to get in those two doors.
DM: The ones at the far end of the room.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: The room itself is about 30 feet from front to end with the pedestal in the middle.
Delwath: Now they're guarding the other doors.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Just open the door.
Wellby: I feel good about opening this door.
Kenzo: What the fuck? And we're just gonna spring the trap?
DM: We don't know there's a trap
Kenzo: Didn't you say there was a magic, the magic door trap thing?
Seeker: I'll, I'll get ready to cast Dispel Magic as soon as he opens the door.
Unknown: What the fuck?
Wellby: Yeah, that was you.
Kenzo: Wait, no, guy, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: This is one of those moments.
Seeker: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, these are the struggles.
Kenzo: This is one of those moments when I was like, when I was like with the Fausto and the stairs thing like-
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Hold on. We can't just open-
Seeker: Okay
Unknown: ... the magic door.
Seeker: This time we're gonna listen to Kenzo.
Kenzo: We can't just... Hold on, hold on. Let's just be thoughtful for a second.
Kenzo: Is there anything we can do to mitigate the, the, the inevitable damage and curses and things that are gonna come from this?
Wellby: Uh, spread out a little bit maybe.
Seeker: Can you Dispel Magic on the door?
Unknown: The door itself?
DM: You can.
Seeker: Is the door itself magical?
Delwath: Is the door magical?
DM: I mean, you can't see...
DM: I mean, there's magic around.
Delwath: But if I, but if I focus on the door, if I-
DM: That's not how this tech magic works.
DM: Like, you sense there's magic around, and if there's something you can see-
Delwath: Yes, I can see the door.
Delwath: Is the door that I can see-
DM: The door itself isn't magical
Unknown: ... okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Okay.
Wellby: All right, I'm gonna pick the lock.
Kenzo: I'm not near this situation.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: Where is Kenzo?
Kenzo: I'm, I'm upstairs.
DM: Okay. [laughs]
Seeker: Kenzo's oddly upstairs.
Wellby: Do you have any action?
Kenzo: I'm like, fuck this shit. I don't want to be near this door whatsoever.
Wellby: Do you have any action that as soon as the door opens, you're gonna Dispel Magic one of my hands?
Seeker: Yeah, that's my intention.
Unknown: I, I, I am like clicking away from it.
Delwath: I'm gonna back up about 40 feet.
Seeker: Do, i- is there any ration- rationale I can use by which to choose the level at which I cast Dispel Magic, like the hands?
Kenzo: Probably pretty fucking high.
DM: I mean, you have no idea whether they're actually spells or not-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... that you can dispel.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: So I should-
Kenzo: No, but they're, but they're magic.
DM: What are you doing for spells?
Kenzo: If they're magic you can... I'm pretty good.
Kenzo: Oh, you can only dispel spells while wearing-
Unknown: 'Cause I've been mostly just doing bird attacks.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Well, I mean, if they're like-
Delwath: I would not use a 6th or 7th, but maybe 4th
DM: ... who knows what magical constructs
Unknown: Oh, yeah, 4th is what you'd have on myself.
DM: Yeah, magical constructs.
Seeker: All right.
DM: A spell might get rid of the invisibility, but it certainly can-
Kenzo: Right, then the fists could be stopped with like the fists or-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... whatever the fuck. Okay.
Wellby: What if you control the fists from the panel on the front side of him?
Wellby: It's like a punchy control panel.
Delwath: Could be. Okay, let's just do this though.
Delwath: Kenzo ran away. Delwath is like 40 feet back.
Kenzo: Kenzo's... I mean, it's... he's just like from the...
Kenzo: He's peeking down, 'cause
Wellby: All right. Wellby unlocks the door [dice rolling] with a,
Wellby: a 20.
DM: Make a dexterity saving throw as a giant fireball explodes.
Seeker: A fireball.
Wellby: Oh, good thing we spaced out.
DM: You two. Mm, 20 feet, so not you.
DM: Not Del, not Kenzo.
Unknown: Yes. Fucking yes.
Wellby: That's a
Wellby: 13.
Unknown: You wanna... Did you do some stuff?
Wellby: Can I have some inspiration, bardic inspiration?
Seeker: Bardic inspiration.
Wellby: That'd be great. [paper rustling]
Delwath: It's a D... No, isn't it... Ah, it's a D12.
Wellby: That's a 12.
Seeker: Nice.
Delwath: 25. [dice rolling]
Seeker: Okay.
Delwath: I'll probably turn and roll.
DM: Plus a 10. 10.
Seeker: See how you do.
DM: 19, 28.
DM: Oh, wait. You succeeded?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: So you take nothing.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Did you... Did you, did you take nothing?
Unknown: You, you-
Wellby: Yeah. My dex save, yeah.
Seeker: So my dex save is plus seven.
Wellby: As a visually queued.
DM: Yeah, I'm pretty good at dex.
Seeker: Why is that?
DM: Wait. Yeah, yeah, you are.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 'Cause dex and int are the ones you're proficient in.
Seeker: Okay.
Seeker: So [dice rolling] that's a 12.
DM: Eh, that's not good enough.
Kenzo: But, but can't you... Oh, you can't. It's by your side.
Seeker: You can't. It's by your side.
Kenzo: Do you want to do your heroic thing, 'cause you're about to get like fucking a shit ton of damage?
Seeker: It's a reasonable moment to use my heroic inspiration.
Kenzo: This is, yeah, this is a fair- fairly good moment.
Seeker: So I just re-roll?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, man. [laughs] So it's plus five.
Kenzo: Plus seven.
DM: Plus seven.
Seeker: Plus seven.
Delwath: Try and get like at least a 10 maybe.
Seeker: [laughs] [dice rolling]
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: 16.
Unknown: You take 32 points of fire damage.
Unknown: That wasn't that bad.
Seeker: That wasn't terrible.
Kenzo: That wasn't awful. I mean, for a fireball it could've been worse.
DM: Um, and roll initiative.
Wellby: With whom?
DM: The sword and the fists.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: Oh, man.
Unknown: The sword. Fuck, we have to fight a death sword.
Seeker: Fuck.
Wellby: Oh, an invisible fist.
Wellby: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Uh, we get advantage, right?
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Wellby: And 25 for me.
Wellby: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Oh, I rolled a natural 20 on my initiative.
Kenzo: Does that do anything? I have a 30, Tim.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: But I rolled a natural 20 on the initiative.
Kenzo: Does that do anything?
DM: Um-
Seeker: You've rolled like three-
DM: It means you go well before anybody else
Kenzo: Can I, I, I finish and then I wait for a while.
Seeker: Oh, why didn't I summon construct before we did this?
Seeker: Ugh.
DM: Uh, you can. You can do that.
Seeker: Should we retcon that? 'Cause it's like-
Unknown: That, that would bring back-
Seeker: Kenzo's like, "Let's get ready," and then-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Summon construct, like bring back Lash.
Seeker: So I, I summon a construct, but what kind of construct?
Unknown: Oh, man. [laughs] Oh, man.
Kenzo: We're fighting a fucking dark demonic
Kenzo: fucking black void sword.
Wellby: I didn't expect the sword to attack us.
Kenzo: I didn't either. I thought it was being, it was being made.
Wellby: We're in the process, right?
Kenzo: Yeah. No. Okay. That's cool though.
Kenzo: I like this. I like this.
Wellby: What size sword is it?
DM: Um, it's like a great sword.
Wellby: So it's like bigger than me.
Seeker: I'm into this.
DM: It's like bigger than you, yeah.
Seeker: I'm into this situation.
Unknown: Why? Smaller than.
Seeker: Do we get-
Wellby: No, I think you should grab the sword and try and take control of it that way.
Seeker: Play with it? Oh, that's not a bad Seeker.
Unknown: Seeker should clearly grab that sword.
DM: Uh, what did you all roll for initiative?
DM: I know Kenzo got a ridiculous-
Seeker: Eight. Uh, 12.
Unknown: I rolled a 30.
Seeker: 10, 10.
Wellby: I rolled a 30.
Wellby: 25 for me.
Seeker: Do we have a, do we have a Wellby?
Wellby: We don't.
DM: 10 for Delwath. What about Seeker?
Seeker: Yeah. 11.
Kenzo: You could use the Rizlan for now.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: All right.
Wellby: That's a good plan.
Seeker: That's a good plan.
DM: Uh, okay.
Delwath: That's like about where the three of us are I think.
Kenzo: And Kenzo is, uh-
Seeker: Kenzo's like even further back.
Unknown: Yeah, Kenzo's-
DM: So the room is a 30 foot square.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Is the door centered?
DM: The door is centered.
Seeker: So-
DM: Well, make it, make it like, uh, it's a little shorter.
DM: It's 25 foot on this side and then 30 feet, so.
Seeker: So 50, like-
Kenzo: Do you want to draw it?
Seeker: Five, six.
DM: Yeah, yeah. I'll draw it.
Wellby: 10 on that. 10 on each side, right?
DM: Yeah, do 10 on each side.
Wellby: And then an extra 10 for the door.
Seeker: Yeah. Oh, yeah, yeah.
DM: Right. And then...
Seeker: Two,
Seeker: three, four, five, six. One, two.
DM: So it's like this. The-
Kenzo: And where are the two doors?
Unknown: Um-
DM: And then in the center it's like that, and then the silver panel is here.
DM: So this is the...
DM: So then the fists are gonna be-
Unknown: Sword panel here
DM: ... these-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: These D10s are the fists and this D4 is the
DM: sword. And Wellby of course is first.
DM: I mean, Kenzo of course is first, unless you wanna switch it around.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: wait, is this the, is this the sword?
DM: That's the sword, yeah.
Delwath: I think you going first and soul sighting something.
Kenzo: Definitely need to soul sight stuff.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: oh boy.
Delwath: And the fists are both invisible currently?
DM: The fists are both currently invisible.
Delwath: But I'll tell everybody where they are.
DM: Yes, you're aware of them, but you have disadvantage on attacks against them.
Kenzo: I can't soul sight them 'cause they're invisible.
DM: You can't, yeah, 'cause they're invisible.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You can soul sight the sword.
Kenzo: Yeah, so I'll, I'll... First let me... I'll get like a-
Unknown: That's me
Unknown: ... no, that's-
Kenzo: That's Delwath
Unknown: ... sorry.
Delwath: You're in the way in the back.
Kenzo: I guess I'll... First I'll, I'll like move over here.
Seeker: What's your... One, two, three, four.
Delwath: Your move is, like, 60?
Kenzo: Uh, I don't even know. Yeah, it's a lot.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: yeah, I'll soul sight the sword.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: the sword
DM: is,
DM: like, CR 24.
Wellby: That's too many.
DM: It's immune to all conditions,
DM: to poison damage, to psychic damage, and to necrotic damage.
Unknown: What is that?
Seeker: Like, a construct.
Unknown: The ladder.
DM: And it has no armor-
Seeker: The ladder's down
DM: ... resistances.
Unknown: It's immune to the-
Seeker: 'Cause it went an hour passed, but I summoned a construct
Unknown: ... poison, psychic, and necrotic.
Delwath: Can you just re-summon a construct?
Kenzo: Would that kill the-
DM: And all conditions
Unknown: ... construct?
DM: Blinded, deafened-
Unknown: Is that concentration?
DM: ... grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, restrained-
Delwath: Can you bring the ladder back?
DM: ... stunned, incapacitated, unconscious.
Seeker: Oh, that's probably what I should do, actually.
Delwath: Just burn a spell slot to bring the ladder back.
Seeker: Yeah, it's a third level spell slot.
Delwath: Sorry. Yeah. Sorry, I was talking to Seeker.
Unknown: I didn't hear what you said.
Kenzo: Holy fuck.
DM: It's immune to all conditions, poison, psychic, and necrotic damage.
Kenzo: Right. Okay.
Unknown: And then-
DM: Not resistant to anything
Delwath: ... and what are its good and bads?
DM: Oh, sorry, I didn't tell you yet.
DM: Um,
DM: it is-
Kenzo: You got the CR 24 part.
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... it is good at
DM: con.
DM: It is bad at int.
Seeker: This is the sword?
Unknown: The sword.
Seeker: Sword. Well, the ladder's back anyway.
Unknown: Fuck.
Kenzo: So all right. And, um, if we...
Kenzo: And if we want to escape, how do we do that?
Delwath: We just close the door and run away.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Did we make a terrible miscalculation?
Kenzo: We can always come back.
Delwath: Nah, let's just fight this.
Kenzo: Of course we're gonna fight this.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: But I'm just saying if, like, we're all, like, gonna...
Kenzo: If, like, the swo-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Kenzo: ... if the sword has, like, eight attacks and is, like, doing, dealing 100 points of damage, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... for each attack, like, you know, maybe we get out of here and then, you know, come back later.
Delwath: Wait, you said it's immune to psychic?
DM: It's immune to psychic, poison, and necrotic damage.
Kenzo: What about force?
DM: Nothing about force.
Kenzo: Oh, all right. Cool.
Kenzo: Then I'll use, um, I'll use my fucking thing.
Delwath: Um, hold on a second.
Unknown: Wait, wait, wait.
Wellby: Ooh.
Delwath: Hold on. Wait. Before we do anything...
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... sorry, I just wanna say we're not necessarily...
Delwath: This would be possibly a time when using scatter would make sense.
Kenzo: Yeah. Interesting point.
Wellby: Another thought is
Wellby: why don't we close the door and cast sickening radiance and call it a day?
Seeker: Will that affect these creatures?
Delwath: It's radiant damage.
Wellby: The room is small enough.
Kenzo: I mean, that's good. That's a good start.
Unknown: Did we-
Seeker: Can we bring down the rod that was-
Wellby: Oh, yeah. Which direction does the door open?
DM: Um-
Wellby: For fire safety, it should open towards us
DM: ... towards you. Yeah.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Wait, so we could in theory move a rod and close, but we don't know if these things can move.
Kenzo: I mean, I like this idea. I li- I like the idea of, of, uh, letting it just...
Kenzo: If that works. If they can...
Kenzo: If the shit can go through the door, whatever, we're fucked anyways, so.
Wellby: Maybe at a minimum that takes out the hands.
Delwath: Do we sickening radiance and then see if it comes...
Delwath: I mean, if they can move out through the door, then
Delwath: this, they can get away from the sickening radiance.
Kenzo: What room are... What's this room that we're in right here?
DM: This is the hall.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
DM: This is the stairway going down.
Unknown: Oh, so this is-
Wellby: Near room
Unknown: ... okay
DM: ... that's the corridor.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: At least it feels like a good opening move, and I could swap.
Wellby: You could close the... Well, wait a second.
Kenzo: I could swap with you, and then you could just do, do some-
Delwath: Well, then you went and soul sighted, but that probably doesn't matter if this was still our plan.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But he could swap.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: What was your initiative?
DM: 25.
Wellby: Yeah. So I'm probably up next.
Delwath: So you could swap with Delwath.
Delwath: One, I could just cast the spell.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, wait, but then they would go...
Delwath: Two, three, four, five, six. I can't actually get...
Delwath: I can't actually
Delwath: cast a spell and get up and close the door 'cause I'm too far away.
Kenzo: Can you, uh, um-
Delwath: The right thing to do would've been to swap with Kenzo.
Wellby: Well, can Kenzo hold action?
Unknown: No, no.
Wellby: So this-
Delwath: 'Cause if I swap with Kenzo, then you could just close the door.
Wellby: But I, I think Kenzo has gone first.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
Wellby: 'Cause we didn't have this plan until we understood what the threat from the sword was.
Unknown: Yeah. It's all good. It's all good.
Delwath: Yeah, and you can't fair, fair, fair, fair.
Unknown: It's all good. It's all good. It's all good.
Wellby: But can you hold action until the spell's cast and your action is to close the door?
Delwath: Oh, yeah. You didn't use your action. Yeah.
DM: Yeah, you could.
Unknown: No. No. Yeah. I can do that.
Wellby: Hope it just didn't roll higher than a 25 initiative.
DM: So, so
DM: Del- well, Wellby is 10 and Delwath is 25?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Kenzo is holding an action to-
Kenzo: Close the door
DM: ... close the door, and I'll say as part of that, if you also wanna move, you can move.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: It's up to you if you want to
Kenzo: Um, can I also, uh, uh, do like se- if I can dodge disengage or just, uh, um, whatever?
Unknown: Um
Kenzo: Like I've got a bunch of these, um, interesting, like,
Unknown: uh...
Unknown: You-
Unknown: I can like-
Delwath: You can't, you can't, um-
Kenzo: Not patient defen- uh, I can do step of the wind.
Kenzo: No, no, no. I can do, um-
Unknown: No, 'cause you already used your action
Unknown: You can use a bonus action.
DM: You can't do anything.
Kenzo: Ah, okay, okay. All right.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So you can close the door and you can move.
Kenzo: All right, I'll do that. I'll, I'll ready the action, close the door.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Wait, what were their good saves?
DM: Con?
DM: Good save con, bad save int.
DM: It's a con save, so
DM: it's DC 19.
DM: So he has a plus 10.
Kenzo: This, this is just for the sword. Who knows, it might, may not...
Kenzo: We don't know what's going on with the magic hands.
Wellby: Even if it just softens it for a minute, like even if it's 10 damage, that's still-
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Probably got some legendary saves. [clears throat]
Wellby: It does, doesn't it?
DM: Yeah, it probably does.
Delwath: Uh, wait, there's no need to use sorcery points to make us immune.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: I wonder if it has any layer advantages in there.
Delwath: Uh, the door's open, so I'm just casting a sickening radiance.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: I mean, it doesn't roll till its turn, but-
DM: Yep
Delwath: ... so it'll be, it'll-
DM: Sickening radiance fills the room.
Delwath: I mean-
Kenzo: And now does the door close?
Delwath: On your turn.
DM: Yeah, 'cause no, you're holding your action, so you just close the door.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Like right away, right? As soon as, soon as-
Unknown: Yeah. I'm gonna...
Delwath: We're not in a great position here.
Kenzo: I mean, if they can... W- um, we should really like get out of here and then if they, they come up, we should go up the stairs and fight it.
Kenzo: Fight, fight everything like upstairs, right?
Delwath: I feel bad moving away from the door because if it comes through the door, like it's gonna just attack by flying through the door and skewering all of us.
Unknown: So I'm gonna move away.
DM: [laughs] What the fuck?
Delwath: That's our plan is to go up the stairs.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: You just said it.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: Mm.
Kenzo: I feel like it would have a lot of layer advantages if we try to fight it in that room.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, how, what is the deal with the quarter Tim?
Unknown: Is this-
DM: Well, how far is that? That's, that's probably, it's probably turning, it probably turns right before we're done with, it's standing right now.
Delwath: That's 10. That's...
DM: That's not that, it's not that far.
DM: It, it turns a corner like, uh, two squares behind Seeker and then goes up another 15 feet to the, um, to the...
Delwath: Like that?
DM: Yep, and then that opens up into the, um,
DM: the storeroom,
DM: which is like a-
Kenzo: And we're just in like a super long hallway right here?
Unknown: Yeah. There's a, you're in stairs right there.
Kenzo: Oh, so it's going up.
DM: It's going up.
Unknown: So this-
DM: And this, this is like a just drawn as a 40 by 40 room
Kenzo: ... dude, totally. This, this sword's gonna fucking s- like fly forward and skewer all of us in a row.
Unknown: It's okay if it's 40 by...
DM: Yeah, that's fine
Delwath: ... 20 by... Should it be bigger than that?
DM: No, no, it should be bigger than that.
Delwath: It shouldn't or it should?
DM: It should.
Unknown: Oh, 'cause it's 40, 40.
DM: It's 40 by 40. It doesn't, the stairs don't have to be centered.
DM: I don't care where the stairs are.
Unknown: All right.
DM: 40 is eight squares.
Delwath: Yeah, this is eight.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Six.
DM: It doesn't have to quite be 40 there.
DM: Just draw it to the end of the map.
DM: That's close enough.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And then there's stairs.
DM: The stairs up to the surface are in that corner right where Finger is inside the room.
Unknown: Here?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: And then they go up like that, right?
Delwath: Okay. Delwath is going to go...
Kenzo: Oh, but I can still move.
DM: You can still move, yeah.
Kenzo: All right. I'm gonna fucking get the fuck out of here.
Kenzo: Uh...
Delwath: Uh, I'll go like right there
Kenzo: ... I'll go like right here.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: I'll go right here.
DM: Con save.
Unknown: DC 19. [die rolling]
DM: Uh,
DM: that is a,
DM: mm, that's a 20.
DM: So-
Kenzo: What about the, for the, the two hands?
DM: Uh, it's not their turn yet.
Kenzo: But don't they have the roll of a con save at the start of their turn?
DM: They do, but it isn't the start of their turn. The sword moves straight to the door.
DM: Who's that standing there?
Unknown: Oh, God.
Unknown: That's Wellby.
DM: Wellby.
Wellby: Yeah. It's, it's kind of, kind of me.
DM: Um, that's a 21 to hit Wellby.
Wellby: When you say straight through the door-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: ... what does that mean really?
DM: The point of the sword is flying straight into your chest.
Wellby: The door is closed.
DM: Yeah. It moves through the closed door.
Wellby: Huh.
Delwath: It's a void sword. Did you expect it to be limited by physical space?
Unknown: That's what-
Wellby: Well, clearly yes, we all did.
Unknown: I didn't. That's what's going right away.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, no.
Delwath: Remember what I said, if it pops through the door, it skewers all?
DM: 21 hits. 21 hits. Um, that's, uh, 11, 12, 19,
DM: uh, 27 points of force damage.
Wellby: Uncanny dodge.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Was that 14?
DM: It then...
DM: Yep. It then moves...
DM: Who's that? Who's the number one dice?
DM: Is that the ladder?
Unknown: That's the ladder.
DM: Uh, it attacks the ladder.
DM: [die rolling] That is a 25 to hit.
DM: [die rolling]
Seeker: Not it, I suppose that's-
DM: Um, the ladder takes nine, 18.
DM: The ladder takes 20 points of force damage.
Seeker: It's a pin. Okay.
Unknown: So that's...
DM: Um,
DM: uh, and then it-
Wellby: Do I get an opportunity attack?
Wellby: Does it move out of my way?
DM: Uh, nope. It's right behind you.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: It's in between you and the ladder right now, and that's where it stops for now.
Wellby: Man.
DM: Uh...
Seeker: Oh, good thing I did some healing on it.
Unknown: [die rolling]
DM: Um, that fails its con save that...
Unknown: What is it, DC?
Unknown: 19.
DM: Is a 19 a tie goes to?
Delwath: Tie goes to whoever rolls.
DM: Okay. [die rolling] So one of the two hands fails.
DM: It now cannot benefit from invisibility.
Delwath: That's true.
DM: So turn it, change it for a, like a brighter colored dice.
DM: Yeah, that's perfect.
Delwath: And it takes 12 plus tw- uh, plus 12, 24 damage.
DM: Okay. [die rolling]
DM: I need a track this on a spreadsheet.
Unknown: It's too hard.
DM: 24
Kenzo: That was better than I thought it was gonna be. I thought the void sword was gonna then like, you know, like some fucking...
Kenzo: It was gonna like suck out part of your soul.
Kenzo: That's what I thought, you know, and you know
DM: No, it's just normal
Unknown: ... it was gonna be a lot worse. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Oh.
Kenzo: My bad. That was cool. All right.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know, void sword into the chest, it felt pretty, you know...
Kenzo: Was worried about you for a second there, yeah.
Wellby: Good. Thanks. So, so worried that you left entirely, huh?
Kenzo: Yeah, I just gotta get out of the way. Yeah, you know.
Unknown: I thought we were all running away. So it is now-
Wellby: Some of us are getting stabbed
DM: ... Seeker's turn.
Seeker: [laughs] I'm thinking...
Kenzo: Wait, where's, where's the sword? We need to put the sword-
DM: The sword, put the gray thing in between the ladder and Seeker.
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
Seeker: Oh, actually...
Seeker: No, there.
Delwath: Wait, in between the ladder and Seeker?
DM: No, no, sorry. In between the ladder and Wellby.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, yeah. Right there.
Seeker: So if I turn into a dire bird...
Seeker: Oh, actually it won't get an opportunity to attack if I just run away.
DM: No, it can fly by.
Unknown: You could attack it and then run away, yeah.
Seeker: Um.
DM: But you have to... It's also not...
DM: This is not immune to spells, it's just immune to conditions.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Seeker: It's like-
Delwath: You can cast spells
Delwath: ... but you would have to use your action to turn into a bird.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: You could still run away having turned into a bird, but...
Delwath: I would, I would, I would blast it with a high level spell, honestly.
Seeker: Yeah. I'm just looking at...
Seeker: So this rune of psychic disruption does psychic damage.
DM: Or you can change it with your glove.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Oh, I didn't think of that because it's not elemental.
DM: But you can make anything elemental, you just can't change things to non-elemental damage.
Seeker: Huh.
DM: You can make it a rune of fire disruption.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: It won't... It's immune to conditions though
Wellby: It's a strategy, so
DM: ... it won't be incapacitated.
DM: But you can still
Kenzo: But you can stop the closed door with your spell.
Seeker: Right. Yeah, I will use-
Wellby: The closed door is a good
Seeker: ... it felt like the closed door was
Wellby: ... I mean, if it contains the hands it's still a great strategy
Seeker: That's true.
Unknown: Yeah. Clearly the fire-
Wellby: I think the goal-
Wellby: If it doesn't... I'm pretty screwed
Delwath: ... the hope here was that the hands
Wellby: suffer something.
Kenzo: At least something. I mean, it's already been h- it's already helpful.
Unknown: The hands
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... at least one hand is-
DM: Visibility is good
Kenzo: ... it's already h- you know, that's also good.
Seeker: So
Kenzo: hopefully they have to stay in here, and then the sword just chases us into this bigger room, and then we fuck it up there.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, so I can't use them.
Kenzo: And the sword doesn't seem like it can cast any spells.
DM: Yeah, I don't think the sword-
Kenzo: It's just like a...
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... you know, regular old
Seeker: All right. So cast-
DM: ... just regular old, uh
Seeker: ... psychic disruption, but use the glove to flavor it as fire damage.
Seeker: There's so many things to check off here.
Seeker: So that's one charge.
Seeker: So that's-
DM: So is that save, what save is that?
Seeker: So the-
DM: Int
Seeker: ... it's an int save.
DM: It's bad int
Seeker: Which is bad.
DM: Yeah, it totally fails.
Seeker: So that means I have to switch back over to the
Seeker: psychic disruption description.
Seeker: So that's 7d6 on a failed save.
DM: But you cast at a high level spell.
DM: Did you cast it at a higher slot?
Seeker: Oh, oh. Uh, it's-
Delwath: So it's 9d6. You cast it with a sixth level slot.
DM: So it's-
Seeker: Should it say that there?
Delwath: No, no, scroll down. It says it if you go down.
DM: See?
Seeker: Oh, that's what I... There you go. You're right.
DM: 9d6.
Seeker: It is nine- 9d6.
Unknown: That's good. We like that.
Seeker: And then plus with the glove effect,
Seeker: 2d10 fire damage.
Kenzo: Yep. 9d6 and 2d10.
Seeker: All right. That's not-
DM: That's not terrible.
Unknown: That's all right
Seeker: ... but... So wait, I'll do the 9d6 on-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... a 20. [laughs]
Unknown: No, you can roll, roll, roll 9d6.
DM: Let's just do a roll for it.
Unknown: Just, it's... Yeah.
Seeker: Aw.
Unknown: That's so boring. 38.
Seeker: That's 38.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: And then-
DM: And then 2d10
Seeker: ... but I have to do a spell attack.
Seeker: Make a spell attack roll,
Seeker: and that's the 2d10, and if it fails, I take the fire damage.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Yes.
DM: What?
Delwath: That's a little risky.
DM: You don't have to do that. You're not obligated to do the fire effect.
DM: That's just a bonus you can choose to do.
DM: You can change it into fire without-
Seeker: Oh, I, I choose it.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: What's my... Uh, the spell attack.
Unknown: Where do we get the spell attack?
DM: It's plus 10.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: So that's-
DM: d20.
Seeker: Uh, that's a 16.
DM: That just hits.
Unknown: Oh. 2d10.
DM: 16 to hit. Nice.
Unknown: That's not bad.
Seeker: So that is 12 additional damage.
DM: Okay.
DM: So Seeker's rune, that you've seen before as a-
Seeker: So I just did 50 total damage
DM: ... as a dis- rune of psychic disruption-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: ... turns into a rune of fire disruption and
DM: bursts in the face of this sword, which
DM: doesn't react in the slightest, but obviously takes damage.
DM: Um.
Seeker: And then I can move 30-
Unknown: But it still has the closed door thing?
DM: It can attack you, I think
DM: It can attack... No, no, it's, it's...
DM: That's the ladder-
DM: Oh, that's the ladder
DM: ... between Seeker and... Yeah.
Seeker: That's as far as I can get, I think.
Seeker: I have a 30 move.
Unknown: Yeah. One, two, three, four, five.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And now the ladder.
Seeker: The ladder will do its force slam attack, which-
DM: The ladder... You re-summoned the ladder, so it should be totally at full health.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Right, I was looking at the-
DM: You spend a third level slot to re-summon it
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... so it's actually now at-
Unknown: 85
DM: 85
Seeker: ... minus the 20 it just took.
DM: Just minus the 20
Kenzo: Good damage sponge.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: It's a great damage sponge.
Seeker: 65.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Um.
Unknown: All right. Taking bets.
Seeker: And then the ladder is gonna attack.
Kenzo: Does the door, does the door hold back the fists?
Seeker: Uh...
Unknown: You know, 'cause not only the fists-
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry
DM: ... it feels like the fists-
DM: The fists get... I skipped the fists' turn.
DM: I rolled their saves, but I didn't get to do what they did.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
DM: But that's okay.
DM: This is happening while S- while Seeker's doing his spells.
DM: You hear, like, the door opens in.
DM: Wellby's the only one s- opens out like this.
DM: Wellby's the only one standing there, right?
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: No, didn't you immov... Oh, no, you didn't immovable rod it closed 'cause you couldn't do that at the same time.
Kenzo: I just closed the door. I don't have the immovable rod.
DM: Uh, make a strength check.
Wellby: Strength.
DM: Or athletics.
Wellby: Athletics.
Delwath: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, athletics is gonna be better probably.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: We like athletics.
Seeker: Is it better?
Wellby: No.
Wellby: What about acrobatics?
DM: Uh, can you use acrobatics to hold a door closed?
Wellby: No.
Seeker: While hanging upside down?
Seeker: Can you stick the immovable rod in now?
DM: No.
Wellby: Can I use survival because my very survival is at stake?
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Here's my strength check.
Seeker: Use intelligence 'cause that would be smarter to do.
Wellby: There's a 10 minus one-
DM: [blows raspberry] The door flies open
Wellby: Inspiration?
Seeker: Inspiration.
DM: You can ins- yeah, you can try it.
DM: [dice rolling]
Wellby: That's 14, and that's 20.
DM: Nope. The door flies open.
Unknown: What?
Wellby: Ugh.
Unknown: 20 on a strength check?
DM: They're strong.
Wellby: Really?
DM: They're giant fists.
Unknown: Giant hands.
Wellby: Yes.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Man.
Delwath: Ah, man, we needed to have the ladder there.
DM: Uh, it's-
Unknown: Yeah, I mean, we can't re-target
Delwath: ... it's pretty strong. The ladder might be able-
Seeker: The ladder has 18 strength. Um,
Seeker: and then...
DM: What was I gonna talk about?
Delwath: Wait, does the ladder go on Seeker's turn?
DM: Yeah, the ladder is about to-
Wellby: 'Cause I skipped-
DM: I rolled the kansais of the fists, but-
Wellby: But you skipped
DM: ... forgot. The ladder can attack, is attacking the, uh-
Unknown: The sword
DM: ... the sword. Well, and-
Unknown: I was thinking-
DM: Robbie doesn't really have space to be pushed back, but you're maybe...
DM: This is its action, but you're also knocked prone by the force [blows raspberry] as the fist pushes the door-
DM: Scatter
DM: ... knocks you prone.
DM: The second fist-
Unknown: I couldn't cast it, actually
DM: ... which is still invisible and you can't see.
Kenzo: When, when can you cast it?
Wellby: On my turn.
Kenzo: As an action?
Wellby: Bonus, I get bonus action.
Unknown: You get bonus action.
DM: Uh, what's your AC?
Delwath: I can use my metamagic to bonus action it.
DM: My AC is 19.
Kenzo: What was your bonus action this turn?
DM: Misses. Um-
Seeker: Okay, so the ladder's attack-
Wellby: I [dice rolling] cast sickening radiance
Seeker: ... is a 22.
Wellby: I, I had nothing to do with it.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Could you have scattered as a bonus action?
Delwath: No, I can't do two spells in one turn.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: Ah, mm,
DM: yes you can.
Wellby: Oh, right, you're right.
DM: Scatter doesn't cost a spell slot.
Unknown: Scatter doesn't count as a spell. I actually could have.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: 200.
Wellby: But there was nowhere to s-
Delwath: I should've thought of that. We should've talked about it, but...
Wellby: If I move as... 'Cause, 'cause-
Kenzo: Scatter includes being able to rearrange the ladder, right?
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Seeker: What's my proficiency bonus?
Kenzo: Well, we'll see what situation we're in at the start of your turn.
Unknown: It's five.
Wellby: Scatter may still be a good thing to do.
Unknown: So 1d10 plus five damage.
Wellby: But it will be a-
Seeker: I assume that hits.
DM: Yeah, yeah, that... Where did you... Yeah, it was 60, may see, so you hit.
Seeker: Oh, fucking prone. 1d10.
Unknown: 1d10.
Wellby: Where's the 10?
DM: Scatter might be very good actually.
DM: Robbie's next.
DM: Oh.
Wellby: Uh, Wellby's next.
Seeker: So that's-
Seeker: Move up to half the speed as a reaction-
Seeker: Oh, a 10. Uh, 15 damage from the ladder
Wellby: ... when an enemy ends its turn within five feet of me without provoking opportunity attacks.
DM: You can crawl.
Wellby: All right. Yeah.
DM: So that's, rather than half your speed, that's a quarter of your speed.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: but I'm boots of speeded, so my speed is 90, so it's...
Wellby: I only need to get to the side of the ladder.
DM: 45, it's like, yeah.
Wellby: 5, 10, 15.
Wellby: Call it
Wellby: 20, 20.
DM: Yeah, say 20 is fine.
Unknown: Does the... Uh, okay.
DM: But you're still prone.
Wellby: Awesome.
Wellby: I'm up right now?
DM: It's your turn.
Unknown: You're up. Wait, did both fists go?
DM: Both fists went.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: One punched through the door and knocked him prone, the other tried to punch him and missed.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: And so is this other fist like here now?
DM: It's invisible. You don't know where it is.
Wellby: Oh, okay. I'll stand up.
Wellby: That's half my move.
Wellby: Is that true?
DM: Yep.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: and I'll shoot the sword, and then I'll go back into the big room.
Wellby: So not advantage, but yes sneak attack.
Unknown: Yep. [dice rolling] That's a natural 20.
Delwath: Nice. [laughs] On sneak attack.
Delwath: Good job.
Wellby: Wow.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Good job. Good job, John.
Wellby: What does that mean?
DM: He rolls double dice.
Wellby: How many dice is that?
DM: That's like four 8d6, no, four 2d6.
Wellby: Which is... Uh, normally I would roll, uh, eight for sneak attack plus one for my-
DM: So it's nine, uh, 18d6.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: So-
DM: You want me to roll them or you want-
Wellby: No
DM: ... me to roll one?
Wellby: Roll them.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah. Let's roll the fuck out of these dice.
DM: Nine.
Wellby: 10, 11, 12.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Wellby: 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Here we go.
Kenzo: All right, 18d6. Roll the fuck out of these dice.
Kenzo: Let's go. [dice rolling]
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: It's all of them, right?
DM: There's some sixes.
Delwath: Yep, there's a lot of sixes.
Delwath: There's a lot of sixes.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Holy shit.
Wellby: Six, six, six.
Delwath: There's another six here.
Wellby: Six.
Unknown: There's another six.
Wellby: Another six.
Unknown: Holy crap.
Wellby: Four plus six. Okay, so 10, 20,
Wellby: 30, 40, uh, what?
Wellby: 52, 64,
Wellby: 76.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Plus-
Delwath: 80, 86
Wellby: ... 86.
Delwath: 86 damage.
Wellby: Wow.
DM: That's bloodied.
Delwath: Wow.
DM: Nice. And now-
Unknown: Wellby
DM: ... Wellby.
Wellby: And then I move.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
DM: Um,
DM: who's... Wait, who-
Wellby: Oh.
DM: Now the sword-
Unknown: Oh, fuck
DM: ...
DM: gets two actions a turn.
Unknown: Section, right.
DM: And is going to stab through the ladder.
DM: [dice rolling] That's a 20 to hit.
Seeker: Uh, that, um... Does that, does that hit?
Delwath: Do we want to rearrange all of our positions?
DM: The ladder takes 15-
Kenzo: Let's, let's see what happens
DM: ... takes 19 points of damage.
Delwath: I guess if it comes around the corner, what's the point?
DM: And then who's this right here?
Delwath: That's Seeker.
DM: And then it stabs Seeker.
Wellby: Does the ladder get an opportunity attack as the sword goes past?
Unknown: Oh, man.
DM: Uh, the ladder can, yep.
Seeker: Oh, oh. So it does a...
Kenzo: Has an opportunity attack, yeah.
Unknown: Hm. [dice rolling]
Wellby: Is that a grapple?
Seeker: That's an 11 plus...
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's immune to all conditions.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: That includes grapple.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
Wellby: Oh, right. I guess it can go through solids.
DM: That hits. If it can go through solid doors, I don't think the ladder can be a problem.
Seeker: Um, so that's 1d10 plus-
DM: Poor sword
Seeker: ... five again. Is that right?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yep. [dice rolling]
Seeker: So that's 12.
Wellby: Oh, the ladder's doing pretty good.
Seeker: The ladder's done 27 damage.
DM: Not, you know, seven, not 88 or anything like that.
Seeker: Right, right, right. It's, but after all, it's just a ladder.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Um, wait, is the door still...?
DM: The door is open.
Wellby: But the hand didn't come through.
DM: The hand did not come through.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: They're stuck for another turn in the, in the-
Wellby: Well-
Seeker: Well, we have our last line of defense there
DM: ... yeah.
Unknown: Actually, if the ladder's gone.
Delwath: Well, but if the ladder can close the door,
Delwath: if the ladder can get back and hold the door closed, they're still in the sickening radiance.
Unknown: Ooh, that's a good point.
Kenzo: And they gotta roll kansais.
Wellby: And they gotta roll kansais.
DM: Um-
Wellby: But we gotta wait for my turn
DM: ... yeah.
Kenzo: Is one of them out the door-
DM: Yeah
DM: ... or is the sword still-
Wellby: No, it's invisible
DM: ... the sword now attacks Seeker.
Kenzo: But the invisible one-
Wellby: Shit
Unknown: ... is it still in the door, or...?
DM: Uh, oh, your AC is terrible, right?
DM: A 19?
Seeker: That hits.
DM: Okay. [dice rolling] That is 12, 20,
DM: 29, 31 points of damage.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: That's rough.
Seeker: What type of damage is that?
DM: Force.
DM: Um,
DM: and that
DM: ends its turn.
Delwath: So then Kenza is next.
Unknown: [sighs]
Delwath: And then Delwath, right?
DM: So Kenza's up.
Kenzo: So, um,
Kenzo: can I... How do I... Can I, can I fight through-
DM: You're... You gotta move Seeker.
DM: You can't move through...
DM: Actually, I mean, Wellby technically shouldn't have been able to move through the space of a hostile creature anyway.
DM: Uh, no.
Delwath: Wellby didn't move through the space of a hostile creature.
DM: When you were crawling you moved through the sword.
Kenzo: He moved past the sword. He crawled past the sword.
Wellby: Can I move through the space of creatures since I'm small?
DM: Oh, yeah, one size larger than you.
DM: That's right. It's medium.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: Yeah, yeah. You can move through it.
Wellby: Good.
DM: But anybody else can't.
Kenzo: So if I want to attack, uh, if you-
DM: If you want to attack you gotta use, like, step of the wind to drag Seeker out of the way first.
Seeker: Which I don't mind. [laughs]
DM: But-
Kenzo: Oh, wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait. How tall is the room?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Can I fly?
Unknown: Oh.
DM: No, these are s- these are steps going...
DM: These are not wide open steps like the spiral staircase going up.
Unknown: It's not.
DM: It's not possible.
Delwath: Oh, but you could bonus action.
DM: You can bonus action step and move Seeker out of the way.
Delwath: But then you can only take two attacks instead of five.
DM: Yes, then you only get two attacks.
Unknown: But that's okay.
Unknown: What else can you do?
Kenzo: But then afterwards I can still move.
Kenzo: After attack.
DM: Yeah, you can still move after you...
DM: You can split up your move.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So [sighs] okay.
Kenzo: Well, I get three attacks, right? 'Cause I get-
DM: No, if you use your bonus action to do step of the wind and move Seeker out of the way, you only get your two main attacks.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Not the three bonus action attacks.
Kenzo: I see. Okay. All right. All right. Then, um,
Unknown: yeah, fuck it, I guess I'll do that.
Delwath: I mean, what else are you gonna do? Unless you have a ranged...
DM: Could you, um-
Unknown: I do. I've got... Oh.
DM: Fist of-
Kenzo: I can use... I'm gonna... I'll fucking use Lengau's...
Unknown: the Lengau's Claw.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: I meant, I meant to do that anyways at the beginning of this whole thing.
Kenzo: I forgot to do it.
DM: Ah, wait, no. Did, did you do it last time?
DM: You didn't do it last time.
Kenzo: I did not because the fucking whole thing was-
DM: 'Cause they forced you to use-
Kenzo: Yeah. Thank fucking goodness.
Unknown: Hell yeah. Perfect.
DM: Can you only do it once a day?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yeah, it's once a day.
Kenzo: But I can, I can punch, uh, 15 feet with it.
Delwath: Yes. Does it, does it last for like a minute or just one attack?
Unknown: Last for a minute.
DM: No, it's a minute. Ah, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, that's for the whole, whole, whole combat.
Kenzo: Great. Um, then I will do that, which is, I think just happens...
DM: Yeah, no action, it just happens.
Unknown: Yeah, it just, just-
DM: It just... Your, the, the-
Kenzo: It's like my fucking... I turn my tattoo on
DM: ... the tattoo like c- climbs out of your fist.
Kenzo: Beautiful. Then I will stand exactly where I am and attack the sword from here.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Perfect. Um,
Kenzo: oh, and, um, I can use Fist of Planar Power against the fist.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Okay. All right.
Kenzo: Then I'm gonna do five... Okay, so this is gonna be fun.
Unknown: I'm gonna do-
Delwath: You can't do fist a- Oh, no, can you replace-
Wellby: It replaces one of his attacks.
Unknown: Yeah. But it's-
DM: You can only do it proficiency or wisdom on three times a day.
DM: But you can use ki to do it again if you-
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So first attack can I...
Kenzo: Do I get advantage right now?
DM: No.
Unknown: I don't, right? So-
DM: No advantage.
Kenzo: Wow, it's the first time attacking without advantage.
Kenzo: This feels... I feel so naked.
DM: His AC is not so high.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's only 16.
Wellby: Wait, wait, wait. Why doesn't he get advantage?
Unknown: Why wouldn't he?
Wellby: 'Cause he hit it during the first round...
Wellby: It's the first thing I hit in the first round of combat.
DM: But this is the second round of combat.
Delwath: This is the second combat.
DM: Right? It's only for the first combat.
Delwath: Back to the top.
DM: Or is it till your turn?
Wellby: It must be my turn, 'cause if I was the bottom of the initiative there wouldn't be any advantage.
DM: I thought that's why everybody went first.
Delwath: That's why we always make you go first.
DM: Check it though.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: 'Cause if it's until your turn then you do get advantage.
Kenzo: Well, it doesn't matter, I hit this first one anyways, right?
Wellby: Attack rolls against that target have advantage until the start of your next turn.
DM: Oh, okay. So it lasts until the start of your turn.
DM: So yeah.
Kenzo: So I do have advantage.
DM: It does have advantage.
Kenzo: All right. Well, I'll roll again in case I get a natural 20.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] Okay, that was inefficient.
Kenzo: All right. Um, and then, um, so for this first one, this is just a regular staff attack.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] So that's seven-
DM: Uh, no, sorry. Well, it doesn't matter 'cause it's all D10 anyway, but with Lengau's Claw you can't use your staff, it's just your fists.
Kenzo: Oh, okay. But it is still D10.
DM: It's still a D10, it's just plus five instead of plus six, so.
Kenzo: Right. But now, but, um, also Lengau's, um, that thing gives-
DM: But it adds extra damage.
Unknown: It does. Yeah.
DM: So that's one D6 extra for every attack.
Kenzo: It, it, it does a- as- add extra damage.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on, real quick, real quick.
Kenzo: Uh, I think it adds a D6.
Unknown: Let me just make sure.
Kenzo: Hold on. Where the fuck is that thing?
Unknown: Where's my fucking tattoo?
Delwath: Uh.
DM: So-
Unknown: Oh, here it is. Okay.
Kenzo: An extra 1 D6. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So that's-
DM: Oh, no, no, no, no, no. Leave that. That's that.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Sorry.
Kenzo: Sorry, sorry, sorry. Hold on. Give me one of these.
Kenzo: Okay. So wait, so I get... It's one plus five is six, and then plus this, so nine.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Nine damage for the first attack.
Kenzo: Okay. Second attack, Tim, I'm doing, um,
Kenzo: Fist of Planar Power.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Which is, um...
Kenzo: What do I even do with that? It's a psychic attack.
Delwath: Uh, it's a... Is it immune to s- Wait, I'm confus- I forget.
DM: Is this guy immune to psychic?
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: But it's... Oh, so, is this not useful then?
DM: No, no. Why, where is it psychic?
Kenzo: Fist, Fist of Planar Power.
Kenzo: Oh, it's just a strength. Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, no, yeah, it does psychic damage 'cause it's like-
Unknown: Okay. So it's-
DM: ... striking their ki
Wellby: So don't.
DM: You probably don't want to do that.
Kenzo: Okay. Then I'll just, I'll just, I'll just punch it.
DM: Just punch it.
Kenzo: I'll choose... Like, I'll just continue using my fists.
Kenzo: Okay. I, it hits and then I do,
Kenzo: [dice rolling] uh, 15 damage.
Kenzo: And then I'm just gonna do three more of that.
Kenzo: Three more of these.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] I hit again.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] Uh, do 15 more damage.
Kenzo: And now I got two more fist attacks.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Wait, no, no.
Unknown: One more.
DM: One more.
Kenzo: No, no, no. The, no, no. No, no, no.
DM: No, two more.
Unknown: I do, I do five total attacks.
DM: Yeah, you've, you've got three attacks from the D10.
Kenzo: Okay. Yeah. So two more. [dice rolling] Oh, shit.
Unknown: Oh, that's allowed.
DM: No, no, it hits.
Unknown: 20 plus.
DM: 16 AC. Yeah.
Unknown: And then-
Kenzo: Uh, 13.
Kenzo: And then last attack [die rolling] hits, I'm gonna do,
Kenzo: uh, 17.
Unknown: Oh, damn.
Unknown: How much damage is that?
DM: That's a lot.
Unknown: Is it, is it-
Unknown: All right
Delwath: Do you guys want to get rearranged?
Unknown: Um, I-
Unknown: I sure do
Kenzo: ... I'm gonna, I'm gonna move just like, I don't know, just like over here 'cause why the fuck not?
Delwath: Don't you need to be within 15 feet to punch it?
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: No, it's not punching it though.
Kenzo: I'm done punching it.
Delwath: Oh, you're running away for the moment.
Unknown: Yeah, it's...
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... let's get out of the way a little bit. Why not?
Seeker: I, I would like to get clear because it could actually knock me out with one more hit.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: I think. Is that true? No.
Kenzo: I have 65, so that's probably fine for one more.
Delwath: I can... I mean, I can move us around.
Delwath: I just don't know if that's-
Kenzo: Do you have an attack that can move...
Kenzo: can, that can get through, uh-
Delwath: Well, I'd have to move Seeker.
Delwath: That's... I could scatter. I... So I could either just...
Delwath: I mean, I could dimension door to just attack it and leave Seeker to his fate, or I could scatter to move me and Seeker.
Kenzo: Is... Oh, but when, but when's Seeker's, uh, turn?
Unknown: It might just go now.
DM: The sword... It's the sword, then the fists, then Seeker.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. You should-
Delwath: Right. But it's dealt with now.
Unknown: Yeah. You should scatter.
DM: Dealt with, sword, fists, Seeker.
Kenzo: You should scatter 'cause this-
Delwath: But I could move the ladder to be next to the door too.
Seeker: That would be good. That'd be good.
Kenzo: You should, you should re-scatter this shit and put the ladder in front of the sword, don't you think?
Delwath: No, no, no. The ladder should block the door so it can't-
DM: The door is currently open.
Unknown: Yeah, but-
Seeker: Okay. The ladder doesn't have an action until next turn.
DM: Till after the fists go.
Delwath: But even if the ladder's just there-
DM: It still keeps the... Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... it still keeps-
DM: That's right. That's true. Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: But, but there's no advantage to it, it being in a different position in the corridor than it is-
DM: Well, but enemies can't move through its ladder space.
Delwath: No, there is, because if it, if it stays in this space, they're still in the sickening radiance.
Seeker: Oh, I see, I see.
Kenzo: Yeah. But, but he can't... The, the ladder can't be moved here though.
Unknown: I can scatter.
Unknown: Yeah. Well, scatter.
Unknown: Oh, scatter can rearrange people.
Unknown: Oh. Six people.
Unknown: Oh, but I thought-
Unknown: This room
Kenzo: ... I thought it was, uh, you can only exchange the positions.
Unknown: No, no, no, no, no.
Unknown: Oh, you can move them.
Delwath: I can move six people anywhere on the board.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Cool, cool.
Unknown: Yeah. Let's do it. Let's do it.
Unknown: All right. Yeah, let's do it.
Unknown: Let's do it.
Delwath: Including enemies.
Unknown: Really?
Unknown: They gotta saves.
Unknown: Oh, so you can try to move-
Delwath: But should I, like, move the forest guy back into the light?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, totally.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: You should move everybody to the back then.
Kenzo: This should also go back.
Unknown: Where-
Kenzo: 'Cause he has to roll a save as well. I mean, he has to-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... roll a con save to-
Delwath: Okay. I'm bonus action scattering.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: But I want to attack it.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Right? Oh, but I can move me.
DM: You don't want to put yourself in the-
Unknown: No
Unknown: ... front 'cause-
Unknown: That's terrible.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Awful, insane idea.
Wellby: I think the sword, we've done enough damage to.
Delwath: I think we weave the sword.
Wellby: But you should just... Yeah. And swap yourself in there-
Delwath: I think I'm-
Wellby: ... and attack it
Delwath: ... I'm g- But Kenzo has enough move that you can run back over here.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: I'm gonna put Seeker
Unknown: as far away as I can.
Unknown: Anywhere else, yeah. [laughs] That's good.
Delwath: I'm gonna put me here, I'm gonna put the ladder here,
Delwath: and I'm gonna put... Oh, wait.
Delwath: Can I move... I'm gonna move this guy.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: What's the save?
Unknown: DC 19.
Wellby: But what ability?
Unknown: Uh, wisdom.
Wellby: Nope.
Delwath: And the oth- uh, the other one.
Unknown: The invisible one.
Wellby: Do you have to be able... You have to be able to see the targets.
Delwath: Oh. I guess I have to be able to see the target.
Unknown: Wait, hold on.
Delwath: Oh, no, it's only th- Let's see.
Unknown: That you can see.
Delwath: It's 30... It's only 30...
Unknown: So actually-
Wellby: I will let you do it like-
Delwath: I can't. I can't
DM: ... it previously. You have to be able to see them.
Delwath: I have... It's only 30 feet also.
Wellby: There you go.
Delwath: So I don't know if I can even get the ladder.
Seeker: Yeah. Well, the ladder's around the corner, so to do it-
Delwath: Yeah. I'd have to, like-
Unknown: ... you couldn't really see it
Delwath: ... I'd have to like...
Delwath: No, I couldn't see it.
DM: You can't see the ladder. It's around the corner.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But-
Unknown: So put that one back
Unknown: ... man.
Kenzo: Then is this whole thing-
Unknown: Is it worth it?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah, that's where it was.
Delwath: It's mostly... 'Cause then it's burning a spell.
Delwath: It's... I don't know if it's worth it in that case.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, the problem is I can't attack.
Delwath: The problem is I can't attack the thing.
Unknown: I mean, is it worth... 'Cause I could like...
Delwath: 'Cause, see, if I just moved myself,
Unknown: right?
Wellby: Can you misty step or dimension door-
Delwath: I could
Wellby: ... to the other side of the sword?
Delwath: Right. I could do that instead and just attack it, right?
Unknown: And then-
Unknown: You might kill it
Seeker: ... and
Delwath: then I could always scatter next...
Delwath: I'm just gonna do that. I... It's not worth a sixth level slot if I can't.
Wellby: Tim, is talking a free action?
Unknown: Yep.
Wellby: Can I reach out telepathically to the sword and say, uh, and try to say, "Surrender or be destroyed"?
Unknown: Sure.
Unknown: Uh-
Seeker: And it's interesting because it's a sword.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: It ignores you.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: I mean, honestly-
Kenzo: Well, this is interesting.
Unknown: Just why not?
DM: Just try.
Unknown: Why not?
Unknown: [sighs]
Unknown: Cool.
Wellby: It's so rarely-
Unknown: Seeker, you-
Wellby: ... do we try talking
Seeker: I should've used suggest.
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: I didn't think of it.
Unknown: Um, okay.
Unknown: Suggest on what? The sword.
Delwath: I think I am just gonna u- I'm gonna s- I think it's better-
Unknown: You're just gonna scatter
Delwath: ... I think it's better to just move Seeker away.
Delwath: I think that's safer for everybody.
Unknown: I think-
Unknown: Are you behind it or in front of it?
Wellby: Put yourself on the other side
Wellby: 'cause that way you can't be flanked by the fists.
Delwath: That's true.
Delwath: Yeah. I'll just do that. It's so what, it's a sixth level slot to swap me and
Delwath: Seeker, but I don't see any...
Delwath: I don't see a better...
Unknown: It's,
Delwath: it's a spell either way.
Delwath: And honestly, in some ways my fifth level slot are more valuable.
Delwath: Okay. Then I'm attacking it.
Delwath: Sorry, just gotta check off my, uh...
Unknown: [sighs] Where is my...
Delwath: Okay. Attack number one, uh, that hits.
Delwath: [die rolling] For, uh, plus six is 12.
Delwath: [sighs] I'm gonna heroic inspiration re-roll my one.
Delwath: I'm rolling terribly. [die rolling]
Wellby: Wait, uh-
Unknown: Now-
Wellby: ... you have advantage.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Yeah, you still have advantage.
DM: So you don't... Well, just use the 10.
Delwath: I'll keep, keep the 10. I'm just rolling again on my-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: Keep the 10.
Delwath: So that was eight plus six is 14.
Unknown: 14.
Delwath: I'm gonna s- oh, I used my bonus action.
Delwath: I can't smite it.
DM: You used your bonus action.
Unknown: For... Oh, wait.
Delwath: Is eldritch smite a bonus action?
Unknown: Let me double check.
Delwath: No, it's just once per turn.
Unknown: It's not.
Delwath: All right.
Delwath: Okay. I am... Okay, so that is one, two.
Delwath: It's 66, 68.
Delwath: So 12, 14 D8.
Unknown: What the fuck?
Delwath: I smited it.
Unknown: 14 D8?
Delwath: I just critted. So I'm using an eldritch smite-
Unknown: Wow
Delwath: ... which does a bonus
Delwath: 5/6 D8 damage,
Delwath: plus my normal two D8,
Delwath: doubled, is 12 D8.
Kenzo: How many times do you get to smite?
Delwath: Uh, it's a spell slot.
Kenzo: Oh, I see. I see. Okay. All right, this better kill it.
Kenzo: This has gotta kill it.
Delwath: So that's one, two, three, four, five, six.
Kenzo: Voidsworn, be dead.
Wellby: There's one there, so.
Delwath: Seven.
Kenzo: Fuck this Voidsworn.
Unknown: More D8s?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Eight, nine, 10-
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry.
Unknown: 11, 12
DM: You hit it once with a melee attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: The first one.
DM: Um, it slashes at you in retaliation as a reaction.
DM: Um, and that's a 26 to hit.
Unknown: Uh, sh- I guess I could cast shield.
Delwath: Oh, no, it'd still hit. But never mind, I'll take the damage.
DM: That's
DM: 7, 10, that's 19 points of force damage
DM: in retaliation to the first attack before the crit.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And it's prone.
Delwath: How is it prone? It doesn't move from prone.
Delwath: My smite automatic- oh.
Delwath: It doesn't use up some of your conditions.
Unknown: 8, 10,
Delwath: 20,
Unknown: 30,
Unknown: 46,
Delwath: not 49, plus 6 is 55.
Unknown: Dead.
DM: You strike it with this mighty blow as this wave of force
DM: s- hits the sword, and it shatters into four daggers.
Delwath: Hold on. Did I... I cast second wind again.
Unknown: Okay, so I used two pact spells.
DM: Small daggers.
DM: Two in a space.
Seeker: Oh my gosh.
Unknown: Four daggers.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Phase one is over.
DM: Uh, that ends Delwath's turn.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: The two daggers are gonna fly through you.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, that's a
DM: 20.
Delwath: Miss.
DM: 22.
Unknown: Shield.
DM: The first one, it still flies through you, but it does no damage.
DM: The second one bounces off your shield and stays in place.
DM: Uh, the next two are gonna fly through you as well.
Delwath: My AC is now 26.
DM: Um, that's a 17 and a 26.
Unknown: One hits.
DM: So one hits, and that's
DM: 15 points of damage.
DM: And the four daggers
DM: are now
DM: there.
DM: And that
DM: ends the sword's turn.
DM: The fist continues.
Unknown: Yep. [laughs]
Kenzo: Where the fuck is the invisible one?
DM: That's-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... that's, uh, like 20-something.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So that one succeeds. Move that into the door and hit the ladder.
Unknown: See, this is the problem.
Unknown: What's the problem?
Delwath: Well, that just escaped through the other one.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Did the other one make it safe?
Unknown: I'm rolling for it. Uh, nope.
Delwath: Okay, it's visible.
DM: It's right next to the,
DM: right next to the door, one square to the right.
Wellby: Are they still visible even after moving-
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... to the square rules?
DM: Yeah, they're... cannot benefit from invisibility.
Unknown: 10,
Delwath: uh, plus 19 damage.
DM: Okay.
DM: Um, the ladder, let's see.
DM: Oh, that was a two. That misses the ladder.
DM: And the next one is just gonna move into the hallway.
Delwath: Yeah. See, I wish we could've gotten the ladder.
DM: But not... Um, but they're, now they're both visible, and that ends their turns because this one can't,
DM: can't do it, can't get th- past.
DM: It's tr- stuck by the ladder.
Kenzo: Is it just gonna be stuck there until they kill the ladder?
Delwath: Maybe. Yeah.
DM: I mean, they might have other things they can do, but they kind of need to hit first.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, 'cause they can shut it if they hit it.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, that ends the fist's turn.
DM: Seeker, you're up.
Kenzo: Well, this is cool 'cause the ladder's kind of like it's gonna have to keep getting pushed along-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... until it gets out of there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, well, this is helpful for a while.
Seeker: So these, all these daggers, maybe I should try slowing them.
Unknown: Can Slow-
DM: They are probably... Well,
DM: Kenza would have to re-soul sight them.
DM: Um-
Delwath: But there's a decent chance they're...
Delwath: But slow's not a condition.
DM: True. Slow is not a condition.
Unknown: They would be immune to slow no matter what.
Seeker: Right.
Unknown: But you can-
DM: You could definitely try slowing them
Delwath: ... is there a 40 foot cube that would hit-
DM: No, no, you pick. Slow, you pick the targets
Unknown: ... I pick targets.
DM: It doesn't matter who it is.
Unknown: Yeah, you should slow them. That's not a bad idea.
Seeker: Okay. I cast slow
Unknown: on...
Unknown: All four
Seeker: ... actually, wait. It's up to six-
Delwath: Yeah, but it's only in a 40 foot square.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. So just the daggers.
DM: What save is it?
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: DC 18 wis.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Wisdom?
Delwath: Oh, it's concentration.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: So animal shapes again.
Seeker: Wait, wait, wait. I can't do this.
Unknown: Sorry.
DM: You want to keep animal shapes for you to run away.
Seeker: I didn't realize that.
DM: Animal sha- I mean, it's a great spell, but it's very limiting when you try and fight.
Seeker: We didn't know just how much we were gonna go into here.
Unknown: I mean, you could-
Delwath: But it's been so useful to have it.
DM: Like-
Delwath: You could just give up on it, but, like, it is really useful.
Delwath: I think we should keep it if you can
DM: Although on the other hand, this is the bottom of the tower.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Unless there's something behind those two doors.
Delwath: Which there could be.
DM: Which there could be.
Delwath: Maybe just give up on animal shape.
Delwath: I don't know, it's up to you.
Delwath: We got a lot of value out of it.
Seeker: We sure... We used it a lot, that's true.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: I don't have any other area effect things aside from watery sphere.
Seeker: That's concentration too.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: I'll just try s- I'll do slow.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Did I already mark off the slot?
Delwath: Yeah, you did.
DM: So it's a wisdom save DC-
Unknown: 18
DM: ...
DM: 18. Um,
DM: fail, fail-
Seeker: What does slow do again?
DM: Fail, succeed.
Seeker: So they are-
DM: Um, can you-
Delwath: The twos all failed though
DM: ... No, no. Make the neon one. Make the one that's the farthest one neon.
DM: That's the ones that succeeded.
Seeker: Um, so their speed is halved, minus two to AC and dex saving throws.
Unknown: Can't take reactions.
Delwath: Can take either an action or a bonus, but not both.
Unknown: And only one attack if it takes the attack action.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: That ends... Oh, ladder.
Seeker: Repeat the save. Oh, the ladder will attempt to grapple.
DM: The fist in front of it?
Unknown: Yeah, why not?
DM: Yeah, awesome.
Seeker: [laughs] Uh, so that's-
Kenzo: I love that there's like a ladder fighting a disembodied fist.
DM: So, so grapple-
Kenzo: It's like Force
Seeker: ... so that's, I just do the attack again?
DM: Uh, no, no. Ladder does not, you don't have to make an attack to grapple.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: The, the...
DM: So it's,
DM: uh,
DM: eight plus, what's its strength?
Seeker: I think it's 18. Let me check.
Seeker: 18.
DM: So eight plus
DM: four plus five is,
DM: uh, 17.
DM: So it needs to roll a seven- a DC 17 strength saving throw.
DM: Uh, it fails.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: So it is grappled.
Delwath: Wow, 17.
DM: Which means that it has disadvantage on attacks against the ladder, a- against anybody but the ladder, and it can't move.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Uh, so that ends Seeker's turn.
DM: Wellby, you're up.
DM: And then Kenzo next, and then Delwath.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: I'm gonna move behi- Am I?
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: I assume you're in this square on this grid here.
Wellby: I assume I'm back. I'm gonna move back he- No, I'm not.
Wellby: I'm gonna take a steady aim and shoot this guy.
DM: Uh, yeah.
Wellby: No, no. I'm gonna shoot this guy.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: The non-slowed one.
DM: Non-slowed one.
Kenzo: Yeah. How many are slowed? Just one?
DM: Just one.
Delwath: All... One is not slowed. Three are slowed.
DM: One is not slowed. Three are slowed.
Unknown: What does slow do again?
DM: Minus two to AC.
Wellby: That's a natural 20.
Unknown: Hey.
DM: I don't think this guy's gonna survive.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: How many dice do you get again?
Seeker: But it doesn't have an eye for you to shoot.
Wellby: 15.
Unknown: It's just a dagger.
Wellby: Uh, three, six.
Wellby: Uh.
DM: You'd have to roll really poorly for it to survive.
Wellby: Um,
Wellby: yeah.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [coughs]
Wellby: I'm gonna call it a three. I think I kill it.
Delwath: How many hit points does it have left?
Wellby: No.
DM: It's not, it's uninjured.
DM: You haven't hurt any of them yet.
Wellby: All right. Six, six, six.
Wellby: Five, five.
Unknown: That's 30.
Wellby: Five, five, six.
Wellby: 20.
Unknown: 30.
Wellby: 35.
Kenzo: Interesting roll.
Wellby: Yeah, it's all fives and sixes.
Wellby: So
Wellby: 36 here.
Unknown: Plus 30, 66.
DM: 66 is-
Wellby: Plus six
DM: ... 66 is dead.
Unknown: 72, okay.
DM: 72 is dead.
Seeker: Amazing.
DM: Your arrow just goes straight through it and
DM: it explodes.
Kenzo: Does it explode into even smaller daggers?
DM: No, it explodes-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: That's what I was hoping for
DM: ... in a fine spray and then vanishes.
Kenzo: Does this, does this blow up in a little, like, like, like-
Unknown: Little, tiny, like, swordsman daggers
Kenzo: ... no, no, no. Like, like little butter knives.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: Eventually we're fighting just thousands of sewing needle daggers.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Wait, who was after Kenzo?
Unknown: And then some darts.
DM: After Wellby? Uh, Kenzo then Delwath.
Unknown: [laughs] All right, uh, I guess I'll get over...
Kenzo: Well, I've got five attacks.
Kenzo: I mean, we'll see how much I damage I do.
Kenzo: Um, I guess, should I, should I go over here and be in melee with the other-
Delwath: But you're 15... Why?
Delwath: Stay, stay out of melee.
Wellby: Yeah, you've got a 15 foot range.
DM: Yeah, fuck yeah. Totally, yeah. That's cool.
Unknown: Yeah, so I hang out over here.
Kenzo: I can hit... Each one of these squares is how much?
DM: Five feet.
Kenzo: Uh, oh yeah, so I can, like, hit them all from here, right?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, okay. All right, cool. I'll stay over here.
Unknown: How are we gonna get out? How are we gonna get home?
DM: Uh, well, yeah, that's a good...
DM: Teleport.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Do you still have your seventh level spot?
Unknown: Wait, why can't we-
Unknown: I hope so
Unknown: ... why are we worried about that?
DM: 'Cause you can't fly now, so if you want to get home you have to tromp through the-
Kenzo: Oh, true
DM: ... church northwest.
Seeker: Save your... I have not burned my seventh level spot.
Delwath: Save your seventh level spot, 'cause then we can teleport back to Dim- to Dimitar's place.
Seeker: That's... Yeah.
Kenzo: All right. Do I, I get advantage.
DM: No.
Unknown: No.
Wellby: Uh, no.
DM: Never have.
Unknown: Why don't I get advantage?
DM: 'Cause it's not the first round of... It's not the beginning of combat anymore.
DM: It's just the first round in combat.
Kenzo: Well, why did I still have advantage last turn?
Kenzo: Oh, okay. Whatever.
Unknown: Um.
DM: This is only the third round.
DM: I think this is only the third round of combat.
Unknown: Yeah, that's so confusing.
DM: You just ro- you've just rolled so many crats.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Okay. All right, all right. So I'm using, um,
Kenzo: fists. Uh,
Kenzo: okay, yeah, so it's regular fist attack, um, plus-
DM: Just a straight roll
DM: ... a five. Yeah.
DM: But these all have a minus two to their AC from slow.
Kenzo: Uh, so 17.
DM: That hits.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: And then this does, uh, 14 damage.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: That's the first one.
Kenzo: I'm gonna keep just attacking the same one.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: That hits. Uh, another 14 damage.
DM: Got it.
Kenzo: Third attack.
Kenzo: That hits. Oh man, nine damage.
Kenzo: Not doing real well on the damage. How many attacks was that?
DM: That's three.
Kenzo: Okay, two more.
Kenzo: That hits. Ooh, this is better.
Kenzo: Uh, 19 damage.
Kenzo: And then the last one-
Kenzo: That hits and that does 16 damage.
DM: Um, 16 you said?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Uh, that one's dead as well.
Unknown: Okay, cool.
DM: The last fist, the claw just
DM: rips it in half and it explodes.
DM: Uh, Delwath.
Kenzo: With the dead ones and then, and then into, uh, like, uh, needles and then something.
DM: I'm just same...
Delwath: Does, uh, uh, 18 hit?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: uh, 18 damage.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Uh, eight, nine, uh, 15 damage.
Wellby: Natural 20. [laughs]
Wellby: 25.
Unknown: That's the die.
DM: That is totally the die.
Unknown: That's the one.
Delwath: [laughs] I'm not smiting or anything.
DM: It's fine with it.
Delwath: Okay. Uh, 10, 21 plus 6 is 20,
Delwath: uh, 7.
DM: That, that's just enough to kill it.
Unknown: Wow.
Wellby: Amazing.
Wellby: Nice.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And that...
Delwath: I don't really have anything else useful to do.
Kenzo: That was pretty useful.
DM: Yeah. The last dagger is gonna make one attack against you.
DM: Uh, that's a
DM: 20.
Unknown: Misses.
Kenzo: 21 AC is pretty awesome.
DM: Sure is.
Delwath: 21 AC is nice.
Kenzo: With the option to 26 it.
DM: Ah, the fist. [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] That's the really nice part.
DM: It's pretty awesome.
Delwath: I mean, I've burdened him with all my first level slots.
DM: Um, the fist-
Wellby: That's first level slots to do the shield
DM: ... uh, is going to attempt to hit the...
Kenzo: We're so nasty.
DM: Yeah. Uh, no.
DM: It misses again.
Delwath: I mean, we've crit four times.
Wellby: So many crits.
DM: And the other-
Delwath: Four crits.
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... the other fist can't do anything.
DM: [laughs] Yeah.
Wellby: Fuck the ladder.
Delwath: And the ladder is seriously the most helpful.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Ladder.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Ladder is a fucking MVP.
Unknown: MVP.
Wellby: It's like an MVP.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Yeah, holding it down.
DM: Seeker, you're out.
Wellby: Most valuable ladder.
Seeker: Um-
Wellby: MVL
Seeker: ... I guess I have slow active still, but I could punch this thing with a catapult.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: I'll use a fifth level catapult,
Seeker: so that's-
Wellby: Better, better on it than, um-
Seeker: ... a single attack. Is that a 20?
Wellby: No, no.
DM: No, it's a dex save.
Seeker: It hits, yeah.
Seeker: I mean, it... Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, slow is good. It is minus two-
DM: Minus two to dex
Wellby: ... dex saves.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: It's a good combo
DM: ... what's your...
DM: That's a 23, so-
Unknown: No
DM: ... it's still a 21.
Unknown: Still 18.
DM: So it slams into the wall.
Unknown: Ah.
Wellby: Oh, the catapult missed?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: Sad.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Um, but ladder gets to attack.
DM: [laughs] Squeeze the-
Seeker: Um, so the, so it's grappled
DM: ... punch the... It can still punch it even though it's grappled.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Just swings a piece of the rope around and just slams it into all the ladders.
Seeker: So do I roll its grapple attacks?
DM: The ladder is gra-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... no, the ladder's grappling the thing.
Unknown: That's a 13.
DM: That misses.
Unknown: Sad.
DM: Still holding onto it, though.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um, and that is-
Delwath: Wait, did you skip the hands?
DM: They, they-
Unknown: Oh, they-
DM: One hand missed
Unknown: ... yeah.
DM: The other hand can't do anything.
Seeker: [laughs] Yeah.
Seeker: It's in a traffic jam.
DM: Uh, that ends Seeker, so Wellby, you're up.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: uh, can I go down the hall without provoking an opportunity attack from the dagger,
Wellby: or will that-
Unknown: Uh, no, yeah, yeah.
DM: You can.
Kenzo: You go from here, and then-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... can you pass through the guy?
Wellby: All right. I'll come over here and-
Unknown: Oh, that's a good idea
Wellby: ... shoot the-
Kenzo: Yeah, way better
Wellby: ...
Wellby: uh, yeah.
DM: You won't get sneak, right?
Wellby: I'll shoot the-
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Oh, no.
Unknown: 'Cause you're in the ladder.
DM: Of course it would.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: He's in... The ladder's engaged.
Wellby: Here we go.
Wellby: That's a...
Wellby: What is that?
Unknown: 14.
Wellby: That's a 15.
Unknown: 14,
Unknown: 15.
DM: Uh, no.
Wellby: Grapple?
DM: That misses.
Wellby: Isn't it grapple?
DM: Grapple doesn't affect their AC.
Wellby: It feels not right.
DM: It gives them disadvantage.
DM: You can u- do you still have your inspiration?
DM: You can use both.
Delwath: You could use your hero inspiration.
Wellby: Sure, why not?
DM: Yeah, that hits.
Wellby: Awesome.
DM: Wait, is that a 13?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: That's 13.
DM: Yeah, yeah. So 23, that hits.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: I'll use all of the flaming bowstring charges, too.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Just one.
DM: You just like rolling giant dice.
Delwath: Wait, are these guys immune to exhaustion?
Wellby: It's really, it's really satisfying.
Unknown: Nobody ever soul sighted them.
Kenzo: Oh, we didn't, we didn't soul sight the, these things.
DM: Uh-
Wellby: Are they immune to fire?
DM: Nobody ever soul sighted them.
Wellby: Do you want the damages separately-
DM: Uh-
Wellby: ... because I rolled them all together?
DM: Uh, no. I don't need the damage separately.
DM: They are, they don't have any fire protection.
Delwath: You are aware they would be exhausted if this-
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: 10, 20, 30.
Unknown: Why, is this one of your dice?
Wellby: 40.
DM: 'Cause they have their save against sickening radiance.
Unknown: Uh-oh. I see.
Wellby: 34 plus six is 40.
Delwath: Oh, but in the new rules, it's what?
Delwath: Just a straight up minus two or something like that?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: 48.
DM: But that's actually much better because-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... disadvantage. 48?
Wellby: Yep.
DM: On the, the one in front.
Wellby: I think on the one in back if I can get it, 'cause it's not grappled, so-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... might as well.
DM: Um-
Unknown: You can shoot through enemies.
DM: Yeah, 'cause he has sharpshooter.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, okay.
Unknown: Plus advantage.
DM: Yeah, that kills it. Oh, fuck.
Unknown: You killed the hand... That one hit?
Kenzo: Oh, 'cause it had been sickened.
DM: That one was already wounded.
Kenzo: From the sickening radiance.
DM: They were both wounded.
Delwath: They've both taken damage from sickening radiance.
DM: Yeah. Wow. Holy shit.
Wellby: Keep up the good work, ladder.
DM: We were so close.
Wellby: Wellby calls it.
Unknown: All right.
DM: That ends Wellby's turn. Kenzo.
Kenzo: All right. Time to finish off this fucking guy.
DM: Don't close with it.
Unknown: Uh, whatever.
DM: Punch it from far away.
Unknown: If you... Because I can.
DM: That one is still on damage.
Unknown: You just... Okay.
DM: So it gets to save against...
DM: Hold on. No, it's-
Seeker: Against slow, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: All right, here we go. Let's fucking go.
Kenzo: Uh, 17.
DM: That hits.
Kenzo: Uh, 14 damage for the first attack.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Oh, I think I missed.
Unknown: Yeah, two's gonna miss. What is it?
DM: 13.
Kenzo: Um, do I do a plus 10 or a plus 11 on there?
DM: Plus 10.
Unknown: 12.
DM: Yeah. Yeah, that misses even with a minus two.
Unknown: Ugh. All right, fuck it.
Kenzo: I, I won't use any random ones.
DM: Yeah, you have five attacks. Just keep going.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You'll do a miss occasionally.
Kenzo: That's the first time I've missed-
Unknown: Yeah [laughs]
Unknown: ... in any combat-
Unknown: In like dozen attacks
Unknown: ... this whole night.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like, all the things we've fought, that's the first time I've missed anything.
Unknown: All right.
Kenzo: Crazy. All right, so this is attack number three.
Unknown: [dice landing] [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: All right, so now, now-
Unknown: That'll do it
Delwath: So six, plus roll both of them again.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah. [dice landing]
Unknown: Plus-
DM: Six plus eight
Kenzo: ... 14-
DM: Plus six
Unknown: ... plus fi- plus five.
DM: 19.
Unknown: 19.
Kenzo: 19, yeah. Okay.
DM: Uh, you still have two more attacks.
Kenzo: Two attacks, yeah. [dice landing] That hits.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Uh, 14 plus 5 is another 19.
Seeker: My one crit of the night was finding something out.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That was really important.
Unknown: But that was the most important thing.
DM: It was huge.
Unknown: Without it, we wouldn't have gotten to know the fucking manacle.
Unknown: If it wasn't for that, you wouldn't have, uh, Seeker wouldn't have been possessed.
DM: [die landing]
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Oh, I think I missed. Wait, do I still have bar- do I have, do I have a bardic inspiration?
DM: No.
Seeker: I think we used it.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: I mean, Seeker could buy-
Unknown: Could
Delwath: ... bard, Seeker could give you one.
Unknown: Right now?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, do it. Right?
Seeker: Uh, yeah, I don't think I've done one this-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... round.
Unknown: Let's do it.
Unknown: I hit.
Delwath: And what's the side, what's the rider effect on Seeker?
Unknown: 16.
DM: Um, yeah, well, that's gonna kill it anyway, so the rider effect doesn't matter.
Delwath: All right.
Delwath: All right. Delwath?
DM: Uh, yep, Delwath is up.
Kenzo: You can always move through your allies.
DM: Yeah, but it's difficult terrain, so it counts as two.
Delwath: That's okay. I'm just gonna shoot a cantrip at it.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Shoot a cantrip?
Delwath: I'm gonna cast a spell.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Delwath: I'm not gonna close him away.
Delwath: Uh, it's probably okay to for- there's no reason to think...
Delwath: I'm gonna, I'll just blast it.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: So I get-
DM: It does get plus 2 to its AC from cover from the ladder.
Delwath: Right. Uh, I get three beams.
Kenzo: And the ladder's not in its, doesn't get hit?
Delwath: No, the ladder doesn't get hit.
Delwath: [die landing] Oh, that's not a D20.
Delwath: Uh, 16 and 14.
DM: Those both hit. [die landing] That misses.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Where's the D- D20?
Delwath: [die landing] So I do six points of damage.
DM: [laughs] Okay.
DM: Dude.
Kenzo: What? You normally do, like, 50 points of damage.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But I'm not-
Delwath: I'm not very good with my spells.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: I like my sword.
Kenzo: Okay. Okay. Oh, you do wanna be in melee.
Delwath: I, well, I can't 'cause I can't get past the ladder.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Okay, the fist.
DM: It's really trying.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Wellby reaches out telepathically to the fist, "Surrender or be destroyed."
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: [laughs] It's really trying.
DM: Uh, what's the ladder's AC?
DM: That's a 18.
Seeker: I think it's 16.
Kenzo: Does the fist wave goodbye when it dies?
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Okay. So the fist hits the ladder.
Delwath: Now something's gonna happen. It's gonna throw the ladder down the cauldron.
Kenzo: It'll push the ladder into you or something.
Unknown: It-
Unknown: Yeah, 16
DM: ... does... Oh, here, I gave you all my D8s.
DM: I need 4 D8 back.
Wellby: Does it break the grapple in the process?
DM: Um, yes, because it's about to do force movement on the [die landing] ladder.
Wellby: Ooh.
DM: So that will break the grapple. So that's six, that's el- 11, uh, [die landing] uh, s- 18 points of damage.
DM: Um, and the ladder is pushed 10 feet back and knocked prone.
Seeker: It's funny that the ladder can be prone, but of course it can.
DM: Yeah. Um-
Wellby: So it folded up over itself and fell.
Kenzo: And it's like, "Ah."
Seeker: Eight.
DM: So that breaks the grapple.
DM: But honestly, [laughs] there's not that much more it can do.
DM: So it's just gonna move forward and still be next to the ladder.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs] The, to its last breath, if it takes breath, the ladder protects us.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And that's Seeker's turn, and then Wellby's next.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: I would just, I wouldn't-
Unknown: Just have the ladder just hang out
Delwath: ... put any slots at this point.
DM: Just-
Delwath: Just hang out. Yeah.
DM: Yeah. Just the ladder can just attack.
Seeker: I'll, I'll just have the ladder attack.
Seeker: [die landing] That's a
Unknown: 16.
DM: 16. That misses.
Wellby: I will take steady aim.
Kenzo: Where are you? Is that, is that you?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. That hits. [die landing]
Unknown: Well, that's a lot of damage.
DM: I, uh, it's got 22 hit points left.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: But I don't know that it can take much more.
Wellby: It's very much dead. Yep.
DM: It's dead. Okay.
Unknown: And then it goes, "Weh."
Kenzo: It waves as it disintegrates.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs] It waves as it disintegrates.
Wellby: It's like, "Ah." [laughs]
DM: [laughs] "Ah."
Wellby: That's really not what I expected to happen when we opened that door.
DM: No.
Seeker: That was a lot more.
Unknown: Huh.
Delwath: All right. Well, I'll dismiss the sickening radiance.
Delwath: Let's go s- let's go inside. Oh, wait, hold on.
Delwath: I still have... That was only three turns?
DM: Uh, yeah.
Delwath: Okay. I still have, like, 30 seconds-
DM: No, it was four turns
Delwath: ... so, like, 10, 20 seconds of ghostly vision.
Unknown: Yeah, go look, go look behind these doors.
Delwath: I'm, I'm just gonna run inside the room-
DM: Four turns
Unknown: ... and look.
Kenzo: Look behind the doors.
DM: Okay. Um.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: You, you run into the room?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I'm opening up doors. [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I'm avoiding touching any of these things.
Delwath: I'm just gonna, like, quickly look behind the doors.
Kenzo: And you lick the silver panel on the wall.
DM: No. No, I'm not silly.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay. Um-
Unknown: ... the room, the room, uh, there are-
Unknown: Nice
Unknown: ... there are small rooms-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... through each of these doors.
DM: Each one is, like, 10 feet out and, like, extends the length of the, of the r- like, going back this way.
DM: So it's like sh- forms, like, an L.
DM: It goes about 20 feet back.
Delwath: Like, around like that?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: And is there any... I'm just gonna glance around all the walls.
DM: There's no other space.
DM: Um, and in these, so in the room to the right, you just have the time for a quick
DM: glance. It looks like there's, like, hundreds of different, or, like, many different kinds of metals.
DM: Like, all sorts of metal bars-
Unknown: Right. Okay
DM: ... and random things. Um, um, in the other one, you see, like, a s- like a stone basin, um, like, uh,
DM: a whole row of glass vials, um,
DM: fine sort of metal shavings and things.
Unknown: This is Fandrix's wet dream.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah. And that's, like, you're only, you're, like, quickly glancing.
Delwath: Yeah. Most of the time just-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... honestly, most of the time just, like-
Delwath: ... walking along, looking to just make sure there's nothing that we're missing.
Delwath: I don't care so much what's in the rooms-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... as long as it looks like there's no monsters Right.
DM: You don't see any monsters
Delwath: ... and then, and then I'm just looking, like, is-
DM: How long does See Invisibility last?
Unknown: An hour.
DM: Okay. You don't see any monsters.
Delwath: Um, so I'm just, like, but it, like, also just like all along, there's like nothing-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... anywhere through any of the walls.
Delwath: It's all just walls.
DM: Nothing to do.
Kenzo: And nothing below, either.
Delwath: Yeah, nothing below.
DM: Nothing below.
Delwath: Or inside here.
DM: Um,
DM: so
DM: how... So ghostly gaze is an X-ray.
DM: It's, it turns solid things.
Delwath: Correct. I would... If there's, like, something hidden in the center of that-
DM: You don't... You just see through it
Delwath: ... like, if it... I would, the way I would rule it is if it was, like, a thin shell, and there was a physical space inside, you would see through the shell.
Delwath: But if it's, like-
Kenzo: A solid thing
Delwath: ... a solid thing, it's not like X-ray vision.
DM: You don't see it, right.
Seeker: Um.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: I, I will also just, um,
Seeker: use my tremor sense.
DM: Nice.
Unknown: Just-
DM: Nothing moving
Unknown: ...
Unknown: as the...
Unknown: Tremor sense.
Unknown: Be quiet.
Kenzo: What does tremor sense do? Like, it helps you do what?
DM: Detect-
Seeker: It's, it's the thing about, like, vibrations in stone.
DM: Right.
Seeker: You can picture Seeker just kind of like crouching down and like-
Kenzo: So if there's like any, if, if there's like an ant walking on the ground, would you notice that?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Would you notice that?
Seeker: I don't know about an ant, but-
DM: But
Seeker: ... any creatures moving
DM: ... like any-
Kenzo: Like walking around
DM: ... walk, anything walking around, you would sense it.
Unknown: Mice?
DM: Mice you could probably sense.
Seeker: Dim, I sense dimitar beneath the-
DM: Dimitar [laughs]
Delwath: ... the temple.
Kenzo: [laughs] All right. Let's, uh, yeah, let's search the room.
DM: There's nothing... I mean, okay.
DM: Uh, so looking around this main room before you open any doors.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: There's a divine forge.
Wellby: Very carefully inspecting all the parts of it and-
Kenzo: Do you, do you, you lick the silver panel on the wall
Wellby: ... panel.
Seeker: I will, um-
DM: The main thing is, like, who's touching what is the main thing I need to know.
Delwath: Okay. I'm touching nothing.
Unknown: I'm touching a whole Seeker back.
Unknown: [laughs] Touching nothing. Seeker, everything.
Seeker: [laughs] Seeker maybe has learned a lesson a little bit today, so.
Delwath: Like there's a mage hand hovering like right here.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: And if Seeker gets too close to anything...
Kenzo: But he does have to touch things. Or how long, how many times can you do the identify?
DM: Just once.
Kenzo: Once a day.
Seeker: Yeah. So we've used it for today.
Kenzo: I mean, also it was a strong use.
Unknown: It was a strong use.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: But man, this fucking forge, that thing would be pretty, that's a pretty-
Delwath: I mean, does the silver thing look like a...
Delwath: Remind us what the...
DM: So there's a sil- there's like a metal, silver metal panel that's like one foot square in the wall.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: There's all of these lu- like lines, silvery lines radiating out from it that look kind of like
DM: sort of jagged etchings that go in this all around the room, forming almost like a cage around the room, but all converge on the floor and then run up the sides,
DM: the bottom parts of the sides of the black pedestal and go into those four holes in the middle.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And then the top has a bunch of concentric circles etched in it.
Wellby: We should figure out how it works, and then we can, like, enhance the stuff that we have.
Unknown: Hmm. Is this like a...
Kenzo: Well, we can't bring [laughs] Fodrick here.
Unknown: Is there anything,
Seeker: there's nothing written or carved onto the panel?
DM: Nope.
Delwath: I, I don't know that... I mean, I think we should just open a door.
DM: Don't you think?
Seeker: Yeah, but... [sighs] Well, the doors are to, like, storage rooms, though.
Kenzo: Well, it's just, like, all the, all the materials to make the fucking super blade.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But it's like, there could be clues in there, right?
DM: Like...
Seeker: Yeah. What materials are used to make divine forge things?
Kenzo: All right. What's on the, what order are the ones?
DM: Uh, which one do you want to go in first?
Delwath: One was, like, metal, and one was vials.
DM: One was metal, and one was, like, vials.
DM: Yeah, pretty much.
Kenzo: Let's look in the metal room first.
DM: Okay.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Seeker, Seeker identifies all the metals.
DM: Um, so you open the door and you look in.
DM: Uh, there's,
DM: you know, there's a, there's a shelf that goes along the back that stretches about 10, 15 feet along the, along the, the side wall.
DM: It's a sort of empty, dusty stone room.
DM: Um, and, uh, there's like probably
DM: 200, like, metal bars all sort of evenly sized like this.
DM: Um,
DM: some fairly mundane.
DM: All the adamantium seems to have been used up.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: But there's, you know, there's some that are, like, silver.
DM: There's several bars of mithril.
DM: There's, like, some metal you don't even recognize.
Unknown: Ooh.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Um...
Kenzo: Take all those.
Kenzo: Lick them first.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Is there anything magical?
DM: Uh, there's, there is nothing...
DM: Wait, you don't, you'd have to...
DM: So you've just ritualed up detect magic again now.
Delwath: It hasn't been 30 minutes, has it?
Unknown: It's not concentration.
DM: Oh, right. It's no longer, it's not concentration anymore.
DM: That's right. So yeah. Um.
Kenzo: We did a short rest.
Delwath: I don't know.
Unknown: Uh-
Delwath: But we did a short rest.
Delwath: Yeah, but I would have probably re-
DM: Redone it
Delwath: ... I mean, or I can take a minute either way, but.
DM: Um, yeah, it doesn't matter.
DM: Uh, the, so there is, there is nothing magical, but the other thing, at the far end of the room, there is a stone chest.
Wellby: Check for traps.
Seeker: Always with the chests.
DM: Uh, okay. Make an investigation check.
Wellby: Uh, 28.
DM: Um, there are no traps.
Kenzo: Is the chest magic?
DM: The chest isn't magic. It's fairly thick stone.
Wellby: All right. Open chest.
DM: It's locked.
Wellby: Unlock chest.
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: 27.
DM: Nope.
Unknown: Try opening.
Wellby: Inspiration?
Seeker: Inspiration.
Wellby: I must really have inspiration That's a 12, so that's a 39.
DM: [laughs] Okay, that picks even invincible magic locks.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: You rolled a fucking 39?
DM: I was-
Delwath: With inspiration. I mean, still
Unknown: ... that's probably, you used at least f- you used
Delwath: We count it back on the short rest, so since the short rest- Yeah ...
Delwath: he's used one, two.
Delwath: I think he's only used two.
Seeker: Huh. All right. How many do you have?
DM: I think there's one more.
Delwath: Maybe three. Maybe it was three.
Unknown: How many do you get?
DM: Yeah, it's fine.
Seeker: Fuck, that sucks.
DM: Yeah, that's fine.
Seeker: We'll call it three.
DM: Um, so there are three items in the chest.
DM: One looks, uh, so the, so it's actually a fairly big chest, right?
DM: It's like, it's like, it's like a-
Kenzo: It's Apollyon's fucking chest, man. There's gotta be some good shit in here
DM: ... um.
Unknown: [laughs] Just a lot of socks.
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Something just like [claps].
Wellby: Two underwear. [laughs]
DM: It's, so it's like, it's almost like a, imagine a stone bench that stretches like the whole-
Delwath: A long bench
DM: ... 10 feet of the feet of the room and it's like a large...
DM: Chest is like the wrong way to think of it.
DM: Like, it's like a bench where the top lifts up, so it's like 10 feet long this way.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Five feet long this way.
DM: Thick stone though, so the interior is, um-
Unknown: Warded from
DM: ... warded.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: There's, there's,
DM: it's sort of divided into three compartments.
DM: Um,
DM: one, one compartment on the far left
Seeker: Apollyon's tax returns.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um, has what looks like, um,
DM: so it's a, it's a silver rod about this long,
DM: um, that has a sort of spiraling, um,
DM: it like a, a spiraling motif that, that spirals up to, um, at the top.
DM: Uh, there's... I actually never decided what this would look like.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, it looks like, uh, it's kind of growing into like the spiraly thing.
DM: It's holding up what looks like a sort of orb, like a s- like almost like a star kind of.
Seeker: It's a prototype for the scepter.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um.
Wellby: That's what it sounds like.
DM: And it's, there's, um...
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: It, it looks, so when you first glance at it, it looks like...
DM: It actually looks nothing really like the scepter at all, right?
DM: The scepter was sort of, you know, intentionally ostentatious, right?
DM: This is like quite... I mean, the scepter was like lined with diamonds and like very kind of show of power.
DM: This is much more subtle.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: Um,
DM: it looks almost natural.
DM: It looks almost like it sort of grew in this way.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: What's it made out of?
DM: Silver.
Unknown: Silver. The true scepter.
DM: But it is, it looks like it has been,
DM: somebody's
DM: fiddled with it, tried to damage it.
DM: Like it's chipped in the middle.
Seeker: Crap. Interesting.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Must've been him, right?
Unknown: Damaged it.
DM: In the middle compartment, um, there is, there are a series of
Seeker: Seeker refrains from touching it
DM: ... um, there are a series of-
Kenzo: Strong action. [laughs]
DM: ... like just stacked little small boxes.
DM: Um, they all have like a different kind of sigil on the front, and they seem to be like they're words like, um,
DM: power or renew or
Kenzo: Potions? Teas.
DM: Trinkets. [laughs]
DM: I mean, do you wanna open one?
Unknown: Are
Unknown: the boxes magic?
DM: They're like little boxes.
Kenzo: Are, are the boxes magic?
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Or just the contents magic?
DM: You can definitely sense magic.
DM: You don't see anything.
Wellby: Yeah, let's open one.
DM: Which one do you want to open?
Delwath: What are the actual words?
DM: Well, there's like 20 of them. Pick a word that you like.
Kenzo: Does one say like, um, refreshed
Unknown: or like renewed?
DM: There's one that said renew, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, it's a fine powder.
DM: Uh, looks almost like sort of a ash, but it smells wonderful.
DM: It smells like cedar and spring and the mountains.
Wellby: Magic item ingredients?
Delwath: Is the powder magical?
DM: The powder is magical.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: Do we just do lines of it right now or like snort a bunch of it and see what happens?
Delwath: Hmm, I'd wait till we know what it does.
DM: Seeker?
Seeker: Uh, Seeker refrains from touching the powder.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] All right.
DM: Deal with it later on the ship.
Unknown: Um, I mean it might be nice to figure out what some of these do For the dragon ...
Kenzo: for the dragon. You can only do identify once a day.
Seeker: But I can put on my goggles and have a look.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: From a safe, uh, distance.
Unknown: What does-
DM: Just to touch it
Unknown: ...
Unknown: what, what can you do with putting on your goggles?
DM: Just advantage on arcana checks.
Kenzo: Yes. Oh, but that, no, but that's useful to figure out what the fuck these are.
Seeker: Right. The touch, the touch is just for identify so.
Kenzo: Yeah, same thing with the wand. You should arcana the fuck out of it.
DM: Uh, do you wanna know what's in the third compartment?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
DM: Um, so the third compartment has, uh, three rings.
DM: They look matched, identical rings.
DM: Um, they're,
DM: uh, each one, they're, they're, they're made of
DM: gold.
DM: Uh, and they're sort of woven.
DM: It's like a, it's like a braided gold design, and each one, um, they look like the braids are identical, right?
DM: Like they look like they were very carefully made to be exactly the same as each other, except that there's a, a small gem set in each one.
DM: There's one that's like a,
DM: a emerald, there's one that's a sapphire, and there's one that's a ruby
Unknown: Wait, what was the third one?
Seeker: Ruby.
Unknown: Emerald.
Unknown: Ruby.
Seeker: Sapphire.
Unknown: Sapphire.
Seeker: What color is sapphire?
Seeker: It's, like, blue-ish.
Seeker: So red, green, blue.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Huh.
Unknown: Arcana.
Seeker: Well, which thing should I...
Kenzo: All of them.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: I think you should Arcana the powders and, like, the forge itself.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Not to identify it, but to try to understand, like, how does it work?
Seeker: I think the, the, the central question is, how does the forge work?
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: So that's what I should probably spend my time on.
DM: Do you want to go into the other room?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Go into the other room.
DM: Okay. So the other room, like, you spend a little bit...
DM: You go in there and you spend a little time looking around.
DM: Like, the Seeker recognizes this is clearly,
DM: um, like, the wor- a workshop for, like, etching metal.
DM: There's, like, a ceramic basin, there's, like, acid.
DM: There's, um, there's, like, vials of different chemicals that you can pour on things, various ways that you could etch metal here.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Nothing magical.
Seeker: Like for making printed circuit boards.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: What did you say?
Seeker: Like for, for making printed circuit boards.
Wellby: Oh, got it.
Delwath: Or, like, whatever [coughs]
Wellby: Layers of dagger cover.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Or the silver stuff in the other room, right?
Unknown: Like,
Unknown: aren't there, like, silvery tracings in the wall?
Seeker: The whole room is a kind of magic circuit board.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: I see.
Seeker: Divine magic circuit.
Seeker: So all right, I'm, I'm gonna in- in...
Seeker: just sort of trace some of the traces around the room.
Seeker: It seemed like it had a pretty simple kind of topology.
Seeker: Like...
Unknown: The room with the forge?
Seeker: The forge, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, it's quite s- s- I mean, the lines, the tracings are, are quite chaotic.
DM: Like, they don't follow any clear pattern, except they all go around and come up and go into these four holes.
Kenzo: Tim, the, uh... Remember, um, you know, Kenza was able to sense those, like, those, those ley lines?
Seeker: Or the r- the sort of line-
Unknown: The divine lines?
Unknown: Yeah,
Unknown: yeah.
DM: Nothing particularly here.
Unknown: Interesting.
Seeker: We're, we're far from the center.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But that's kind of weird. You'd think you would put the divine forge at the dead center of all the...
Kenzo: Well, maybe it's not using the divinity power.
Kenzo: It's using something else.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Well, for some reason we thought this was a divine forge, but maybe we're just guessing about that.
Kenzo: I think so.
Seeker: It uses some other kind of energy.
Seeker: What kind of energy does this thing use?
Seeker: We just have to open up this panel here, see.
Seeker: Uh, uh, no, I don't touch the panel.
Kenzo: [laughs] Can you open the panel or is it just a piece of...
Kenzo: It's just like a-
Wellby: You should open the panel.
Kenzo: Is it a panel?
Seeker: I'm picturing it being a circuit breaker.
Unknown: On the wall?
Seeker: But it's probably not. Does it open?
Delwath: I mean, is there any obvious latch or mechanism?
DM: There's no obvious latch or mechanism.
Kenzo: I mean, are there fingerprints?
Seeker: That's a good question.
Wellby: Can I investigate closely?
DM: I mean, it's been 700 years since anybody would have wiped surfaces in here.
Wellby: So the fingerprints are fresh?
Kenzo: Are, are highly, are t-
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Are exactly perfectly preserved.
DM: Make, make a, make a investigation or perception check.
Wellby: Uh...
Kenzo: Like an extremely high.
Wellby: 31.
DM: Um, it definitely is something that people have touched.
Kenzo: More than one person?
Unknown: That you cannot tell.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: I'll say to Seeker, "I think you should touch it there."
Unknown: Touch it where?
Seeker: Why, why do you say that particular place?
Wellby: 'Cause other people have touched it there.
Seeker: In that place? Oh.
Wellby: Maybe it's like a
Wellby: power button.
Seeker: I l- look over to Delwath.
Wellby: There's a constant kind of...
Seeker: Maybe we should mage hand it?
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: Can I tap it? I'll tap it with mage hand.
Delwath: Oh, wait, you ain't got mage hand too.
Seeker: Yeah, I know.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: I don't have spells. None of the others.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: If we have to beat a hasty retreat, we've already gathered up what we need to gather, right?
Delwath: [laughs] Do you think we should ask the Tanshi whether it's a bad idea to touch it?
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: There you go.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah. There you go.
Seeker: That's a great idea.
Wellby: I think we should ask the Tanshi whether it's a productive idea to touch it.
Seeker: Right. Good is relative in this situation.
Delwath: [laughs] Right. Okay, I get five yes or no questions.
Wellby: Is it dangerous to touch it?
Delwath: Yeah, okay. I, I'm gonna ask the Tanshi.
Unknown: I'll start. I'll like-
Seeker: Okay
Unknown: ... reach out.
Seeker: If we'll be in danger if we touch it.
Unknown: Um, uh,
Delwath: would it be dangerous to us?
Kenzo: Immediately dangerous maybe.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Eh, long-term dangerous.
Delwath: No, I'm just gonna say, would it be dangerous to us to touch this panel?
Seeker: Not as far as we know.
Wellby: Huh.
Wellby: That's less confident than I hoped for.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Well, d- then... Hmm.
Unknown: Uh...
Seeker: Is this older than the Tanshi?
Delwath: Probably, but they've shown evidence of be- of being able to find answers to things.
Kenzo: Oh, yes or no questions. Yes or no questions.
Unknown: Um...
Seeker: No, that would be a question for Mike.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. I...
Delwath: It almost... I mean, it could very well, but bef- in the past, they've answered things that the Tanshi themselves couldn't possibly have known.
Unknown: So I think there's-
Seeker: I see
Unknown: ... a little bit of a...
Seeker: Divine networking
Delwath: ... divine networking effect here.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: how about, uh...
Seeker: Do we have any guesses about the type of magic that we could ask, like, is it-
Wellby: Yeah, we can ask those questions, right?
Seeker: ... is this actually, like, a necrotic magic forge?
Delwath: Yes, no, or, like, one-word-answer kind of questions.
Wellby: A one-word answer.
Kenzo: 'Cause, like, like, well, can you ask it, like, what's the...
Kenzo: What powers it?
Seeker: What type of magic powers it?
Wellby: Can you ask it whether it's operable?
Seeker: Oh.
Unknown: We should ask.
Delwath: That's a good, that's a good question.
Kenzo: No, but, like, what kind of magic? What... How's it powered?
Kenzo: Don't we want to listen to the...
Delwath: Uh, I'll start by asking, um,
Unknown: is this,
Delwath: is this place,
Delwath: meaning the forge area, still functional?
Seeker: Yes.
Unknown: Is it...
Delwath: Uh, I want to, like, is it, mm-
Kenzo: There's always an energy source.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. Is it... And I'm trying to think, should I ask is it powered?
Delwath: I... What is it?
Seeker: The panel's on the back wall?
Unknown: What-
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh-
Kenzo: What is the source of its power?
DM: That has to be a yes or no question, right?
Kenzo: Only one word.
Seeker: Okay.
Seeker: Wait, from your, like, look, looking through the walls, was there anything behind the panel?
Delwath: Nah. Tim's like, "No," right? There's nothing, nothing behind the panel.
Seeker: Like, empty space or just solid rock or?
DM: Um, there was nothing behind, there was nothing behind the panel.
Delwath: I mean, Ghostly Gaze would s- turn the wall translucent.
Delwath: So if there's nothing for 30 feet, it would just be translucent wall for 30 feet.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: Is there a manual for this?
Unknown: Uh-
Wellby: Like...
Delwath: Um, hold on. Let me just see.
Unknown: Let's see.
Wellby: Well, there's a-
Delwath: You must ask your... Let's see.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: One note-
Delwath: It's five questions.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: yeah. The... It's not strictly yes/no.
Unknown: It's-
DM: It's one word
Delwath: ... it's like the, the DM answers each question with one word such as yes, no, maybe, never, irrelevant, unclear.
Unknown: Very good.
Delwath: Or, um, or if a one word answer would be misleading, you, you're allowed to answer with-
Unknown: Very good
Delwath: ... a short phrase. Yeah.
Delwath: What, what source of...
Unknown: What is the,
Delwath: what is the source of energy?
Unknown: What, what powers the-
Delwath: What, what e- what type of magical energy powers this place?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: You.
Delwath: Is that a singular or plural you?
DM: Uh, more precisely it would be the user.
Seeker: So we have to provide some energy.
Kenzo: Yeah, that makes sense. It comes from the, the caster or whoever is like the-
Delwath: Um, wait, hold on. That was-
Wellby: ... two
Unknown: ... two, right?
Wellby: That
Wellby: was... Do you know what that... Do you think it's worth double checking that that second book we got isn't like a how to use my elemental forge book?
DM: That is three. Wasn't that three?
Delwath: I asked dangerous-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... operable. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Operable.
Unknown: Yeah. Um...
Wellby: S- that's an interesting thought.
Unknown: I had two more questions.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: um...
Kenzo: Wait, we searched in the vial room yet?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, it was... I mean, there's lots of like vials of stuff.
Seeker: Something about the operating the forge harming the...
Unknown: Oh, wait. Right, I was just thinking-
Seeker: Is there-
Unknown: ... right, Mike.
Unknown: Is this-
Seeker: Like, is it gonna suck my soul out-
Unknown: But-
Seeker: ... if I touch the panel?
Wellby: Do you-
Seeker: But then we could forge something. [laughs]
Kenzo: But hold on. The, the, the...
Kenzo: s- like, okay, let's say we learned how it worked, like we're not gonna make anything right now, right?
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Or like-
Unknown: Not right now
Kenzo: ... what, like what could we do here right now?
Kenzo: Like, if we wanna learn something about it, it's almost like, um,
Kenzo: you know, do we wanna know like if there's like some item that it made that we're not aware of that we should go find?
Kenzo: Or, you know what I mean? Like, or, or is there, or is there like something else here that we would be interesting for the dragon or...
Kenzo: You know, if we wanna like... Like, if anything,
Kenzo: we wanna find something cool that we could potentially trade with the dragon or that could kill the dragon or make it easier for us to do stuff with the dragon.
Delwath: Isn't that why we took Apollyon's throne?
Unknown: You know-
Kenzo: That's helpful, but I'm, I'm saying here, down here
Seeker: ... w- we could try asking,
Seeker: uh, Wellby's question.
Kenzo: Which was?
Seeker: Is, is the locked book-
Wellby: Why don't we just pull the book out right quick-
Seeker: ... a guide to the use of the forge
Wellby: ... and take a look?
Delwath: I mean, we probably can't...
Delwath: The spell doesn't last.
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: We have like, we have like a minute.
Delwath: I mean, it's more... It's not like a long duration.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Probably can't go investigate the book before the spell runs out.
Wellby: But you just asked
Wellby: if it is. Uh, ask if is there a manual for how to operate it.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: yeah. I, uh...
Delwath: Yeah, I will ask, um-
Kenzo: Are there instructions someplace?
Unknown: ... uh, um...
Delwath: Where could we find
Delwath: guidance on operating this thing?
Wellby: Hmm. That's good.
Delwath: The manual.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So there is such a book.
Unknown: I think we have it.
DM: Or rather it would be more like the notes.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: You wanna ask if the book is the notes?
Delwath: No, I think it's gotta be the no-
Unknown: It must be
Delwath: ... the book is either the... It, it's probably not worth asking, right?
Delwath: 'Cause either it is or they're lost.
Delwath: Like where else would they be?
Unknown: May-
Wellby: I th-
Kenzo: I mean, you, you could ask, you could ask it if the, the notes are, um,
Kenzo: are in this room or in this building.
Delwath: I was more thinking Seeker's question about is it-
Unknown: Is it-
Kenzo: ... right? Like-
Seeker: Like dangerous or like lethal to operate this thing?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Right. Like...
Delwath: But I almost wanna ask, I'm trying to think.
Delwath: I mean, I could just ask if it's, if it's evil, right?
Delwath: Like, I wanna know is this like Apollyon witch magic or like wholesome divine magic here.
Delwath: I'm guessing maybe it could be used either way.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: Yeah, like is this evil or just a neutral tool, something to that effect.
Delwath: Right. Um,
Unknown: is this...
Delwath: What price, if any, must the oper- must the user-
Unknown: Hmm
Delwath: ... use, pay to use this?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: There may not be a way to answer that in a non-misleading way in one word.
DM: What happens to the spell then?
Delwath: Well, if you're allowed to answer-
Unknown: Use phrase
Delwath: ... in a short phrase
DM: But it doesn't... It's not supposed to give you sentences.
Unknown: No.
DM: So what do you do if you ask it a question it can't clearly answer?
Unknown: It goes, "Err."
Seeker: It's like, can't answer, can't explain.
Unknown: Do you know that?
Delwath: Ah, I, I think it's up to what the party would do, right?
DM: Like...
DM: It's complicated.
Unknown: There you go. [laughs] That makes sense.
Unknown: All right. Do we pull out the book?
Unknown: Check the book.
Unknown: Check the book?
DM: Well, it's, it's been-
DM: Okay. So where are you putting the portable hole?
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
Delwath: Oh, yeah. In the hawk.
Unknown: Uh...
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: Or, or in the room. Or in this room?
Unknown: Go.
Kenzo: A little away from... Get a little ways.
Delwath: Let's, let's actually...
Delwath: Should we take the three items?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Which, the, the ring, the three rings and the-
Delwath: The, the 24 items.
Delwath: The 20 boxes, the three rings, and the rod.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Let's just... I think we could pick these up.
Kenzo: Did you mage hand them into the...
Delwath: One at a time.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That'll take some time.
Wellby: We just pick them up.
Delwath: Yeah, I think we just pick them them up.
Unknown: Okay. You guys can do that.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: I'm picking up the scepter.
Seeker: I'm... Yeah.
DM: Nothing happens.
Kenzo: I'm not picking anything up.
DM: So let's load the-
Unknown: Fuck it, I'll pick up, I'll pick up the rings
Delwath: ... I'll, no, I'll put the three of the rings, one on each finger of the mage hand.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Okay. That's cool.
Delwath: And then I can pick up
Unknown: two boxes or three boxes, right?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: All right, so we start loading into the hole and so-
Delwath: Well, w- I think just bring everything up to the storeroom.
Wellby: Yeah. Good
DM: You put the hole
DM: down in the storeroom and you open it up and there's like a whiff of blood that comes up.
Unknown: No.
DM: Looks fine.
DM: Everything seems normal.
Delwath: Where's the, where's the book?
Wellby: Where's the blood whiff coming from?
DM: Just from the air in the hole.
Unknown: Where's the book?
Delwath: Where's the, I mean where's the necromancy book?
DM: In the hole. I guess under the throne or on top of the throne.
Wellby: I don't... We have shelves around the sides.
DM: Okay. It's on a shelf.
Unknown: Yeah, it's-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: All right. Mage hand that thing out.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: We might... We, we could leave that book here probably.
Wellby: Can we destroy it?
Unknown: We should try.
Wellby: Leave it here.
Seeker: It did, it did definitely
Delwath: cause some trouble.
Delwath: I mean, just going once here, but nobody wants to become a witch, right?
Kenzo: R- well... [laughs] I mean, the one thing we could do is fucking give it to the dragon.
Kenzo: Trade it to the dragon.
Wellby: Is there a way to become a friendly witch?
Delwath: I mean, how friendly are you after you've sacrificed the souls of, like, hundreds of people?
Wellby: What if the-
Unknown: For your own immortality
Wellby: ... followed suit? [laughs]
Seeker: Sacrifice is such a harsh word.
DM: [coughs] What if they were bad people?
Unknown: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wellby: [laughs] Simplistic elf morality.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: I am gonna mage hand the necromancy book out of here.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And put it on the floor as far away from Seeker as possible.
Seeker: Oh, I don't wanna get close to that thing anymore.
DM: And you're also mage handing the other book out?
Delwath: Uh, well, yeah, sure.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Yeah, we'll take the other book out too.
Wellby: So you should take a look at that book.
Seeker: So that one's... It's got like a metal closure.
DM: It's got a metal closure that's locked.
Unknown: Pick it.
Wellby: Unlock it.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Are there... Is it trapped?
Unknown: [laughs] Go ahead and roll investigation.
Wellby: Uh.
Kenzo: You investigate well
Wellby: 31. No, 28.
DM: Um, there is a small rune, tiny, that you almost don't see that's carved into the metal clasp.
Wellby: I'll point that out to you.
Seeker: Can I read it
Seeker: from a safe distance?
Delwath: How about you cast Dispel Magic on the arcane glyph that will explode when we open the book?
Seeker: Ah. 'Cause that's probably what it does, isn't it?
DM: [laughs] You wanna cast Dispel Magic?
Unknown: I cast Dispel Magic.
DM: What level slot?
Kenzo: Really high. It's like Apollyon.
Unknown: How are you doing for fifths?
Kenzo: Apollyon level high.
Seeker: I have two more fifth...
Seeker: One more fifth.
Delwath: I'd just use it.
Seeker: Okay. Dispel Magic.
Delwath: That's my advice
Seeker: At fifth level.
DM: Roll a D20.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: That's a nine.
DM: Plus... How does Dispel Magic work again?
DM: Sorry, I should have checked before I told you to roll a D20.
DM: I'm pretty sure you do have to roll a D20.
Wellby: It's a powerful book.
Delwath: It depends on the level of the spell.
Delwath: If it's under fifth level, it just dispels the magic.
DM: I know. It's not under fifth level.
Seeker: For each ongoing spell of level four or higher on the target.
DM: 10 plus the spell's level.
DM: Uh, so that's plus five.
Wellby: So it's-
DM: Oh, plus half plus two, so plus 17.
DM: Uh, it does not... Nothing happens.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: It make a...
Seeker: Wait, where did you get the 17 from?
Delwath: But you can... Ah.
Kenzo: Open it anyways and bear the consequences?
Unknown: You add your... Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: You add your caster
Unknown: level.
Wellby: That's what I just did.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So you get-
DM: Plus five, but that is far too high.
Wellby: We did that downstairs. We did that downstairs.
Unknown: Oh, no. Not only a fifth level.
Unknown: And we're fine.
Wellby: Every floor we just open...
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: But, but you should...
Wellby: And we're fine. [laughs]
Delwath: Do you still have heroic inspiration?
Unknown: Did you use it?
Kenzo: Isn't the lesson that we're fine?
Wellby: Open doors.
Unknown: I think I did.
DM: Did you?
Delwath: You c- you know the-
Unknown: Yeah, you did. You used it.
Delwath: Ah. There, there's no way we can, you can do a better...
Delwath: 'Cause y- you know you'd have to...
Kenzo: You used your heroic inspiration already?
Kenzo: Oh, no. But you get to use it again 'cause you, you ate the fucking...
Kenzo: Oh, you only can once a day.
Unknown: You used it during the combat, right?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: I think. I don't remember for sure what it was.
Delwath: You know you can-
Wellby: What spell slots do you have left?
Delwath: You can, you can check heroic inspiration.
Unknown: You can see that little thing right there.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: You can just tick it
Kenzo: and then untick it to determine if you...
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: But you never ticked it to... You when you used it, right?
Delwath: He... I don't think... But I think he did use it.
Delwath: He used it to re-roll-
Wellby: Some-
DM: Something, yeah
Delwath: ... one of your fail, something that you f-
Delwath: a failed saving throw or something.
Unknown: After the, after the short rest.
Wellby: But you have another, you have another fifth level spell slot too.
Wellby: You could also just take another swing at it.
Delwath: Yeah, I could use... I mean, you could use a fourth level slot.
Seeker: Yeah, I now have one fourth level.
DM: I mean, now that you know it's above fifth, there's no point.
Unknown: One third level.
DM: It makes no difference to use anything higher.
Delwath: Like, may as well use a third level slot 'cause you have to roll anyway
Seeker: All right. I could use a third l-... I could try again.
Delwath: Does Chime of Opening disarm traps?
Unknown: No.
Delwath: Just, yeah.
Seeker: It's probably not that harmful a trap.
Wellby: If it destroys the book.
Seeker: It could destroy the book. I'll try it again at third level.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: And I hope you're rolling it really high.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
Wellby: Natural
Wellby: 20.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Nope.
Kenzo: Brutal. [sighs] Okay, I mean, I was, I was saying this to, to, to Schwartz.
Kenzo: I mean, so far we've just opened things and then just bear the consequences of opening them.
Unknown: [laughs] Okay.
Kenzo: So do we just, you know, kinda go like, uh, you know, and then just, just fucking open it and see what happens?
Seeker: Is the ladder still up?
Kenzo: Get the ladder to open or get the mage, mage to open it with Mage Hand.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah, 'cause it was the beginning of the session.
Wellby: Well, it's locked. It's locked.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: Wellby would have to pick the lock,
Delwath: and then it would, like, explode, and Wellby would take 50 points of damage.
Wellby: That's okay. Or the book would die, or the book would...
Wellby: It's if the book is damaged would be...
Kenzo: Ah, I guess we should probably wait and do it on the...
Delwath: Do, do it later. [sighs] So like-
Wellby: If we do it later, we won't be here to use it, though.
Seeker: What? I was initially hoping to read the rune to see if I could figure out what the thing does.
DM: I mean, it's, it's a, it's a glyph.
DM: It's a spell glyph that will trigger some spell when you try and open it.
Unknown: But we don't know what spell it is.
DM: But you can't tell what spell it is.
Kenzo: Nice. Can you do Counterspell?
Wellby: It's an interesting idea.
DM: No, not... That's when somebody's casting and want to affect a glyph.
Unknown: This is a dispel magic situation.
Wellby: Hm.
Unknown: Can we...
Unknown: [sighs] Just have to do it later.
Kenzo: Or just, we just open it and see what happens.
Seeker: Or we just open it and see what happens, or Wellby opens it and see what happens.
Wellby: Seems like it wouldn't destroy...
Wellby: It, it seems like a poor trap that would destroy the book.
Unknown: It does.
Seeker: Right.
Unknown: Why?
Wellby: It seems like it should destroy the reader of the book.
Unknown: It should dest- Yeah.
Wellby: It should, like, disintegrate the reader.
Unknown: But after it's used-
Wellby: And leave the book okay
Kenzo: ... but, but after it's used, is the glyph restored?
Kenzo: Does, does the glyph stay? 'Cause if you're Apollyon, right, and you've got a glyph on the fucking thing,
Kenzo: probably you'd want...
Kenzo: 'Cause, like, if it's just gonna kill the user and then the book is still fine, then somebody else could go use his magic forge and make like fucking crazy shit.
Kenzo: Like, if you're like an egomaniac narcissist-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... you'd want the book to be destroyed so nobody else could fucking use that thing except for yourself.
Unknown: Now, but-
Wellby: But it's in a portion of the tower that nobody goes to but you.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: And it's in your tower, in your stronghold.
Kenzo: Well, no, no, no. The, the book was upstairs.
Wellby: It was in the library in the little tower.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It was. Yeah.
DM: It was in what was, like, Apollyon's private library.
DM: It's right next to the book where he was like, the instructions to be a lich.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So it's clearly, like, his private library.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I can see it being, like, one and done.
Wellby: Like, it...
Wellby: Maybe the ladder could open it.
Unknown: Wait, one and done like?
DM: The ladder can't pick locks.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Uh.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Can you use Mage Hand? Can you pick, ha- pick locks with Mage Hand?
Wellby: No. [laughs]
Wellby: Chime of Opening has a range.
Unknown: There you go.
Delwath: Ah, 120 feet.
Delwath: Pretty sure it's 120 feet.
Wellby: It is 120 feet.
Wellby: Strike it as an action, pointing it at an object within 120 feet that can be opened.
Delwath: Oh, that's a good idea. Let's just use the Chime of Opening.
Kenzo: Guys, hold on. I know I suggested this, but...
Seeker: [laughs] You having second thoughts?
Kenzo: I'm totally having second thoughts.
Delwath: No, first instinct.
Kenzo: Guys. W- wait, hold on, hold on.
Unknown: W- so where are we gonna do this?
Seeker: Chime it. Chime it.
Unknown: We're-
Delwath: We're gonna do a chime...
Delwath: Is the Chime of Opening even,
Unknown: um-
Kenzo: We've done so well so far. We've done so well all the way to this point.
Delwath: [laughs] We, like-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... stand, put the chime, put the book, like, here.
Kenzo: What's... No, no, I'm thinking, like, go upstairs or go outside or something.
Delwath: No, but we wanna be around... So here's my idea.
Delwath: Put the book here. Wellby stands here with the Chime of Opening.
Delwath: The rest of us stay over here.
Delwath: 'Cause you're good at dodging things.
Unknown: Hm.
Delwath: Evasion and stuff.
Unknown: That's fine.
Seeker: You just poke your head around the corner, chime, chime.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Any of us can ring this chime.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: But you are the one who is best at dodging explosions.
Wellby: [sighs]
Delwath: You are... Well, no, Kenzo could do it.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: But the... Don't you-
Unknown: Okay, uh-
Delwath: Don't you also have evasion?
Kenzo: No, I don't know if that is... I don't think so.
Unknown: No.
Wellby: You-
Unknown: Yeah, you have evasion.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Wait a minute.
Unknown: Wait, if I don't know I have it, I don't have it.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: No, that's-
DM: Okay, just tell me what you're doing, please.
Wellby: Yeah. Th- this is what we're doing.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Wellby, Wellby hits the chime.
Wellby: The book's there. I'll hit the chime.
Wellby: The ladder will open the book.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: No, the chime just causes it to fly open.
Wellby: No, the chime opens a lock or latch,
Wellby: and if no locks or latches remain, the object itself opens.
Wellby: So conceivably, the rune is triggered by being unlocked or conceivably-
Unknown: Ah, I see
Wellby: ... is triggered by being physically opened-
Unknown: Oh
Wellby: ... after being opened.
Unknown: Could be either one, yeah. Right, I see.
Kenzo: This is great.
DM: So you're hitting the chime?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Make an intelligence saving throw.
Unknown: Intelligence?
Wellby: Make an intelligence saving throw.
Wellby: Luckily, I recently became proficient in these.
Wellby: And that's a 24.
Unknown: That's it.
Wellby: Do I turn evil now?
DM: Um, you take-
Unknown: Now think of
DM: ... 55 points of psychic damage.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: But you avoid the befuddling spell,
DM: which would... Actually, wouldn't do anything to you.
DM: You can't cast spells or take the magic action for 30 days if you fail.
Wellby: I'd be okay with that.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: You would've also taken more damage.
Wellby: Wow.
Wellby: Wow, wow, wow, wow.
Unknown: 55.
Wellby: That's intense.
Kenzo: And does it open?
DM: How can we... It has a range of 150 feet.
Wellby: I look at the ladder hovering right in front of the book and just shake my head.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: The, it's the ladder unlocks the lock.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: [laughs] W- "Well," says Wellby with blood trickling down the sides of his head.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: "Uh, I think it's open."
Seeker: [laughs] Great, now we can read it.
Unknown: Thanks.
Unknown: Uh.
Kenzo: Okay.
Seeker: So.
Kenzo: So we, when I say we I mean not Kenzo, but we open the book and look at it.
Seeker: We can do it.
Wellby: For the record, Kenzo, you were correct about just open it [laughs].
Unknown: [laughs] I mean, three for three.
Unknown: Just open the things, observe the damage.
Unknown: Let's hopefully, you know, it's all right.
Seeker: It, it can be such a struggle to really obtain knowledge, but it's worth it in the end.
Kenzo: All right, what's in the book?
DM: Um, the book is Apollyon's backup spellbook and private notes.
Unknown: Holy fuck.
Seeker: Backup spellbook.
Seeker: Interesting.
Wellby: What good does that do us?
Kenzo: I mean, what are the private notes? Is it like-
Seeker: Private notes
Kenzo: ... I enjoy badminton on Wednesdays.
DM: That's why-
Kenzo: Turning myself into a lich on Tuesdays [laughs].
Wellby: I met a girl.
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: [laughs].
DM: Um, now it's mostly-
Unknown: Is this a private chat?
DM: I mean, it's all written in cipher.
Kenzo: Hmm. That we can decipher?
DM: I mean, you can spend some time to try and do it.
Seeker: Seeker's interesting.
Wellby: It feels like a Seeker problem, yeah.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
DM: Make a
DM: in-
DM: investigation check.
Seeker: That's an 18.
Wellby: That, you gotta stop rolling that die.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: That die is terrible.
Kenzo: Dude, it's, that's not, that one's, that one's, that one's not good.
Kenzo: You should roll... This one's really good.
Wellby: Mm.
Unknown: This is a good one.
Wellby: This one's good.
Kenzo: That one's way better.
DM: Um, how long are you willing to spend at this?
Seeker: Oh, I'm, I'm...
Seeker: I mean, this potentially tells us the secrets of the forge.
DM: It's like an hour and you're like, [sighs] "I sort of think I'm piecing this together.
DM: Like, maybe if I had another hour or two."
Wellby: What time is it now?
DM: Now it's, like, 4:00 in the afternoon.
Kenzo: And we can still fly back?
DM: Your aid is gone.
Seeker: Yeah, good point.
Unknown: Uh, what is gone?
Wellby: The temporary hit points.
DM: So set your max HPs back.
Wellby: We can teleport back to Dimitar.
DM: You can teleport back.
Seeker: That's the plan. We c- we, yeah, we can.
Kenzo: Well, and also to be fair, we can teleport back here, too.
Wellby: Feels like it would be good to leave here before-
Unknown: Dark
Wellby: ... sunset.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: I agree.
Wellby: So we can come back.
Seeker: So let him, let him do another one.
Seeker: Yeah, but I just need a little more time-
Seeker: Yeah
Unknown: ... with this thing.
Kenzo: Just let him, let him, just let him try to f- follow.
DM: Like, another hour. You're like, [sighs] "I just need another hour."
Seeker: Yeah. It's, I'm almost there. I'm starting to see the patterns.
DM: Another hour.
Wellby: I'm gonna short rest while he's doing this.
Kenzo: Yeah, I'll short rest too.
DM: It's like-
Seeker: Yeah
DM: ... 6:00.
DM: You've tr- you've pretty much figured it out.
DM: You're not sure you've got all the information,
DM: but you get the sort of...
DM: So there's a, like, you ha- like, there's a lot of notes here, and it's take some time.
DM: And you've managed to figure out, like, the, the way that the table of contents is ordered.
DM: So it's like, you know, how to become a lich, you know.
DM: Uh.
Unknown: Ooh, does it tell us what the crown is?
Unknown: That'd be great.
Seeker: Really?
DM: And then-
Wellby: That'd be so freaking sweet
DM: ... then there's a lot of notes on...
DM: It doesn't, it's not like a, it's not, like, a note of, like, everything I've done.
DM: It's not, like, my... It's not like a diary.
DM: A lot of it seems to be, like,
DM: uh, like, there's a bunch of copies of translations from other texts and things.
DM: It's like a sort of clip art, clip notes kind of thing where he's like mostly copied-
Unknown: Scratchpad
DM: ... copied things from other books.
DM: So it doesn't really talk very much about what he's done, but it talks about, like, the research he was doing from other books before he found the how to be a lich.
DM: And crucially, like, a collection of apparently
DM: Elven notes about how you...
DM: Written in Elvish, whether they're Elven or not, notes, 'cause they're all written out in Elvish, but you get somehow translated, um, about how to use the forge.
DM: And it seems-
Seeker: Nice
DM: ... the way to use the forge, he says it's costly
DM: because it drains your magic-
Unknown: Oh
Unknown: ... for a week or more.
Seeker: Oh, man.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Faldric.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: What?
Seeker: We just find some other magic user to drain it.
DM: Basically, the way, like,
DM: you give up your highest level slot and you can roll every day to get it back, but you don't get it back on a long rest until you roll.
Seeker: Right.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: But the higher level slot you give up, the better a magic item you can make.
Unknown: Wow.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: And that's
Seeker: all that's required. Surely there's other components.
DM: Well, I mean, there's, like, a whole bunch of instructions about how you have to etch the right runes.
Unknown: Oh, there's s-
DM: Correct, take, take, take the right powders to do the effect you want.
Kenzo: Oh, it's those powders. Those powders are, those powders and stuff you said.
DM: And sprinkle them on the...
DM: Like, you need to take a piece of metal, and you put the metal in the middle, then you put your hand on the plate, and you channel your magic into it, and it drains your spell slot and runs through the silver cords
DM: into the etched metal. You put the item you want to enchant in one of the four holes, depending on what item it is.
Unknown: Whoa.
DM: The metal, etched metal disintegrates.
DM: You lose your spell slot.
Kenzo: Anything about the rings or the wand?
DM: No.
Kenzo: 'Cause th- those boxes were integral to the whole process in the middle.
DM: Um, those-
Kenzo: The 20 boxes
DM: ... I mean, the vibe of those were, they were things that either...
DM: The vibe of the scepter was actually something he was, like, fiddling around with how to destroy.
Kenzo: Okay. Yeah, that's not his item.
Kenzo: He was trying to fuck with it.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Huh.
DM: And the vibe of the-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... and the vibe of the
DM: rings were just, like, they were something he fo- like, it was something he found and he hadn't gotten to yet when he was killed or when he left.
Seeker: Something he found? Huh.
DM: I mean, you don't know, but, like, they w- they don't seem to be things he made.
DM: They don't look like things Apollyon made.
DM: The vibe-
Seeker: Right. Right
DM: ... is very much not things that Apollyon made, but he would clearly, like, obviously, he would occasionally find things.
Kenzo: There's nothing else that he made here, though?
Unknown: We didn't, we didn't find anything.
DM: He didn't leave a lot of stuff around.
Seeker: Well, the-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... that crazy sword.
Kenzo: Is there, yeah, is there anything in there, um, about, um, the crown?
DM: No, it's not about the things he made.
DM: It's the notes about him figuring out how to...
DM: It's, it's all, like, copies of notes, right?
DM: He didn't-
Unknown: Got it
DM: ... he didn't, like, keep a jour- keep a journal-
Unknown: Mm
Unknown: ... like, I'm gonna make a crown today.
Kenzo: No, no, no, but it's more like if he wants to make a crown, then do some crazy shit.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: But you could infer that based on some of the stuff he was researching, right?
DM: Um, it's really, it's really focused on how to be a lich.
DM: Like this, with this plus the red book, you could definitely become a wretch
Seeker: [laughs] That was his main quest, obviously.
Kenzo: Wait, so but why, why... We still don't know the Woof of Blood situation and the portable hole
Seeker: Well, it's just that book is somehow leaching out its
Seeker: dark energy into everything else.
DM: Right. And, and they're connected, right?
DM: Because he used the forge to enchant these pieces of metal that he then took upstairs, right?
DM: So, like-
Wellby: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah
DM: ... he was, th- this was... They were interconnected research, like how to use the f- and it obviously took a while 'cause he had to give up his [sighs] magical slot each time he wanted to enchant something.
Unknown: And so it would be weeks and weeks and weeks.
Seeker: Yeah.
Kenzo: But, but is taking the book bad for us if it's, like, smelling bloody all the time?
Unknown: Do we leave that here or do we like-
Seeker: I, it seems like the kind of thing-
Seeker: ... or just kind of-
Seeker: ... that we don't... Unless we have a real specific plan for what to do with it, we shouldn't just carry it around.
Kenzo: Well, we also shouldn't just leave it here 'cause we destroyed all the stuff, so like somebody random could come in and find a bloody look fucking lich book.
Seeker: Mm.
Unknown: Right? It could destroy-
Seeker: We should follow the hints of the dragonets for instance [laughs].
DM: Like they would be-
Kenzo: Who are the most likely people to find it next, and who would then bring it to the dragon if we don't kill the dragon, which it probably will
Seeker: We could just, we could just lock it back into this cabinet here.
Seeker: I don't think... I don't sleep well knowing-
Seeker: Having stolen it. Well stolen
Wellby: It shouldn't exist in the world, man
Kenzo: ... yeah, I don't sleep well knowing that there's like a, like a, this, this book.
Seeker: Oh, we should destroy the b-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... How do we destroy it, though?
Kenzo: How did we destroy the scepter? We dropped it into a, into a volcano.
Seeker: Yeah. No, it was the holy water.
Wellby: Mm.
Seeker: In the end. It wasn't the volcano.
Unknown: Wait.
Seeker: I, uh-
Kenzo: Hold on. No, no, no, no, no, wait.
Kenzo: Hold on. I've got, um, a holy...
Kenzo: I've got holy water.
Kenzo: I have holy water. I have a flask of it.
DM: Holy water's probably not enough, but this does not seem like a...
DM: I mean, this isn't an artifact, right?
DM: You don't-
Unknown: I mean-
DM: ... not necessarily something we need
Delwath: ... would fire destroy it?
DM: You could... I mean, it probably wouldn't burn.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I mean, it clearly survived 700 years of...
DM: It's un- very unlikely you can destroy it without magic.
Kenzo: Do we though, um, keep it with us at least until after the dragon thing?
Kenzo: Because maybe we can destroy it in th- in the acid or maybe it's a useful bargaining chip for the lich dragon.
Seeker: It, it is not unreasonable to think that.
Delwath: I mean, I mean, but, but we should be careful 'cause, like, maybe it's gonna, like, seep somehow through the mirror of soul trapping.
Wellby: I think we should not put it back in the portable hole.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: I don't like putting it in a place where we d- can't see it.
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... we don't know what it's doing and it's-
Unknown: But what, how are we gonna transport it?
Wellby: Just put it back there.
DM: Who's gonna carry it?
Unknown: Fuck.
Wellby: Wait a minute. Uh, there are metal scraps.
Wellby: Let's make a little lead box for it.
Seeker: An adamantium box.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Is that better?
Unknown: Or it's a mithril box.
Wellby: And put it inside some... Whatever blocks magic.
DM: I mean, it'll take a while to actually forge, but only a second and a Seeker wants to just...
DM: [whooshing] How long does that last for?
Seeker: Which?
DM: Performance of creation.
Seeker: Oh, an hour, isn't it? An hour?
Seeker: Yeah.
Kenzo: So we just need it to teleport.
Seeker: Like, we just need to... Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Performance of creation.
Delwath: Fine, so we, we come back to the forge.
Delwath: We're not gonna... We're gonna teleport out to Dimitar from here,
Seeker: right?
Kenzo: But with the box.
Seeker: Which box?
Kenzo: We're gonna put the, put the fucking lich book inside a box and bring it with us.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So, or, or we're... He's gonna...
Kenzo: So Seadra's making a little box that we can put the lich book in.
Seeker: Oh, no, it create after a number of hours equal to your proficiency but-
DM: So it lasts for five hours.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Cool.
Seeker: So totally.
DM: And you can make...
Kenzo: And then we'll ask Dimitar to watch it for us while we go kill-
Seeker: Yeah
Unknown: ... the dragon.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So you make a fancy
DM: metal box.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: It's a mithril box. What, what's it made out of?
DM: Lead.
Seeker: Lead. Lead is the best protector.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And you're leaving, teleporting back?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's gotten dark.
DM: Sun... Well, it's not quite dark.
DM: The sun is setting.
Seeker: So we teleport back to the temple of s- the Sibyl?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Where Dimitar is?
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: We tell Dimitar, um, that there's a, a evil lich book in there and, uh, thanks for watching it for us while we kill the dragon later tomorrow.
DM: Wait.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: No.
Wellby: Look,
Unknown: I know we appreciate you a lot.
Seeker: You don't look green.
Kenzo: But it has to be you.
Kenzo: It's kind of the on- you're the only one here we trust.
Unknown: We gotta destroy it.
Kenzo: We can't leave it back there.
DM: Okay, everybody away.
DM: Open the box. Pulls out his wand.
Wellby: What?
DM: Quick, hurry.
Unknown: Okay. Okay. We go away.
Wellby: We-
DM: Giant fireball. [die rolling]
Kenzo: So much for using it as a bargaining-
DM: At the wa- the, the, uh-
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: ... book bursts into flames.
Seeker: Oh, thank goodness.
Wellby: Wow [laughs].
Unknown: Okay. All right.
Wellby: I'm very impressed.
Seeker: Di- Dimitar, I think you solved the problem.
Kenzo: That's... Okay. I mean, we were thinking about using it as a bargaining chip with the dragon, but, um, maybe this is better.
DM: Oh, you should've opened with that.
Seeker: [laughs]
Wellby: This is just another-
Unknown: We weren't really taking-
Wellby: ... situation that's solved-
Unknown: ... it as a bargaining chip
Wellby: ... with a wand of fireball.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Hey, there are a lot of problems you can solve with a wand of fireball.
Seeker: I think we're learning Dimitar's style and approach to solving problems.
Kenzo: Act first, think second.
Seeker: Fireball first.
Kenzo: Fireball first.
Wellby: Ask questions later.
Unknown: Do other things. Yeah.
DM: I mean, what's the worst that can happen?
DM: It wouldn't burn.
Kenzo: Yeah, I mean, we were thinking about that as a bargaining chip with the dragon, but I guess, well...
Wellby: The, the worst that can happen is, like, the evil that inhabits it leaves the book and takes control of you, and then you attack your friends.
Wellby: I'm speaking-
Kenzo: Using the, using said wand of fireballs
Wellby: ... hypothetically. [laughs]
DM: Oh, wow, I didn't... That didn't occur to me.
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, we should've mentioned it.
Seeker: I mean-
Kenzo: It possessed him for a little while-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... and he tried to kill us, so.
Seeker: And also-
Wellby: It didn't occur to us either
Seeker: ... what else?
DM: Yeah.
DM: He's okay now?
Seeker: I'm totally fine [laughs].
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, he's fine. Wait, but you, you're not possessed by the book, are you?
DM: No.
Unknown: You didn't... Did you touch it? I don't think it touched you.
DM: I would not let a stupid book like that possess me.
Unknown: Okay. And-
DM: I mean, are you weak or something?
Seeker: That other book actually had a bunch of lich related information, so you know.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Wait, what other book?
Kenzo: No, no, no, no, no, no, there's nothing else to burn.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: There's not another book.
Seeker: Yeah, there's no other book.
Delwath: It's, it's fine.
Seeker: It's fine.
Unknown: It's safe.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: We're, we're good.
Seeker: That's, that one's, that one's perfectly safe.
DM: Except for the arms
Kenzo: But, um, you know, we cleared the tower out, so if you do wanna find another place to hang out, there's a sweet tower west side.
Kenzo: You know, it gots a nice view of the ocean.
Unknown: Uh-
DM: Mm
Kenzo: ... you know. I mean, it is, it's Apollyon's Tower, so it's probably not...
Kenzo: You know, but it's cleared now. There's nothing in there, and it's, uh, you know.
Wellby: But tainted by the-
Unknown: Ex- except for the, the, the-
Wellby: ... memory of an unspeakable evil
Kenzo: Yeah, but, but also the, you know, the divine forge that's there that can make, um, you know, really powerful weapons if you wanna do that, or artifacts,
Kenzo: if you're into artificing.
DM: Not really.
Seeker: There's, there's a throne. We took the throne.
DM: Wait.
Seeker: But-
DM: Where is the throne?
Unknown: Well, we took, we took it. [laughs]
DM: You're wearing the throne around your neck?
Unknown: Extradimensional.
Seeker: [laughs] Yeah.
DM: Ah.
Kenzo: Spaces, you know. Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: We got a few tricks.
Seeker: Clever person.
Kenzo: Yeah, we're clever.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. Hey, do you know how to identify items?
DM: He, like,
DM: looks at his wand, looks at his staff.
DM: Fire?
DM: Ice?
DM: Mm, no.
Seeker: So you just got those two tricks?
DM: Stone.
Unknown: I can speak like the gods.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: That's, that's a good trick too.
Wellby: That's a, that's a good one.
Seeker: Yeah, it's very loud.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Very good.
Unknown: That's cool.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: See, you, you are pretty good.
Kenzo: Try not to do that in our ears.
Unknown: That's kinda like, you know.
Seeker: You have a number of tricks, actually.
Wellby: Give, give us a heads up before you do that.
Kenzo: Yeah, that'd be nice.
Seeker: [laughs]
Kenzo: Respectful.
Kenzo: Guessing you haven't talked to anybody in, like, 17 years or whatever since we got here, so.
DM: Oh, I talked to a few people.
Unknown: Really?
DM: Yeah, a couple dragonets. How do you think I knew about-
Kenzo: Oh, the dragonets. Okay, yeah.
Kenzo: But no, no, humanoids.
DM: Oh, oh.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: That's what you meant by people.
Seeker: I see.
DM: None of them, no.
Unknown: Kenzo.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: People, people.
Unknown: I'm just using the word people.
Seeker: Uh-huh.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: Bipedal, normally.
Delwath: Which method you like for that one?
Delwath: Two legs, that somehow makes people more worthy of, uh-
Kenzo: No, that's not... No, that, that's your perspective, elf.
Kenzo: You know, I'm, I'm a, I'm all, I'm a, you know, all consciousness
Kenzo: are part of the same large unity, so, you know.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So you're here to sleep again?
Kenzo: That's all right.
DM: Yeah, why not?
Seeker: It's been, uh,
Seeker: it's been a long day.
Wellby: It's been a day.
Unknown: Yeah, it's been a day.
DM: Uh-huh. [yawns] Okay.
DM: Good seeing you.
Kenzo: Yeah, glad you think so. We think so too.
DM: I didn't think you'd come back.
Kenzo: Alive?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: We had some dicey moments there.
Wellby: I think we did pretty much great.
Seeker: Yeah, we s- we should-
Delwath: I mean, we only got, you know, we got, like, five crits.
Delwath: Of course we did great.
Wellby: There was some great shooting, great exploding